<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"> <channel><title>Niximagery</title><description>Stories and images</description><link>https://niximagery.com/</link><atom:link href="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_created.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><managingEditor>Nick Hood</managingEditor><docs>https://github.com/NixImagery</docs><language>en</language> <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 14:15:28 -0000</pubDate> <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 14:15:28 -0000</lastBuildDate> <ttl>1440</ttl> <generator>MkDocs RSS plugin - v1.1.0</generator> <image> <url>https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/4/43/Feed-icon.svg/128px-Feed-icon.svg.png</url> <title>Niximagery</title><link>https://niximagery.com/</link> </image> <item> <title>Belhaven Beach</title> <category>Apple iPhone</category> <category>Fuji X</category> <category>Ilford Ortho</category> <category>Nikon FM</category> <category>Ricoh GRIII</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;belhaven-beach&#34;&gt;Belhaven Beach&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;More local exercise&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF7302.jpg&#34; /&gt;X-T2 XF16mm, ISO 400 f/11 at 1/500s using Velvia film simulation&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s nothing like a walk on a beach, especially when it&#39;s one of the long, windy, sea-birdy beaches like you find along the coast near Dunbar. We took ourselves off to Belhaven beach for such a walk, to clear the head, and to reset our fish supper metrics after a bad experience at Ballachulish.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m finding myself using a mix of digital and film cameras when I&#39;m out. When I need to shoot quickly, it&#39;s more likely that I&#39;ll grab the Ricoh in my pocket, like when I noticed a figure walking across the scene before us:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/R0000655.jpg&#34; title=&#34;Lone figure walking&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Socially distant&lt;/strong&gt; Ricoh GRIII, cropped and desaturated&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I keep the Ricoh in aperture-priority mode at f/16 when shooting landscape, if the light is OK. It really is a fabulous camera, and more than once I&#39;ve thought that if I could only have one camera, it would be this one. If I could only have no cameras, I&#39;d still have my phone, which is a pretty amazing piece of kit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/IMG_8861.jpg&#34; title=&#34;Belhaven beach&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Belhaven beach&lt;/strong&gt; (iPhone)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;also&#34;&gt;Also&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I also took some photos with my Nikon FM, on Ilford Ortho Plus 80 film. Read about those exposures &lt;a href=&#34;/Exposures/2020/2020-11-07-Ilford-orthochrome-80/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-07-18-belhaven-beach/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 14:16:02 -0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_created.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-07-18-belhaven-beach/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-07-18-belhaven-beach/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Learning about the CLA</title> <category>Fuji GW690ii</category> <category>Nikon FM</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;learning-about-the-cla&#34;&gt;Learning about the CLA&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/IMG_8897.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dirty little sisters&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s been a few months now, since I started shooting film again. Needless to say, I&#39;ve had some results I am very pleased with, and a whole series of disappointments and frustrations with myself on the way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;focusing-the-fuji&#34;&gt;Focusing the Fuji&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;My monster medium-format Fuji GW690ii (above, centre) is a rangefinder on steroids, one of a series of cameras known as the &#34;Texas Leicas&#34; on account of their size. They were made for Japanese bus tour customers, who got a souvenir snap of the group as they visited Mt. Fuji, or Kyoto, which was developed and printed in time for the end of the trip. The huge 6cm x 9cm negatives it produces are large enough to render detail from the fixed 90mm lens even when enlarged and printed for the office wall. I bought a &#34;near mint&#34; one from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ebay.co.uk/str/odacamerajapan&#34;&gt;ODA-Japan&lt;/a&gt; at the end of 2019 for over £500 including taxes and fees. From the listing:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Grade: Near Mint - Pre-owned, minimal signs of use. Appearance is very beautiful, tiny scuffs from normal use. It shows signs of use. *Please check photos. New Light Seals!! Optics:&lt;Finder&gt; Beautiful condition.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;None of those words, I have learned, describe the camera. I had been disappointed with some of the photos taken with it. This, for example, taken on Kinghorn Beach, I hoped would be much clearer:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/20-3-20-Pro50-8.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Parasurfers, Kinghorn Beach&lt;/strong&gt; Fuji GW690ii, Ilford Pan F Plus 50, f/11 at 1/60s&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes sharpness doesn&#39;t matter too much. This image, taken on a trip to the Faroes before the COVID lockdown, still looks pretty nice to me, not least because the Portra film I was using is just wonderful if you catch the light right:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Portra-160-2.4-Feb-13-2020-1-sm.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Huts near Vágar Airport&lt;/strong&gt; Fuji GW690ii, Kodak Portra 160, f/11 at 1/60s&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;two-nikon-fms&#34;&gt;Two Nikon FMs&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;My old Nikon FM, which went everywhere I did as I travelled with the military and then work from 1977 to the turn of the century, had been condemned by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hlehmann.co.uk/&#34;&gt;Lehmans&lt;/a&gt; as being beyond repair, specifically, the shutter mechanism, for which no spares are available. Its &#34;FULLY TESTED &lt;em&gt;EXCELLENT&lt;/em&gt;&#34; replacement I had bought from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ebay.co.uk/str/secameras&#34;&gt;SE Cameras&lt;/a&gt; (eBay) has never been right, showing light leaks and odd exposure variations. Here&#39;s an example:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/20-3-22-Delta-400-34.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Parasurfers at Kinghorn, Nikon FM&lt;/strong&gt;, Nikon AI-s 28mm f/2.8, Ilford Delta 400, f/16 at 1/125s. Yellow filter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The light leaks were particularly bad in a recent film - 20 of the 36 exposures were spoiled - and this is what triggered me to finally take action and get professional help.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-cla&#34;&gt;The CLA&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Practice makes perfect, they say, and they also say that a bad workman blames his tools. That said, I bet even Chippendale launched more than one of his chisels across the workshop on his learning journey. Ergo, I decided recently to get these cameras &#34;CLA&#34;-ed, or &lt;em&gt;clean, lubricate, and adjust&lt;/em&gt;-ed. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I took the two Nikons and the Fuji to a little repair shop in Morningside, Edinburgh and asked, if possible, for them to make one good camera out of the two Nikons, and fix any focusing problems there might be in the Fuji. All I really wanted to know is whether the criticism I have had of recent photographs is all down to poor technique, or whether it might - just might - be something to do with the camera.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I picked up the three cameras today, all in excellent working order, with a clear list of things that had been done to them and an assurance (and a reasonable limited warranty) that they are &#34;to specification&#34;. Can&#39;t wait to get out with some film in them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;lessons-learned&#34;&gt;Lessons learned&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Don&#39;t buy from eBay and expect things to be as described&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Get cameras that are new to you, checked and serviced&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Get your CLA done by a reputable, local repair shop&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;recommended-suppliers&#34;&gt;Recommended suppliers&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I buy (too much) film from &lt;a href=&#34;https://analoguewonderland.co.uk/&#34;&gt;Analogue Wonderland&lt;/a&gt;, and get it developed at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ag-photolab.co.uk/&#34;&gt;AG Photolab&lt;/a&gt;, who have been brilliant in helping me make sense of some of the recent exposure problems.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cameratiks.co.uk/&#34;&gt;Cameratiks&lt;/a&gt; in Edinburgh is staffed by calm, competent and polite people who know what they are doing. They are not cheap, nor are they expensive: you can buy quality digital and film gear there, and have them offer decent advice on the basis that you will go back there next time you need anything. That&#39;s my kind of business.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-07-30-film-cameras/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 14:16:02 -0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_created.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-07-30-film-cameras/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-07-30-film-cameras/</guid> </item> <item> <title>A few days in Assynt</title> <category>Apple iPhone</category> <category>Bergger Panchro</category> <category>Fuji GW690ii</category> <category>Fuji X</category> <category>Ilford Ortho</category> <category>Lomo Berlin</category> <category>Nikon FM</category> <category>Ricoh GRIII</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-few-days-in-assynt&#34;&gt;A few days in Assynt&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Holiday how the Scots do it&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF7259.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Achmelvich beach&lt;/strong&gt;, X-T2 XF35mm, ISO 1600 f/2 at 1/1000s&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Emerging confidently from weeks of COVID-19 lockdown and the sting of a cancelled Hebridean trip at Easter, we consoled ourselves with a few days immersed in the beauty of the Sutherland Assynt.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I went armed with a full complement of cameras (five - count them. Who needs five cameras?), most of which I now fit into a new kitBrick which I picked up at Tiso in Perth on the way up. Finally, I have a camera kit bag solution that works for all the gear I carry on a trip like this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;achmelvich&#34;&gt;Achmelvich&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The drive was long but pleasant, in a new (to us) Mercedes GLA, which is much more suited to the kind of driving one does on a trip to the Northwest of Scotland than the saloon it replaced. We took a look at Achmelvich beach after settling in to the apartment we had AirBnB&#39;d for a few nights. Everything seems booked up, which seems weird, given that there are almost no overseas visitors to these shores at present and the roads are almost utterly empty.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF7264.jpg&#34; title=&#34;Achmelvich beach&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Achmelvich beach&lt;/strong&gt; X-T2 XF35mm, ISO 1600 f/2 at 1/1000s&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We returned to Achmelvich a couple of times, well, because we love it, even if the weather doesn&#39;t always love us. The machair is in full bloom at the moment. The local people care for it by mowing swards through the meadow-like grass to encourage visitors not to trample randomly over the new growth. There are visitors here apart from ourselves: I edited out the tent on the beach in the next photo, because camping isn&#39;t allowed on the beach at Achmelvich.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF7292.jpg&#34; title=&#34;Achmelvich again&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Achmevlich beach&lt;/strong&gt; (long exposure) X-T2 XF16mm, ISO 200 f/16 at 20 s&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/img20200716_02.jpg&#34; title=&#34;Achmelvich again&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Achmevlich beach&lt;/strong&gt; (Panchro 400). The figure in the grass is Kara. Fuji GW690ii f/11 at 1/30s. Toning in Capture One. You can read more about this roll and how I developed it &lt;a href=&#34;/Exposures/2020/2020-07-12-Bergger-Panchro-400/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;stac-pollaidh&#34;&gt;Stac Pollaidh&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We took the walking route around Stac Pollaidh. There&#39;s a new, lottery-funded, improved path here to protect the slopes and give the old well-trodden path a chance to recover. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF7274-DSF7276.jpg&#34; title=&#34;Going up Stac Pollaidh&#34; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Going up Stac Pollaidh, looking East&lt;/strong&gt; X-T2 XF16mm, ISO 200 f/11 at 1/250s. Stitch of 3 images (Hugin)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/IMG_8838.jpg&#34; title=&#34;Going up Stac Pollaidh&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Going up Stac Pollaidh, looking South back towards the car park&lt;/strong&gt; iPhone 11 wide-angle&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although we hadn&#39;t really intended to, we took the higher path, and reached the ridge near the top, which in retrospect, is something we feel good about. Going the last few metres higher required better climbing experience, gear, or stupidity. Fortunately, we had left ours at the fork in the lower path.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/R0000589.jpg&#34; title=&#34;On the ridge&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On the ridge on Stac Pollaidh&lt;/strong&gt; Ricoh GRIII, taken by Kara&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-coigach-peninsula&#34;&gt;The Coigach peninsula&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;On a long meandering drive around the Coigach peninsula, the light changed constantly. Waze told us we were 2 hours from our apartment as we turned for home, yet only 37 km distant. This is because, perhaps, the twisty single-track roads ought to be driven only at 20 kph. The streams and foliage, deer and passing places pass by the window even at that speed, every now and then opening up wide open skies, the cotton grass stretching to the distant hills.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF7286-DSF7288.jpg&#34; title=&#34;Road to Achnahaird Bay&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Road to Achnahaird Bay&lt;/strong&gt; X-T2 XF16mm, ISO 320 f/16 at 1/125s. Stitch of 3 images (Hugin), cropped and coloured in Capture One Pro 20&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;... and the ever-present sheep.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/IMG_8855.jpg&#34; title=&#34;Two wanderers&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Two wanderers&lt;/strong&gt; iPhone 11 wide-angle&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;stoer-and-clachtoll&#34;&gt;Stoer and Clachtoll&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This holiday was a good way to get familiar with a new car and I felt comfortable enough after a day or so to take it off-road down to a fisheries bothy at Stoer. We got chatting to a ranger when were here last October about whales and dolphins. We had promised to send the Mercedes dealer a picture of the car from our trip.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/R0000623.jpg&#34; title=&#34;Mercedes GLA at Stoer&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The new Merc looking moody at Stoer&lt;/strong&gt; Ricoh GRIII, Silver Efex Pro 2.0&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of our favourite places (of all the favourite places we have around this part of Scotland) is Clachtoll beach, which at the time we visited, was at high tide. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/R0000611.jpg&#34; title=&#34;Clachtoll beach&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clachtoll beach&lt;/strong&gt; Ricoh GRIII, Capture One colour adjustments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;glencoe&#34;&gt;Glencoe&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The final day of our holiday was spent much further South, in Glencoe, stopping on the way down to make a brew and eat BLT sandwiches and cheese&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:cheese&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:cheese&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; on the gravelly beach at Loch Lochy. Even with a wind, that was paradise.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/IMG_8857.jpg&#34; title=&#34;Loch Lochy&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loch Lochy&lt;/strong&gt; iPhone 11 wide-angle&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We checked in to The Corran by the ferry terminal and headed straight out for a walk along the Coupall to catch some time with Buachaille Etive Mòr.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF7297.jpg&#34; title=&#34;The Buachaille&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buachaille Etive Mòr&lt;/strong&gt; X-T2 XF16mm, ISO 200 f/16 at 0.4 s&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a magical place, even in the rain. Actually, probably &lt;em&gt;especially&lt;/em&gt; in the rain. The heather and harebells, dancing in the wind to the syncopation of the river rushing over the rocks, flail and flutter, the great herdsman above, indifferent to their earnest performance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/R0000639.jpg&#34; title=&#34;Harebells&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harebells at Etive Mòr&lt;/strong&gt; Ricoh GRIII, ISO 400 f/16 at 1/40s&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The day&#39;s adventure concluded with a flaccid fish supper from the Quarrier&#39;s Kitchen in Ballachulish, before heading back to Corran to journal the day. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;home&#34;&gt;Home&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The drive home was wet but not without adventure as we stopped at Tindrum, more to support the business than to buy stuff we actually needed. We marvelled at how busy it was, and how heavy the Northbound traffic was, caravans and campers heading in droves for the NC500 and the midges.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We stopped briefly at Achnambeithatch, the little white cottage below Bidean nam Bian on the A82, to watch the weather for a while. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/R0000643.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Achnambeithatch&lt;/strong&gt; Ricoh GRIII, ISO 400 f/16 at 1/60 s&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We decided that the rain was in for the day, so headed South, and lunched at the King&#39;s House, as much to their delight as ours, emerging as they were for the first day back in business after months of COVID-19 closure. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are more images associated with this post, taken with the Nikon FM using &lt;a href=&#34;/Exposures/2020/2020-11-07-Ilford-orthochrome-80&#34;&gt;Ilford Orthochromatic film&lt;/a&gt;. I am a bit disappointed with the film photos on this trip. I hoped for better, sharper, images but am just not getting that with the big Fuji GW690ii at the moment. I am making errors, &lt;a href=&#34;/Exposures/2020/2020-06-07-Lomography-Potsdam-100&#34;&gt;losing an entire roll&lt;/a&gt; from an earlier trip by using stop bath instead of developer, and the &lt;a href=&#34;/Exposures/2020/2020-07-13-Lomography-Berlin-400&#34;&gt;Lomo Berlin&lt;/a&gt; film I had in the GW690iii on this trip, which I ruined by using the wrong developer. You live and learn. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:cheese&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cashel Blue, bought at the House of Bruar on the way up.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:cheese&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 1 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-07-14-assynt/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 14:16:01 -0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_created.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-07-14-assynt/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-07-14-assynt/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Sunshine walks with E100</title> <category>Kodak E100</category> <category>Nikon FM</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;sunshine-walks-with-e100&#34;&gt;Sunshine walks with E100&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Being in the sunshine with Kodak Ektachrome E100&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/img20200518_19184489.jpg&#34; /&gt;Frame 28. &lt;em&gt;Young tree shoots&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kodak Professional Ektachrome E100 is a new, fine grained colour transparency film perfectly suited to bright spring sunshine and the countryside. In good light, I have always favoured Kodak transparency film for colour saturation, so this first time out for me with Kodak&#39;s new T-grain modern slide film was a good exercise.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;soaking-up-the-sunshine-at-pattiesmuir&#34;&gt;Soaking up the sunshine at Pattiesmuir&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The April sun was splitting the sky, so we went out around Pattiesmuir, a local walking route which winds through rural pathways and copses, offering glimpses of the iconic Forth bridges and over rolling farmland.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/img20200518_17325634.jpg&#34; /&gt;Frame 3. &lt;em&gt;Pattiesmuir&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My wife and I have been going out with cameras for a number of years, both of us using Fuji X-series digital cameras usually. Recently, though, I have left the digital behind, and carried only a film camera. The more careful selections I am making is, I think, good for my photography because it slows me down and makes me think more carefully about framing, intent and especially the light. As a result, I do not take as many frames as I would with a digital camera in my hands. I find it hard to finish a roll of 36 in one go, and today was no exception. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;norton-common&#34;&gt;Norton Common&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I next picked up the camera when, on another sunny day, we took ourselves on a bitter-sweet reflective walk on Norton Common. Earlier that day, we had said goodbye to my beloved Mum and it felt right to take ourselves to this special place in my old hometown. We found deer, and squirrels, sunbeams and forget-me-nots there, all of which seemed to be speaking to us in some way that was comforting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/img20200518_19103767.jpg&#34; /&gt;Frame 24. &lt;em&gt;Forget-me-nots&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We had stayed in a little Air B&amp;amp;B in the pretty village of Great Wymondley, the smaller of the two Wymondleys, not far from the A1. The country kitchen of the old stable block featured a table where we had sat in the sunrays and listened to the voices of the host&#39;s children playing at the big house. There were poppies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/img20200518_19224915.jpg&#34; /&gt;Frame 30 &lt;em&gt;Poppies&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;rosyth&#34;&gt;Rosyth&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The remaining half dozen frames were made on short exercise trips out the back door and into the park during the continuing COVID-19 restrictions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/img20200518_19410207.jpg&#34; /&gt;Frame 35 &lt;em&gt;Blossom&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Blossom is so photogenic, and we are lucky to be living in a place where there is plenty to be found at this time of year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-camera&#34;&gt;The camera&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The camera I used for this roll was an eBay-sourced Nikon FM of similar vintage to my old FM, whose shutter was sadly condemned last year. It feels very similar but different, not least because the focusing screen is quite mucky, which reminds me every time I frame a shot that this is a substitute for my &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; Nikon FM. It&#39;s just not the same. I am loving the lens, however, which is the superb AI-s 28mm f/2.8 which gives excellent results across a range of apertures.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Colour positive (slide) film, cost £14 per roll from Analog Wonderland. Exposed between 4th and 28th April 2020. Sent to AG for processing at £8.98, works out at about 64p per shot.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Brand&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Type&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;ISO&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Format&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Exposures&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Camera&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Lens&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Kodak&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Ektachrome E100&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;100&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;35mm&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;36&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Nikon FM&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Nikon AI-s 28mm f/2.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;Frame&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Image&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Aperture&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Shutter&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Comment&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;1.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Golf Course&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/16&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Charles Hill Beach&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;2.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Crows&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/16&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/60s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;3.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Landscape&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/16&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Pattiesmuir, 7th April&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;4.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Log 1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;5.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Log 2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/2.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/1000s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;6.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Leaves&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/2.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/1000s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;7.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Mushroom&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/5.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;8.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Post top&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/500s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;9.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Pattiesmuir trees&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/16&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;10.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Tank with fence&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/16&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;11.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Sign&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;12.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Mushrooms&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;13.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Forth bridges&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/16&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;14.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Forget-me-not&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/1000s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;15.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Gorse&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/5.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/500s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;16.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The Common&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Norton 14th April&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;17.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Blossom&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/5.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;not sure of shutter&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;18.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Smoke&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/5.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;19.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Forget-me-not&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/5.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/30s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;20.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Forget-me-not&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/60s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;21.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Canopy&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;22.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Tunnel&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/30s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;23.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Forget-me-nots&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/2.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;24.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Forget-me-nots&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/60s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;25.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Forget-me-nots&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/2.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/500&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;26.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Woods&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/2.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/60s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;27.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Common lane&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/60s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;28.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Young tree shoots&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/2.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/500s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;29.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Poppy&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/2.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/500&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;15th April, Great Wymondley&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;30.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Poppies&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/5.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/250&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;31.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Swan&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Rosyth park, 23rd April&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;32.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Blossom&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/2.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/500s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;33.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Blossom tree&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;34.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Braefoot Lane&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/60s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Braefoot, 28th April&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;35.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Blossom&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/1000s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;36.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Blossom&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/1000s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-05-18-sunshine-walks/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 14:16:00 -0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_created.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-05-18-sunshine-walks/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-05-18-sunshine-walks/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Lost and found: Images recovered from found film</title> <category>Coronet Consul</category> <category>Kodak Verichrome</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;lost-and-found-images-recovered-from-found-film&#34;&gt;Lost and found: Images recovered from found film&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/20-4-4-Kodak-Verichrome-1.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Unknown family group&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, my wife was given a box of cameras and bits, including an old Coronet Consul box camera. Recently, we dug it out and I had a play around with it. It was absolutely goosed&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:fubar&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:fubar&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, but it did contain a roll of exposed film. Having recently started playing with home development, I binned the camera and processed the roll in Rodinal R09, just to see what we might find. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I thought we might find some pictures of my wife&#39;s family back in the day, but it seems the uncle who gifted the box had picked the camera up at a car boot sale. I scanned a couple of frames and put them into Capture One to tweak the exposure and try to recover as much as I could. The header on this page is an example, and I have no idea who these people are. It looks like a nice family enjoying a proper British 1960&#39;s holiday on the Costa Brava.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Brand&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Type&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;ISO&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Format&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Exposures&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Camera&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Kodak&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Verichrome Pan&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;125&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;120&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Coronet Consul&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;Frame&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Image&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Aperture&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Shutter&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;1-4.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Family group&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;unknown&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;unknown&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;5-6.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Garden images&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;unknown&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;unknown&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;7-8.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Blank&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:fubar&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;FUBAR, BER, FBR, knackered, broken, done for, deid.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:fubar&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 1 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-04-11-lost-and-found/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 14:15:59 -0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_created.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-04-11-lost-and-found/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-04-11-lost-and-found/</guid> <enclosure url="https://niximagery.com//img/20-4-4-Kodak-Verichrome-1.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="None" /> </item> <item> <title>First experiences with Ilford Delta 400 35mm film.</title> <category>Ilford Delta</category> <category>Nikon FM</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;first-experiences-with-ilford-delta-400-35mm-film&#34;&gt;First experiences with Ilford Delta 400 35mm film.&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/20-3-22-Delta-400-5.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Earlsferry, Fife.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ilford Delta is a well-known black and white film from the famous UK manufacturer that has been around for almost 30 years. I put a roll of 400 through a Nikon FM. This post describes some of the images I made and what I did with them. The film was exposed over the first few weeks of 2020 and sent to AG Photographic in Birmingham for developing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;harlow-water&#34;&gt;Harlow Water&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We had to take a trip to Essex in January and had time to take a walk along the River Stort that runs through a generic-looking town on the outskirts of London. The river seems clean enough to sustain life, as there were people fishing along the banks. The first image here is a crop: bottom right you can see fading from what looks like a light leak in the camera. I think it&#39;s something to do with the back plate. I bought this camera from eBay to replace my original 1970s Nikon FM that has a condemned shutter, and the back doesn&#39;t shut cleanly with the satisfying click of my original.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/20-3-22-Delta-400-18.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Harlow Water&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not sure I&#39;d be eating any of the fish they caught, as there were dog walkers kicking their poochy-poo directly from where it was dropped on the tow path into the river. I asked one of the fishermen if this is normal behaviour round here. He said everybody did it. I was disappointed with that level of cultural disrespect amongst the dog-walking people of this town towards their environment. Despite being in the middle of an industrial estate, this little stretch of river, with its abandoned house-boats, is pretty, and no doubt home to a lot of life. It&#39;s worth exploring - there&#39;s more information &lt;a href=&#34;https://canalrivertrust.org.uk/places-to-visit/harlow&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/20-3-22-Delta-400-19.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Harlow Water&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next image has been adjusted for tone in Capture One for a more vintage look. This might offend some &#34;analogue&#34; purists but I&#39;m just playing here. There aren&#39;t any rules, and Capture One is a nice tool for messing about with images that might otherwise be considered uninteresting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/20-3-22-Delta-400-20.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Harlow Mill&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-fife-coast&#34;&gt;The Fife Coast&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I next picked up the camera, we were up the &lt;a href=&#34;/2020/03/08/the-east-neuk.html&#34;&gt;East Neuk&lt;/a&gt;. I continued the split toning exercise with the next two frames, toning the shadows blue and the highlights in the complementary yellow.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/20-3-22-Delta-400-22.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bass Rock&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here, the Forth River basks in sunrays from an approaching storm. The toning enhances, I think the menacing clouds and waters. For monochrome images, it might seem weird to re-introduce colour but I think as an artistic technique, it enhances these shore photos. It didn&#39;t work for me with the Harlow Water images.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/20-3-22-Delta-400-26.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Forth River&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;kinghorn-beach&#34;&gt;Kinghorn Beach&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The last of these photographs was taken a few days later, down on the beach at Kinghorn. It is untoned but suffers with the same light leak problem I talked about above. This image was taken in portrait orientation and cropped slightly to make use of the false flare. I think it looks OK.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/20-3-22-Delta-400-34.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kinghorn&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary-of-the-results&#34;&gt;Summary of the results&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reviews of this film suggest that it is very sharp, although I am sure that this is true only when in better hands. I am not convinced that I get the best results by sending it to AG Photographic, although I don&#39;t doubt they are the best of the labs out there. Perhaps this is just a manifestation of the Dunning-Kruger effect and I&#39;ll change my mind once I learn more about it. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I took a roll of photographs back in the 1970&#39;s and 1980&#39;s, I would consider it a success if I got one or two good frames from a roll of 135. I think I have half a dozen here that I&#39;m pleased with, despite the leaky light problem. A significant factor in this increased success rate must be the greater opportunity there is to work with the images post-processing. Even the scanning tool &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:SF8&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:SF8&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; allows me to straighten the horizon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;next-steps&#34;&gt;Next steps&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I will try this film again and process it myself to see if I get better results, but also maybe I ought to stop buying old cameras online and expecting them to perform optimally without at least letting someone who knows what they are doing check them over for me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/20-3-22-Delta-400-24.jpg&#34; /&gt;Frame 24 &lt;em&gt;Bass Rocks&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This film was in my Nikon FM between 10th January and 14th March 2020. It was processed by AG Photolab. I switched lens part way through this film to a new 28mm f/2.8 Nikon which is very much better than the E series lens I had been using. At the same time, I added a Tiffen Yellow filter which made sky contrast much better too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Brand&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Type&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;ISO&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Format&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Exposures&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Camera&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Lens&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Ilford&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Delta&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;400&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;35mm&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;36&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Nikon FM&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Frames 1 - 20 Nikon 50mm f/1.8 Series E&lt;br/&gt;Frames 20 - 36 Nikon AI-s 28mm f/2.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;Frame&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Image&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Aperture&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Shutter&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Comment&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;1.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Euston&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/2s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;10 Jan. Hand held&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;2.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Preston station&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/4s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;3.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Preston station&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/15s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;4.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Preston station&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/1.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;5.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Earlsferry&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/16&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;12th Jan.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;6.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Shore&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;7.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Waves&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/1000s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;8.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/15s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;9.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/250s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;10.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/16&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/60s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Hand held&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;11.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Sunset&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;12-13.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Birds&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/250s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;14.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/250s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;15-17.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Crashing waves&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/2.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/1000s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;18.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Harlow water&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/60s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;18th Jan&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;19.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Harlow water&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/30s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;20.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Harlow mill lock 8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;River stort&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;21.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Culross sunset&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/5.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;26 Feb 28mm lens yellow filter&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;22.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Bass rock thru wall&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;8 March 28mm lens yellow filter - The East Neuk&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;23.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;KM at work&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/60s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Hand held&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;24.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Bass rocks&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/16&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;25-6.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Shafts/Edinburgh&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/16&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;27.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Shafts&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/60&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;28-30.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;shafts and rainbow&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/60s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;31-36.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Kinghorn Beach&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/16&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/500s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;14th March&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:SF8&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;SilverFast 8, which is actually bloody awful software with a functionality and interface from the 1990&#39;s. This software came with the Epson V600 scanner I bought from Wex and was provided by Epson because their own software doesn&#39;t work at all with OSX.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:SF8&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 1 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-03-22-delta-400/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 14:15:57 -0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_created.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-03-22-delta-400/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-03-22-delta-400/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Beach Stories</title> <category>Fuji X</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;beach-stories&#34;&gt;Beach Stories&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Imagined back stories of things found on the beach&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/beach-stories/breakwater.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;The famous breakwater at St. Monans, Fife.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most of these images were made in November 2019 at Clashnessie, in the Assynt, and all of them were made with the Fuji X-T2 camera and the Fujinon XF16mm F1.4 R WR lens at ISO 200.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-backwards-aerial-with-half-twist&#34;&gt;The backwards aerial with half twist&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/beach-stories/the-backwards-aerial-with-half-twist.jpg&#34; /&gt;A difficult manoeuvre to perform with grace, it can be done with concentration and a great deal of practice. She had thought mindfully all morning as she prepared, emptying her head of distractions and day to day concerns. When the moment came, she was ready: time stood still and the crowd were hushed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;epsilon&#34;&gt;Epsilon&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/beach-stories/epsilon.jpg&#34; /&gt;Berry-like prophecies of Christmas coming, arms reaching forward in time. I thought I could see the shape of a letter E, moving to the right of frame.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-argentine-tango&#34;&gt;The Argentine Tango&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/beach-stories/the-argentine-tango.jpg&#34; /&gt;Carlos and Eva seemed to defy the laws of gravity as they danced their contragiros. Onlookers would gasp as she poured herself over his limbs in a steamy, sensuous, syncopated embrace.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;kestrel&#34;&gt;Kestrel&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/beach-stories/kestrel.jpg&#34; /&gt;He glides, and hovers on the imperceptible breeze, scanning for little violet trickles and traces that betray the poor vole, scurrying, hopping, scampering along, cursing his evolutionary luck.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Image&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Camera&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Lens&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Film/ISO&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Aperture&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Shutter&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Comment&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;St. Monans breakwater&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Fuji X-T2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Fujinon XF16mm F1.4 R WR&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;ISO 200&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/60s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The backwards aerial&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Fuji X-T2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Fujinon XF16mm F1.4 R WR&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;ISO 200&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/5.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/200s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Epsilon&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Fuji X-T2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Fujinon XF16mm F1.4 R WR&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;ISO 200&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/5.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The Argentine Tango&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Fuji X-T2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Fujinon XF16mm F1.4 R WR&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;ISO 200&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/320s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Kestrel&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Fuji X-T2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Fujinon XF16mm F1.4 R WR&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;ISO 200&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/5.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/200s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;All images on this page were processed from the RAW file in Capture One Pro 20.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-03-16-beach-stories/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 14:15:56 -0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_created.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-03-16-beach-stories/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-03-16-beach-stories/</guid> </item> <item> <title>The East Neuk</title> <category>Apple iPhone</category> <category>Fuji GW690ii</category> <category>Ilford Delta</category> <category>Ilford PanF Plus</category> <category>Nikon FM</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-east-neuk&#34;&gt;The East Neuk&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sunday 8th March, 2020. &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/IMG_8646.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rainbow over Earlsferry&lt;/em&gt; iPhone&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We love a road trip and had been promising ourselves a little get-away day for the past couple of weeks. Having worked together all morning to tidy the house, we finally sorted the camera gear and jumped in the car to head up the coast of Fife towards the East Neuk and the little town of Earlsferry.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;earlsferry&#34;&gt;Earlsferry&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We went to the shore at the Western edge of the town to exercise ourselves and our gear. Kara was keen to get some long exposures and I went looking for contrast as I had both the Fuji GW and Nikon FM loaded with black and white film&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:exp&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:exp&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. This is Bass Rock, taken with the Fuji:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/20-3-20-Pro50-1.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bass Rock through wall&lt;/em&gt; Fuji GW690ii, Ilford Pan F Plus 50 f/22 at 1/15s&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The same view, in Delta 400, taken with the Nikon FM and post-processed in Capture One Pro:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/20-3-22-Delta-400-22.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bass Rock&lt;/em&gt; Nikon FM AI-s 28mm f/2.8, Delta 400 f/22 at 1/125s. Yellow filter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The difference between the above two images goes beyond what you see, which is as much down to what I did with the image after it was developed as it is the difference in the two cameras. The Fuji is a medium format camera and produces negatives which are 6cm by 9cm in size: six times larger than those produced in the 35mm Nikon FM. This only really makes a difference if you want to make very large prints from the negatives, when the limitations of the photographer are as significant as anything else. This, I think, will torment me for the next few years as I develop and learn. What this big Fuji isn&#39;t going to do, I am learning, is give me 350 mega-pixel images in super-sharp crispy detail, not at least until I learn how to manage and operate the equipment better.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Nikon made some more good images of the wonderful coastline here. I was using a Tiffen yellow filter to give contrast and texture in the sky at the same time as sustaining details in the shadows.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/20-3-22-Delta-400-24.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Forth&lt;/em&gt; Nikon FM AI-s 28mm f/2.8, Delta 400 f/16 at 1/125s. Yellow filter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;stmonans-and-anstruther&#34;&gt;St.Monans and Anstruther&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;St Monans is famous for its zig-zag breakwater but is also where Kara&#39;s family have deep fishing roots. We drove around the town and enjoyed a brilliant sky as the weather pushed and tugged at the air over the Forth Estuary, making rainshafts, cloud patterns, whooping, whacking waves on the rocks and double bows over the Eastern landscape. Food lust overcame us, so we headed for the world-famous Anstruther chippie and enjoyed proper fish and chips in the car as it got dark.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:exp&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Exposure logs &lt;a href=&#34;/Exposures/2020/2020-03-10-Ilford-Pan/&#34;&gt;here (Pan F)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;/Exposures/2020/2020-03-14-Ilford-Delta-400/&#34;&gt;here (Delta)&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:exp&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 1 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-03-08-the-east-neuk/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 16:01:08 -0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_created.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-03-08-the-east-neuk/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-03-08-the-east-neuk/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Kinghorn Beach</title> <category>Agfa Isolette</category> <category>Fuji GW690ii</category> <category>Ilford PanF Plus</category> <category>Kodak Kodacolor</category> <category>Ricoh GRIII</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;kinghorn-beach&#34;&gt;Kinghorn Beach&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Saturday 14th March, 2020. With the COVID-19 pandemic evolving around us, a spot of sea air was in order, so we drove along the coast to Kinghorn.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/R0000538.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Riding the storm&lt;/em&gt; Ricoh GRIII&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;new-friends&#34;&gt;New friends&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had film to finish off in the Texas Leica, my Nikon FM&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:exp&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:exp&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and my newest and cheapest (so far) camera, an Agfa Isolette I which arrived with half a roll of (I think) unexposed Kodacolor II still in it. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.photomemorabilia.co.uk/Colour_Darkroom/Early_Kodak_CameraFilm.html#anchorK11&#34;&gt;This post&lt;/a&gt; tells me that this film was rated at 100 ASA and went out of production in 1983. I don&#39;t expect very much from the three or four images I made with it, but it was fun trying out this old toy. The lens seems a little grubby but otherwise the camera seems to be clean and in good order for its age, and worth the £18 punted on it on eBay. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Isolette.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Isolette&lt;/em&gt; by iPhone&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;/Stories/2020/2020-03-21-1983-kodacolorII/&#34;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt; for how the images from this film turned out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;beach-life&#34;&gt;Beach life&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The sky over Edinburgh across the Forth was pretty dramatic, so we were excited to see a group of parasurfers setting up and enjoying the elements. There was a stiff breeze as the tide was coming in, so the waves were expressive and obviously not a small challenge for the boys and girls braving the wind chill. We had our own challenge with the rapidly incoming tide.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/20-3-20-Pro50-8.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Parasurfers&lt;/em&gt; Fuji GW690ii Ilford Pan F Plus 50 f/11 at 1/60s. Brightened and split toned in Capture One.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:exp&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Exposure logs &lt;a href=&#34;/Exposures/2020/2020-03-10-Ilford-Pan/&#34;&gt;here (Pan F)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;/Exposures/2020/2020-03-14-Ilford-Delta-400/&#34;&gt;here (Delta)&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:exp&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 1 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-03-14-kinghorn-beach/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 16:01:08 -0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_created.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-03-14-kinghorn-beach/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-03-14-kinghorn-beach/</guid> </item> <item> <title>1983 Kodacolor II film</title> <category>Agfa Isolette</category> <category>Kodak Kodacolor</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;1983-kodacolor-ii-film&#34;&gt;1983 Kodacolor II film&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;How I got on with an old film found in a cheap camera.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;admonition quote&#34;&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;admonition-title&#34;&gt;Robert Bresson&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Make visible, what without you, might perhaps never have been seen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/20-3-20-KodacolorII-1a.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kinghorn, 2020&lt;/em&gt; f/22 at 1/200s &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;a href=&#34;/Stories/2020/2020-03-14-kinghorn-beach/&#34;&gt;recent post&lt;/a&gt;, I mentioned that I had bought a new-to-me Agfa Isolette I camera. In it, I discovered as I opened the back, was an old roll of Kodacolor II. I closed the back and rolled it on to the next frame. A couple of days later, when my wife and I went to the beach for some relief from the emerging COVID-19 situation, I took the camera along.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;exposure-heuristics&#34;&gt;Exposure heuristics&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the beach, having not really thought about it properly, I decided to finish the film off. The Isolette doesn&#39;t have a meter, and I&#39;d forgotten my Gossen, so I figured I&#39;d give the &#34;Sunny 16&#34; rule a try. This goes something like: &#34;if it&#39;s sunny, and you&#39;re shooting at f/16, then the shutter speed is the inverse of the film speed.&#34; I later discovered that this fim had a speed rating of 100 ASA, but at the time I guessed that it might be a 400, so went for a shutter speed of 1/200th of a second at f/22. This blunder might have been mitigated against by the well-known heuristic or rule-of-thumb for expired films stock, which suggests that you should treat the film as being slower by 1 stop for every decade it is out of date. So, I should have rated the original 100 ASA film at 25. If all of those estimates and rules were correct, I was effectively underexposing on the beach by about 4 stops. They weren&#39;t.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;results&#34;&gt;Results&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The film was turned round by the brilliant &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ag-photolab.co.uk/&#34;&gt;AG Photolab&lt;/a&gt; in double-quick time, and I got to the scanner to have a look at these images. I wasn&#39;t expecting stellar quality images and wasn&#39;t disappointed. I pulled the scans into Capture One to see if I could do anything but in the end, I just cropped and exported them. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-effect-of-age-on-film-emulsion&#34;&gt;The effect of age on film emulsion&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The recent exposures at Kinghorn show quite a lot of fogging and what looks to me like a fungal film over the whole frame. There is evidence of light leaking into the frame at the top and bottom. I can&#39;t explain this because the back of the camera hinges open - the central frames I inadvertently exposed when I opened the camera when I first unpacked it are as you&#39;d expect. The red fog at the edges appears across the whole film. This is one of the frames exposed last week:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/20-3-20-KodacolorII-10.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kinghorn beach&lt;/em&gt; Isolette I, f/22 at 1/200s. Recent exposure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;history-in-the-roll&#34;&gt;History in the roll&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The exposures from the beginning of the film were perhaps made when it was put into the back of the cupboard, or wherever, back in the 1980s when this little Isolette was last used before finding itself washed up on eBay. I have no idea where they were taken but the houses look familiar, as if in a garden city like Letchworth or Rosyth. The colours are endearing, unsurprisingly retro, perhaps.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/20-3-20-KodacolorII-1.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rose garden&lt;/em&gt;, one of the &#34;found&#34; exposures in the old film.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This was fun. I think I&#39;ll try to clean up the camera a bit and try another roll.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;exposure-notes&#34;&gt;Exposure notes&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Exposed on 14th March 2020, sent to AG for processing at £3.49 plus £1.17 pp.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Brand&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Type&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;ISO&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Format&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Exposures&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Camera&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Lens&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Kodak&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Kodacolor II&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;100&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;120&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;12&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Agfa Isolette I&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Agfa Agnar 1:4.5/85&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;Frame&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Image&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Aperture&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Shutter&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;1-8.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Garden images, possibly from around 1983 ?&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;unknown&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;unknown&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;9.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;I opened the back, dammit&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;10-12.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Kinghorn Beach 14th March&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;1/200s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-03-21-1983-kodacolorII/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 16:01:08 -0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_created.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-03-21-1983-kodacolorII/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-03-21-1983-kodacolorII/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Pattiesmuir and Portra</title> <category>Kodak Portra</category> <category>Nikon FM</category> <category>Ricoh GRIII</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;pattiesmuir-and-portra&#34;&gt;Pattiesmuir and Portra&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/R0000549.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pattiesmuir, Ricoh GRIII&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We took a walk down at Pattiesmuir again, because we can and we need to. I took my Nikon FM loaded with Kodak Portra 800 this time, and my little Ricoh GR III in my pocket. This gave me a picture to share on Instagram (above) when we got home - with a fresh 36-exposure roll of Portra, which I got developed later&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:july&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:july&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This little place is a secret haven for photographers, it&#39;s so photogenic and variable with the seasons. The bluebells are coming, after the last frosts have become ancient history. The wild garlic is flowering, too, and the whole place, with its gnarled stumps and undergrowth on the hill, is magical.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;portra-800&#34;&gt;Portra 800&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Kodak-Portra-800-135-20200722_09.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Still life&lt;/em&gt; Portra 800, Nikon FM, AI-s 28mm f/2.8 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The film I started on this outing was pretty much wasted, as most of the shots had what I described as &#34;flare&#34;. AG, the film processing business I use, were very helpful and suggested these were light leaks in the camera - I put the Nikon in for a proper clean, lube, adjust and had the light seals replaced. The Fuji GW690ii also, and my old Nikon FM body. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think that when everything works (i.e. the camera, the operator), this film stock works really well, even if at the moment most of what I am taking is pretty dull stuff.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Kodak-Portra-800-135-20200722_06.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clematis&lt;/strong&gt; Portra 800, Nikon FM, AI-s 28mm f/2.8 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Colour negative film, cost £12.50 per roll from Analog Wonderland. Loaded 28th April 2020, finished 12 July. Sent to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ag-photolab.co.uk/&#34;&gt;AG Photolab&lt;/a&gt; for processing: £3.49 plus £3.49 P&amp;amp;P. About 54p per image.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;Frame&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Image&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Aperture&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Shutter&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Comment&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;1.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Wild garlic&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/5.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/250s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Pattiesmuir 30 April&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;2.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Portal&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/16&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/250s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;flare&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;3.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Field&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/16&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/500 s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;4.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Bluebell stump&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;5.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Horse chestnut&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/2.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/500s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;flare&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;6.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Post&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/5.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/500s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;flare&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;7.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Bluebells&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/2.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/1000s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;flare&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;8.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Bluebells&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/2.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/1000s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;9.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Clematis&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/5.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/1000s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;2 May, The Artist&#39;s Garden&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;10.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Lane&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Braefoot May 4th - flare&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;11.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Moon&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/500s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;flare&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;12.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Lines&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/250s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;flare&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;13.,14.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Bluebell&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;flare&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;15.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Lime tree&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/5.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;16.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Narcissus&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/1000s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;flare&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;17.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Scots pine&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/16&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;flare&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;18.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Pine&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;flare&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;19.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Moon tree&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/500s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;20.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Different Moon tree&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/500s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;flare&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;21.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Bitch teeth&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/500s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;flare&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;22.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Fruit bowl&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/2.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Home 8th May&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;23.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Fruit bowl&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/5.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;flare&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;24.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Campion&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/1000s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;flare&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;25.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Campion&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/2.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/250s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;flare&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;26.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Shoe tree&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/500s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;flare&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;27.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Selfie&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/2.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/30s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;hh 21st April - bad focus&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;28.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Kinghorn beach&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/1000s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;27 Jun&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;29.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Kara&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/1000s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;27 Jun - flare&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;30.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Beach at Achmelvich&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;11 July flare&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;31.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Beach at Achmelvich&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;flare&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;32.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Canisp, Suilven, Stac Pollaidh&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/250s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;12 July&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;33.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Canisp, Suilven, Stac Pollaidh&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/16&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/1000s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;34.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Swimmers at Achmahaird Bay, Assynt&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/16&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/1000s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;35.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Achmahaird Bay, Assynt&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/16&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/1000s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;36.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Achmahaird Bay, Assynt&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/500s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;37.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Achmahaird Bay, Assynt&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/500s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;flare&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:july&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Eventually, this was in July. I finished the roll during our &lt;a href=&#34;/Stories/2020/2020-07-14-assynt&#34;&gt;trip to Assynt&lt;/a&gt; and had it processed at AG Photo Labs.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:july&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 1 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-04-30-pattiesmuir/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 16:01:08 -0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_created.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-04-30-pattiesmuir/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-04-30-pattiesmuir/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Five films</title> <category>Cinestill</category> <category>Fuji GW690ii</category> <category>Hasselblad V</category> <category>Ilford Delta</category> <category>Kodak E100</category> <category>Kodak Portra</category> <category>Lomo Metropolis</category> <category>Nikon FM</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;five-films&#34;&gt;Five films&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;More random rolls from the COVID era&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Kodak-Ektachrome-E100-20210730_20010914.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;February sunset at Patteismuir&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Continuing the series of films I had lost track of this year, there were another five exposed films kicking about with only partial notes and recall to record them. Again, using my new Digitaliza film holders and a new MacBook Air, the scans were interesting. In this series:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Brand&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Type&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;ISO&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Format&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Exposures&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Camera&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Lens&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Kodak&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Ektachrome E100&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;100&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;120&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Fuji GW690ii&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;90mm&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Cinestill&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;800 T&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;800&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;35mm&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;36&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Nikon FM&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Nikon AI-s 28mm f/2.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Lomography&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Metropolis&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;EI 400&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;120&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;12&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Hasselblad 503CW&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Zeiss 80mm F2.8 C&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Ilford&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Delta&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;3200&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;35mm&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;36&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Nikon FM&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Nikon AI-s 28mm f/2.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Kodak&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Portra&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;160&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;35mm&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;36&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Nikon FM&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Nikon AI-s 28mm f/2.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ektachrome&#34;&gt;Ektachrome&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am becoming a big fan of Kodak&#39;s modern slide film: no big surprise, really, because years ago I favoured Kodachrome and Agfa&#39;s transparency film in my Nikon FM. Here, a few frames in the huge Fuji GW690ii 6 x 9 camera taken around Kilconquhar and St Monans around 9th April. Scanned at 3200 dpi, the digital images are about 80 mega pixels in size, although sharpness doesn&#39;t satisfy the pixel-neurotic: it&#39;s colours that make these images worth making.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Kodak-Ektachrome-E100-20210730_20292470.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Church at Kilconquhar. Fuji GW690ii, Ektachrome E100&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The composition here isn&#39;t perfect: it was tempting to crop out the part-of-a-treee on the left of this picture but there is something in me that wants to crop and adjust as little as possible. I can see what I was thinking with the line of the path central to the composition and am pleased that I kept these parallel to the lines of the church tower. There&#39;s always a bit of difference between what you see in the rangefinder window and the image on the film so I consider this a successful image.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Kodak-Ektachrome-E100-20210730_20370722.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kilconquhar. Fuji GW690ii, Ektachrome E100&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I like the colours in this image taken at the loch, facing in the other direction, a few paces from where I captured the church. The complementary sky and grass tones here work for me. What is most impressive with this film stock is that there is almost no post processing required -- the header sunset image taken in February at Pattiesmuir shows this, I think, as well as these snaps from Kilconquhar and St. Monans. Sunlight and good skies are a real bonus too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Kodak-Ektachrome-E100-20210730_20451049.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;St. Monan&#39;s harbour. Fuji GW690ii, Ektachrome E100&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Taken from the walk down to the famous wonky sea wall at St. Monans, this again might have been cropped on the left if it had been a digital capture. I love the two-weather sky here.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cinestill-800t&#34;&gt;Cinestill 800T&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Cinestill-800T-20210731_18185960.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Flowers at Dumbarnie Links, Nikon FM, Cinestill 800T&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cinestill 800T is a fast popular film stock, with the &#34;T&#34; indicating that it is designed to be used in tungsten light. It&#39;s ideal for shooting urban scenes at night, which was my intention when I bought a few rolls of 135 and 120 at the beginning of 2021. This first roll was exposed in April in a Nikon FM in daylight at Seafield Beach, Dumbarnie Links (frames 16--25) and Elie (frames 26ff). Scanning as before, I processed them in Capture One, severely adjusting white balance and contrast to compensate for the blue shift of the abused film.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Cinestill-800T-20210731_18112996.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Seafield Beach. Nikon FM, Cinestill 800T&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This seemed to do the trick, rendering colours realistically with only two slider adjustments off the scanner. I&#39;m learning to not allow the scanner to do anything with the colour of the files it creates. The above image of flowers at Dumbarnie Links illustrates this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m generally pleased with the results if not a little &lt;em&gt;meh&lt;/em&gt; about my collection of dead boring images. Cinestill 800T is an exciting film to use for exciting images: punchy urban scenes evocative of some other era or dark filmic concepts. It&#39;s not really meant for landscapes taken on walks, the purpose of which was not photography but clearing heads. I hope my next set of images with this film stock will do it better justice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Cinestill-800T-20210731_18550535.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Elie Beach. Nikon FM, Cinestill 800T&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I do like the rendering of contrast and tone in this film, once adjusted. Below, Lady&#39;s Tower on a sunny day in Fife gives the film a chance to show this to create a nice image that evokes the feeling of the moment it was captured. More than that, I guess, can&#39;t be asked for.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Cinestill-800T-20210731_19054350.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lady&#39;s Tower, Elie. Nikon FM, Cinestill 800T&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;lomography-metropolis&#34;&gt;Lomography Metropolis&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Lomochrome-Metropolis-EI400-20210801_12592490.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;St. Monans, Fife. Hasselblad 503CW, 80mm Zeiss.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This film stock was introduced in 2019 as a new film emulsion with extended range, meaning that the sensitivity is stated on the box as ISO 100 -- 400 and you take your pick. I exposed this roll at the higher speed to see how it worked there. As with all of the films in this mini-series, I got AG Photographic to develop them for me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Lomochrome-Metropolis-EI400-20210801_13364835.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bass Rock from Crail. Hasselblad 503CW, 80mm Zeiss.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I first scanned this roll using 48-bit colour and 6400 dpi settings which produced square image files post-processing of about 180 megapixels. The colours are muted and cool. It took some time to find the correct white balance adjustment in Capture One but I think the image of St Monans church in Fife is a fair rendition of the film&#39;s character. I like that the contrast is strong. You will not see the Hasselblad notches in that image because, as with many of my hand-held photographs, the horizon was a bit squint, as they say around here, so I had to adjust it and crop.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Lomochrome-Metropolis-EI400-20210801_13364835-1.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Crail, Fife. Hasselblad 503CW, 80mm Zeiss.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This was the last useful frame off the roll, as some time later, during a visit to the Hermitage at Dunkeld, I reached for the Hasselblad and forgot there was film in it. Sheer stupidity caused me to open the film back to load a new film without first checking the clever mechanical indicator on the cartridge. I&#39;m going to say that I will not do that again but then again I also say that my next car will be a Maserati.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ilford-delta-3200&#34;&gt;Ilford Delta 3200&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Ilford-Delta-3200-20210801_17251720-1.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;St.Monans Harbour. Nikon FM, 28mm f/1.4 AiS&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As this is a black and white film, I might have developed this myself but as with all of the films in this mini-series, I got AG Photographic to develop it for me. It was scanned at 6400, then 3200 dpi in 24-bit colour (otherwise the scanner screws up the colour profile in the output file). In post-processing, the profile is switched to black and white. The early images were not of good enough resolution to justify 6400 dpi, hence the switch to something lower.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Ilford-Delta-3200-20210801_16112152.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Edinburgh, from Fife. Nikon FM, 28mm f/1.4 AiS&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most of those early frames were quite disappointing, being underexposed and losing detail in the shadows. I&#39;m fairly sure this was a metering issue: I rely on the built-in LED through-the-lens metering when shooting with the Nikon FM and this might be the price of laziness. Some can be recovered, though, and this image shows a sort of moody shoreline to illustrate the point.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Ilford-Delta-3200-20210801_17025154.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Edinburgh. Nikon FM, 28mm f/1.4 AiS&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the view from my office window on the Holyrood campus. Delta 3200 might suggest a good low-light film but I think it&#39;s more fast than it is good in the dark. It needs light to function properly. The next image also, perhaps, is more suited to the grainy emulsion of Delta 3200.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Ilford-Delta-3200-20210801_17174590.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Palace, Rosyth. Nikon FM, 28mm f/1.4 AiS&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Something more urban in flavour demands not only monochrome but also the character of a grainy film stock like this. I don&#39;t think it handles wide dynamic range the way I had hoped, however. Shooting into the light is probably not the best idea:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Ilford-Delta-3200-20210801_17251720.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Harbour Bell, St.Monans. Nikon FM, 28mm f/1.4 AiS&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Delta 3200 can perform well with good light, and yield decent contrasty images if you meter and expose correctly. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;kodak-portra-160&#34;&gt;Kodak Portra 160&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Kodak-Portra-160-20210808_18071280-2.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Queensferry Crossing from St. Margaret&#39;s Marsh&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I scanned most of these at 3200 or 4800 dpi in 48-bit colour with the scanner&#39;s colour handling switch off. The first few frames were taken at the Hermitage, near Dunkeld, during a weekend run up to one of our favourite places in May. We needed reflection time and the COVID restrictions were just so that we could do the right thing as we did The Right Thing for us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Kodak-Portra-160-20210808_18071280.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ossian&#39;s Hall. Nikon FM, 28mm f/1.4 AiS&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Dunkeld weekend was not in the brightest of sunshine and that tends to wash out the colours in Portra, I think. This is a dark and moody kind of place when it&#39;s overcast, so the image above does portray that. No marks for composition -- there&#39;s a better portrait version but that favours the bridge over the hall and I wanted to show that in this post.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Kodak-Portra-160-20210808_18071280-1.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Queensferry Crossing from St. Margaret&#39;s Marsh&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There was better light when we walked on the Forth Shore at St. Margaret&#39;s Marsh, between the bridges and the dockyard. Some while later, we were at Loch Lubnaig where the colours of the greenery dominate the images taken with this film.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Kodak-Portra-160-20210808_18365655.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m not such a fan of 160 in anything other than really good daylight. Composition plays a part, too, and these images aren&#39;t my best: the last few frames of the roll were taken at Burntisland.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Kodak-Portra-160-20210808_18565359.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--15 May Strathyre and LubnaigFM 8 ff Portra27 June Fife beachFM still Portra 160 ff28ff--&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2021/2021-07-30-five-films/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2022 16:01:08 -0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_created.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2021/2021-07-30-five-films/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2021/2021-07-30-five-films/</guid> </item> <item> <title>RPS Distinction</title> <category>Fuji X</category> <category>RPS</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;rps-distinction&#34;&gt;RPS Distinction&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/47090179834_cb210348da_b.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03 Julian Alps, one of the images in my LRPS Panel.&lt;/strong&gt; Fuji X-T2 16mm ISO 200 f/11&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Royal Photographic Society has recommended a panel of my photographs for the distinction of Licentiate (LRPS). This, some 8 months after my wife and I first submitted, with one of us being awarded LRPS immediately. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-lrps-panel&#34;&gt;The LRPS Panel&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had to make changes to one of my images (09 Fenchurch Street) to remove distracting lines that were at first taken to be a printing error. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;panel-layout&#34;&gt;Panel Layout&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes called the eleventh image, the layout of the panel of photographs is an important aspect for the assessors. There has to be a pleasing aesthetic to the arrangement and balance of the images when displayed as a complete body. I spent far too long worrying about details of aspect ratio and colour balance across the panel, I think. The advisory day was useful to get a sense of what the assessors like. These are things like the two faces looking inwards, similar colours at each end of a row, those kinds of spectrumy details that provide satisfaction for a critical viewer, and they are, critical.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;next-steps&#34;&gt;Next steps&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am pleased to have finally achieved this distinction which I take to be an acknowledgement that I am learning something about photography. I&#39;d like to continue my artistic journey by developing my knowledge and skills of the photographic process. I have continued this through making the improvements required to the panel first submitted, and by exploring composition using medium format film, for example.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;RPS Logo&#34; src=&#34;/img/RPS_LRPS_RGB.PNG&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-02-06-lrps/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 20:28:15 -0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_created.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-02-06-lrps/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-02-06-lrps/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Self Isoletting with Kodak T-Max 400</title> <category>Agfa Isolette</category> <category>Kodak T-Max</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;self-isoletting-with-kodak-t-max-400&#34;&gt;Self Isoletting with Kodak T-Max 400&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;A beach walk for exercise, officer, with an old Agfa.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/2020-04-17-Kodak-TMY-9.jpg&#34; /&gt;Frame 8 &lt;strong&gt;Inside the Monk&#39;s cave&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the first roll of my own film I have put through this little Agfa Isolette (see what I did there?). My wife and I went out during the so-called lockdown for some messages and a little exercise, having heard on the news that it&#39;s OK to get in your car and take a short drive to somewhere local if it helps you remain socially distanced enough to fight the spread of COVID-19. We decided that a walk on a beach would be safer and more responsible than a walk in the local park.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;stupid-is-as-stupid-does&#34;&gt;Stupid is as stupid does&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m still not quite myself following a recent loss, but I make no excuses for myself: the first four exposures on this film in the camera were all carefully exposed without remembering to advance the film. I re-took the building (Charles Hill Battery) on frame 2 using the same settings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/2020-04-17-Kodak-TMY-2.jpg&#34; /&gt;Frame 2 &lt;strong&gt;Building&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I double-exposed again on frame 4, re-taking the shots in 5 and 6. Apparently, photography is good for mindfulness. One of the scans, of the Monk&#39;s Cave, where monks used to wait for the boat to take them to Inchcolm Island out in the Forth, I processed using the Nik Collection Silver Efex Pro 2 application to bring out the detail in the sky and foreground. I quite like it:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/2020-04-17-Kodak-TMY-6.jpg&#34; /&gt;Frame 6. &lt;strong&gt;The Monk&#39;s cave&lt;/strong&gt;, post processed in Silver Efex (Nik Collection)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;processing&#34;&gt;Processing&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I like this film, known as TMY, because it&#39;s reliably good and very tolerant of my handling. This roll I processed myself, using 50:1 Rodinal R09 for 18 minutes and Kodak Fixer/Hardener. I had the devil of a job getting the film on the Paterson Reel and got quite grumpy at myself. The development went OK once I&#39;d sorted out my fingers and thumbs. I scanned a selection of the frames on my Epson using their dreadful Silverfast 8 software and noticed that pretty much every one had a band across the top, presumably from a light leak in the camera somewhere. You can see it in the building image above, and faintly in the tree image:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/2020-04-17-Kodak-TMY-12.jpg&#34; /&gt;Frame 12. &lt;strong&gt;Dead tree&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I really don&#39;t think I am going to worry about it - this camera cost me less than twenty quid including postage so a professional CLA&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; is not economically viable. Quite probably the light seals along the bottom of the camera are just needing replaced, a job I might do in a future lock-down.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The scanned tiff files were converted in Capture One, with a bit of contrast adjustment and cropping in the header image.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary-of-the-results&#34;&gt;Summary of the results&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I notice that I didn&#39;t deviate from 1/200s shutter speed with this roll. It was quite bright and so perhaps 400 ISO wasn&#39;t right for the conditions, given that this camera&#39;s shutter doesn&#39;t go any faster than that. Even inside the Monk&#39;s cave (above), I was exposing for the surfaces lit directly from the outside.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/2020-04-17-Kodak-TMY-5.jpg&#34; /&gt;Frame 5, &lt;strong&gt;Inchcolm Island&lt;/strong&gt;, cropped&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;All images on this page taken with an Agfa Isolette I fitted with the Agfa Agnar 1:4.5/85 lens. The film used was Kodak TMY, or T-Max 400 Black &amp;amp; White film, rated at EI 400. Cost £6.40 per roll from Analog Wonderland. Exposed on 4th April 2020, processed at home in Rodinal R09 one shot, works out at something like 75p per shot.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;exposure-settings&#34;&gt;Exposure settings&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;Frame&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Image&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Aperture&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Shutter&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;1.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Golf course &amp;amp; beach&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;f/16&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/200s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;1.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Terminal&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/200s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;1.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Boat&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/200s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;1.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Building&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/200s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;2.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Building&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/200s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;3.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Boat&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/200s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;4.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Inchcolm Island&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;f/32&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/200s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;4.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Monk&#39;s cave&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;f/32&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/200s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;5.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Inchcolm Island&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;f/32&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/200s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;6.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The Monk&#39;s cave&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;f/32&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/200s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;7.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Monk&#39;s cave&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/200s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;8.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Inside the Monk&#39;s cave&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;f/8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/200s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;9.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Monk&#39;s cave window&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;f/8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/200s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;10.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Inchcolm Island&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;f/16&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/200s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;11.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Beach&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;f/16&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/200s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;12.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Dead tree&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;f/11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/200s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Clean, lubricate and adjust.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 1 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-04-04-self-isoletting-with-Kodak-T-Max-400/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 20:28:15 -0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_created.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-04-04-self-isoletting-with-Kodak-T-Max-400/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-04-04-self-isoletting-with-Kodak-T-Max-400/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Stories and images</title> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;stories-and-images&#34;&gt;Stories and images&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/IMG_9378.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Achnahaird beach&lt;/strong&gt;, sketch &lt;em&gt;en plein air&lt;/em&gt;, Mont Blanc fountain pen&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Storytelling is one of man&#39;s oldest cultural habits, and the evidence we have for this is in the images our ancestors left behind. From the earliest cave paintings to the &lt;em&gt;insta&lt;/em&gt; trophy, we record from imagination and experience the world around us. Photography is the ubiquitous manifestation of this in much of the contemporary world we inhabit, so much so that the art of capturing images might seem trivial. In these pages are some of my own images, with perhaps some thoughts or stories to go with them using my powerful ally, words. Here I have the advantage over the cave painter: I can express or explain context to help the observer make sense of the image on the screen. You are at liberty to make your own mind up, of course, and you should critically engage.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2022 10:01:17 -0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_created.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/</guid> </item> <item> <title>A Summer Hebridean trip</title> <category>Fuji X</category> <category>Ricoh GRIII</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-summer-hebridean-trip&#34;&gt;A Summer Hebridean trip&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9085.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cuillins&lt;/strong&gt;, X-T2, Nikon 85mm&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s been a long time since there has been time for photography: life, COVID, and other everyday challenges have conspired to distract us from our one-time major non-work activity. A trip to the Hebrides for a short summer break demanded at least some effort, so I took my &lt;a href=&#34;/_cameras/fuji-x-t2.md&#34;&gt;Fuji X-T2&lt;/a&gt; and three lenses; the &lt;a href=&#34;/_cameras/ricoh-gr-iii.md&#34;&gt;Ricoh GR-III&lt;/a&gt;; and one concession to analogue photography, the &lt;a href=&#34;/_cameras/afga-isolette.md&#34;&gt;Agfa Isolette&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;skye&#34;&gt;Skye&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We drove cross-country from the Forth to Skye Bridges, taking our time to shop a little at the House of Bruar (one &lt;em&gt;has to&lt;/em&gt;, surely) and dally at Sligachan bridge, an old favourite of ours with a newish statue to the mountaineers Prof. Norman Collie and John Mackenzie.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9090.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Statue of Collie and Mackenzie&lt;/strong&gt; at Glen Sligachan. X-T2 with a Nikon 85mm f/1.4 lens.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The 50-year-old Nikon lens holds up nicely on the Fuji. Wide-open at f/1.4 I find it very hard to get the focus exact -- the depth of field is very narrow -- but it is still a very nice lens for softening the background. It performs better on the Nikon it was designed for, being quite dark on the Fuji compared to the Fuji XF 90mm f/2.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9086.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glen Sligachan&lt;/strong&gt;, X-T2, Nikon 85mm f/1.4 lens at about f/4.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The header image of Collie and Mackenzie&#39;s Cuillins was also taken with the same camera and lens and shows off, in my view, the distinct colour profile of the Nikon glass. Make your own mind up whether you prefer the filmic shades of the Nikon over the technically superior and brilliant Fuji lenses.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/R0001279.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The iconic Portree harbour houses&lt;/strong&gt;, Ricoh GR III at f/11, cropped.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overnighting at a Hostel in Portree, we took the early ferry from Uig to Loch Maddy. I am always impressed with CalMac&#39;s well-oiled operation, especially compared to the sometimes stressful experience of air travel. The 90 minute crossing was smooth and only slightly disappointing for not spotting seals at Vaternish Point. We consoled ourselves with a bacon and egg banjo in the &#34;Mariners&#34; café.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;five-islands&#34;&gt;Five Islands&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9112.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first couple of days in our remote &#34;pod&#34; were quite overcast with an ever-present wind between 20 and 40 mph, as the rest of the UK was baking in a record-breaking heat wave. It was nice, actually, and gave us a chance to explore comfortably and get a feel for the local group of islands. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9100.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;East Beach, Berneray&lt;/strong&gt; Fuji X-T2, XF16mm f/1.4 lens at f/11, 1/250s, ISO 200.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The colours of the water and the machair were striking, different at every location and under the changing light. The sands are also rich with pattern and shade (below). The header image on this page was taken at Traigh Lar on North Uist which became one of our favourite places on our short trip. It was captured with the Fuji X-T2 and the XF16mm f/1.4 lens at f/16 to get the depth of field required to keep the grass in focus as well as the horizon. 1/1000s to freeze the waves, ISO 1000. There was a steep drop of about 20 m to the beach from this point.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9095.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;East Beach sands, Berneray&lt;/strong&gt; Fuji X-T2, XF16mm f/1.4 lens at f/8, 1/1250, ISO 200.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Back on East Beach, the sands are also rich with pattern and texture. The countryside is rich with signs that it is expensive to dispose of old machinery and vehicles. Some effort seems to be made to at least gather the wreckage together. At Baleshare, a small collection of refrigerated trailers was forming. This one has signs of another era, like you see when shops change hands and ancient signwriting appears for a while.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/R0001290.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dead trailer&lt;/strong&gt; Ricoh GR III, processed in Capture One.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These two at least look like they&#39;re trying to keep out of sight. The wheels stick out like shoes from under a curtain.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/R0001293.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hidden trailers&lt;/strong&gt; Ricoh GR III, a similar process in Capture One.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;to-eriskay-and-back&#34;&gt;To Eriskay and back&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We drove the length of the Outer Hebrides, at least without leaving the land. There are many causeways now connecting the various island communities and making commerce and life in general much easier for the people who live and work here. We visited five islands: North and South Uist, Berneray, Benbecula and Eriskay. We&#39;re not counting Baleshare, although it connects to North Uist by another causeway. Most of the time one side of the causeway is all sand, and when it&#39;s not, you could probably still wade across. We didn&#39;t test that theory.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9117.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Howmore Bothy&lt;/strong&gt; (Fuji, Nikon 85mm lens)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Everywhere there are what seems like abandoned or derelict buildings. This example I photographed with both the Fuji (above) and the Ricoh (below) to create a different mood. I&#39;m not sure how successful it is: the wider angle of the Ricoh allows more context to create a story with.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/R0001294.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Howmore Bothy&lt;/strong&gt; (Ricoh, 18mm lens)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What really captured my heart during our leisurely and unstructured schlep around these islands was the sheer loveliness of the flowers that are just everywhere, clearly loved and protected by the local people. The wildflower meadowland that edges the beaches and reaches inland is diverse and colourful. I took far too many photographs of these flowers but will not tire of them as they adorn my desktop and walls in the coming months. Here, from the beach at Eriskay, right by the Barra Ferry terminal, is Sea Rocket:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9127.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fuday Island from Prince Charles&#39; Beach, Eriskay&lt;/strong&gt; Sea Rocket, Fuji X-T2, Nikon 85mm lens.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Back &#34;home&#34; to the bothy and a walk after dinner on our own beach on the doorstep, entertained on the way by rabbits and various birds playing and raising families in the meadowland.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9140.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The beach at Baleshare&lt;/strong&gt;, Fuji X-T2, Nikon 85mm lens.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Along the way, we met many of the residents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;residents&#34;&gt;Residents&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9159.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Locals&lt;/strong&gt; Fuji X-T2, Nikon 85mm&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The islands have a thriving farming sector and there are sheep on every single-track road personally introducing themselves to foreign visitors. Birds are many and diverse: it is easy to see a host of sea birds in and around the machar and on the hillsides are Golden Eagles, Hen Harriers and short-eared owls hunting in the daytime.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!-- Local drivers are used to them and know how much care is required: visitors must err on the side of caution or display the appropriate yellow sticker in the back window to warn other road users. --&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9157.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Locals&lt;/strong&gt; Fuji X-T2, Nikon 85mm&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The diversity of the wildlife is noticeable for visitors like us from the central belt of Scotland. We seem to have a disproportionate seagull population and we can probably do with less of the fat pigeons and magpies, frankly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9149.jpg&#34; /&gt;Where once working families lived, now stand more mechanised, efficient farming practices that make use of the land by fewer humans. A still nascent tourism industry is booked to capacity and locals still wave as visitors yield the right of way in the passing places. There is potential for development of abandoned plots and buildings across the islands. I hope that never comes to spoil the place.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/R0001301.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The roadside food wagon&lt;/strong&gt; is no innovation nor is it a quaint enterprise: the food is home-made, delicious and locally sourced. You have to try the scallops and black pudding roll. Radio buzzers notify in your car when your lunch is ready and yes, they take contactless American Express. Check out the recycling bins. Even the coffee-cup lids are made of paper pulp. The Outer Hebrideans are right on trend when it comes to sustainable service.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9180.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sea birds&lt;/strong&gt; abound along the shorelines and there are &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Sites_of_Special_Scientific_Interest_in_Western_Isles_South&#34;&gt;sites of special scientific interest&lt;/a&gt; intended to protect the diverse species, not least those that depend on the environment to breed and thrive. There are as many halfwits who will open gates to drive their SUVs across these spaces to access their picnics, of course but we think we saw at least one person openly challenge such behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9166.jpg&#34; /&gt;Most precious and beautiful of the environmental backdrop here is the machair. It is looked after and protected, as far as one can protect from human activity. Here may be common buttercups and clover but if you look, you can see many kinds of orchid.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;au-revoir&#34;&gt;Au Revoir&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9206_Panorama.jpg&#34; /&gt;This image will give you a sense of what we had hoped for when we headed North on our holiday. That image is actually a stitch of 8 images taken with the X-T2 and 35mm f/2 lens. Each image was exposed at f/8, 1/125s at ISO 200 and assembled into a panorama in Capture One. It should make a nice print about 50 inches x 20 inches if I ever get around to that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our sixth island of the trip was Skye, of course, our gateway to the Outer Hebrides. The hills and skies of Skye are something to behold: a mere photograph, least of all a digital image on a computer screen, can&#39;t give you anything like the sense of &lt;em&gt;being there&lt;/em&gt;. I tried with images like this pano, taken from the side of the road on the way from Carbost, not far from Sligachan where this series of posts began.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9283_Panorama.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Broadford Co-Op was full of surprises. The cheapest diesel I&#39;ve bought for weeks, and the right range of snacks for the rest of the journey home. Oh, and this view from the car park:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9289_Panorama.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What we got from our trip was much better than we had hoped for, of course. We had the chance to explore and learn, visit and revisit under changing skies and light. We left with just the tip of a toe dipped in Hebridean life. In the end, I only took one photo with the Agfa. I forget what it was but no doubt it will pop out in a few months.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-07-12-hebridean-trip/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 23:00:00 -0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_created.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-07-12-hebridean-trip/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-07-12-hebridean-trip/</guid> <enclosure url="https://niximagery.com//img/DSF9206_Panorama.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="None" /> </item> <item> <title>E100 in an Isolette</title> <category>Agfa Isolette</category> <category>Kodak E100</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;e100-in-an-isolette&#34;&gt;E100 in an Isolette&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sunday 4th October, 2020. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Kodak-Ektachrome-100-120-20201004_06-sm.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I took my little Agfa Isolette, loaded with Kodak Ektachrome E100 to nearby Kinghorn beach, a place my wife and I often go to for a bit of headspace and diversion from the rest of the world. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;sunny-16-will-do&#34;&gt;Sunny 16 will do&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite the habits of the digital age, for this roll, I didn&#39;t record all the exposure details, going broadly with &#34;sunny 16&#34;, occasionally referring to an app on my iPhone for aperture and shutter speed combinations that might be reasonable. It was a bright, partly sunny day, and I took some of the shots at 1/50 s hand-held, although some were at 1/200 s or between these two. Apertures were between f/8 and f/16, mostly. I finished the film and sent it to AG for developing with another E100 I had recently finished in my &lt;a href=&#34;/Stories/2020/2020-10-04-E100-gw690/&#34;&gt;Fuji GW690ii&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;scanning-and-pixel-peeping&#34;&gt;Scanning and pixel peeping&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The transparencies were scanned in an Epson V600. At 6400 dpi, this yields a file around 750 MB in size, and an image approaching 250 megapixels, but this is not anything like equivalent to &#34;better than a Fuji GFX&#34; unless the camera and photographer have combined to capture the absolute highest quality image possible. I certainly am not consistently getting that kind of precision, even if the camera can, but it won&#39;t stop me trying. I scanned these at 3200 dpi for an image nearer 50 Megapixels in a file under 200MB after cropping.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Kodak-Ektachrome-100-120-20201004_05-sm.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Near Kinghorn beach.&lt;/strong&gt; Adjusted for crop and wonky horizons in Iridient Developer. Size reduction for the web was in Apple&#39;s Preview.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Kodak-Ektachrome-100-120-20201004_08-sm.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inchkeith Island.&lt;/strong&gt; Cropped and adjusted in Iridient Developer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s not lost on me that a roll of this film, with processing, costs more than the camera did. I&#39;m sure that&#39;s not a unique situation but given that the Agfa Isolette is a medium format camera, and the quality of the capture and rendering are, in my view, pretty good, then I am left wondering why I am also happy, from time to time, to launch a grand or more on a digital camera. Maybe those days are over.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The variation in exposures in this roll are certainly operator error. I do a lot of calculating while I shoot, having never developed any real &#34;intuitive feel&#34; for exposure over the years. There&#39;s time yet -- as Henri Cartier-Bresson says, &#34;your first 10,000 photographs are your worst&#34;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes-on-exposures&#34;&gt;Notes on exposures&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Colour positive (slide) film, cost £12.40 per roll from Analog Wonderland. To AG photographic for E-6 developing 20th September 2020 £14.49 for 2 rolls.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Brand&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Type&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;ISO&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Format&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Exposures&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Camera&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Lens&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Kodak&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Ektachrome E100&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;100&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;120&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;12&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Agfa Isolette I&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Agfa Agnar 1:4.5/85&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;Frame&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Image&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Aperture&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Shutter&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Comment&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;1. and 2.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Heather&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;f/8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/50 s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Dunkeld drive, 4th September 20&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;3.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Kinghorn beach&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;f/11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/50 s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Sat 19 Sep&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;I didn&#39;t record the rest of the exposure details, but went broadly with &#34;sunny 16&#34;, occasionally referring to an app on my iPhone. It was a bright, partly sunny day, and I took some of the shots at 1/50 s hand-held, although some were at 1/200 s or between these two. Apertures were between f/8 and f/16, mostly. I finished the film and sent it to AG for developing with another E100 I had finished in the Fuji GW690ii.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-10-04-E100-isolette/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 23:00:00 -0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_created.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-10-04-E100-isolette/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-10-04-E100-isolette/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Faroes Trip February 2020</title> <category>Apple iPhone</category> <category>Fuji GW690ii</category> <category>Fujifilm Acros II</category> <category>Fujifilm Pro</category> <category>Ilford Ortho</category> <category>Kodak Portra</category> <category>Kodak T-Max</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;faroes-trip-february-2020&#34;&gt;Faroes Trip February 2020&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I exposed several rolls of 120 film in my Fuji GW690 &#34;Texas Leica&#34; during a trip to the Faroe Islands in February 2020. The camera has a fixed 90mm f/3.5 lens and takes 6 cm x 9 cm frames, or 8 per roll of 120. I sent them all to be processed by AG Labs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-1&#34;&gt;Day 1&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;!-- Thursday, 6th February --&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;lrps&#34;&gt;LRPS&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Well, the good news came by email around 12:40 from Simon Vercoe, the LRPS admin assistant at the Royal Photographic Society, that I am finally to be awarded the distinction of &#34;Licentiate&#34; of the RPS. I&#39;m delighted about that, of course. More on that story &lt;a href=&#34;/Stories/2020-02-06-lrps&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;travelling-by-plane-with-film&#34;&gt;Travelling by plane with film&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are on board a flight from Edinburgh to Vágar, the capital of the Faroe Islands. I have my Fuji GW690ii medium format camera with me and a stock of 9 film rolls that hopefully haven&#39;t been ruined by the airport security scan at Edinburgh. Despite my protests, the security people scanned all of the unexposed film. We&#39;ll see if there is any effect on the stock&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:1&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. I think the greatest danger to the film still lies in my photographic skills. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/IMG_1043.JPG&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Airbus&lt;/strong&gt;, iPhone 11 4.25mm lens at ISO 125. f/1.8 1/84s. Cropped, colour shifted warmer in Preview&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/IMG_5763.JPG&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Films&lt;/strong&gt; iPhone 11 at ISO 100. f/1.8 1/100s, cropped&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;sandavagur&#34;&gt;Sandavágur&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/29-2-20-Kodak-400TMY.3.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sandavágur&lt;/strong&gt; Kodak TMY, frame 3&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not Scotland, not Thailand, but with some characteristics of both. The first film I loaded into the camera was one of the rolls of Kodak TMY, aka T-Max 400 and fitted a deep yellow Tiffen filter. Why that one? It&#39;s the one I have. Why a filter? We&#39;re going to be focusing on landscapes and I want to try not to wreck the skies: the yellow will darken the bluer highlights in the sky and reveal the cloud texture. You can see how this turned out in the above image which was taken later that morning. As it turned out, this was the only roll of this film stock that saw the light of day on this trip&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:fw&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:fw&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;kodak-t-max-400-exposures&#34;&gt;Kodak T-Max 400 exposures&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;Frame&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Image&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Aperture&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Shutter&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Comment&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;1.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Morning, East over the village&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/4s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Yellow filter&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;2.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;River&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/32&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/2s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Portrait&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;3.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Sandavágur&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/32&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/60s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;4.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Sea stacks&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/30s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;From Bøur&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;5. &amp;amp; 6.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Sea stacks&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/45s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;7.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Beach&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/32&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/60s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;8.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Beach&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/32&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/30s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-2&#34;&gt;Day 2&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;!-- Friday 7th February, 2020. --&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;mivagur&#34;&gt;Miðvágur&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A good sleep. waking early to a still, deep darkness. Aurora Watch says we ought to be able to see some action but the 8 okta cloud cover says otherwise. Coffee, fruit and biscuits to wake us up instead. Once the daylight appeared we got to see and appreciate the view from the house.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/R0000443.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Miðvágur&lt;/strong&gt; Ricoh GRIII 18.3mm ISO 1250 f/16 1/30s&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;bur&#34;&gt;Bøur&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/29-2-20-Kodak-400TMY.4.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sea stacks&lt;/strong&gt; Kodak TMY, frame 4&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The delightful little village at Bøur has some great views, including the Draganir Sea Stacks, an iconic feature of the Faroes. All around the islands and in these communities are signs reminding visitors of the importance of respect for the environment, the creatures that live here and the people. One of the striking features of this place is the black sand beach.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/29-2-20-Kodak-Portra.2.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The black sands at Bøur beach&lt;/strong&gt; Portra&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My first efforts with Portra. I think we might have been too far North for this film, which seems to be more at home nearer the Equator. I exposed this film during the rest of day 2 and the following morning. If you think I didn&#39;t take many photos, remember I was also carrying a couple of digital cameras, something I don&#39;t do as much now.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;portra-160-exposures&#34;&gt;Portra 160 exposures&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;Frame&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Image&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Aperture&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Shutter&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Comment&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;1.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Boat House&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/6s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;at Bøur&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;2.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The black sands at Bøur beach&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/30s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;3.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Above Bøur&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/250s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Hand held&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;4.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Waterfall&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/60s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Hand held&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;5.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Waterfall island&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/60s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Hand held&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;6.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Waterfall island&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/60s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Hand held, portrait&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;7.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Beach church&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/8s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Next day&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;8.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Giljavegur&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/16&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/60s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Sandavágur, hand held&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;digital-backup&#34;&gt;Digital backup&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I finished that roll of TMY at Bøur on the beach, and backed up the captures using the Ricoh GRIII I carry everywhere, and my Fuji X-T2 fitted with the brilliant Fuji 16mm f/1.4 prime lens. I wondered whether the sun was too low in the sky for the Portra film (Miami, this ain&#39;t) but the film worked out really nicely, in my view. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Gasadalur.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gasadalur&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The best image of the day has been a 3-photo stitch of the village Gasadalur from the bench at a hairpin bend in the road looking west towards the helipad that was the only outside communication link for the community before the road was built. This is a 3-image stitch panorama taken with a Fuji X-T2, using the XF16mm F1.4 R WR lens. ISO 400, f/11, 1/60s.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;later-re-scanning&#34;&gt;Later - re-scanning&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I re-scanned a couple of these images to see if the output quality was any better. It is, depending on how you measure it. This is a (reduced version of the scanner output) 350 Mega-pixel file, scanned from 6x9cm negative at 6400 dpi:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/img20200719_09.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Island&lt;/strong&gt; (Re-scan of frame 5, Portra)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you compare the quality of image I got with the Fuji X-T2 (Gasadalur, above), there really is no argument for film photography, based upon these results. Now, I know that medium format cameras capture a lot of information, but that depends on a lot of things being exactly right. Get more than a couple of parameters sub-optimal and you&#39;re wasting your time striving for that Nirvana of image-making. To me, the important difference is how it feels.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-3&#34;&gt;Day 3&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;!-- Saturday 8th February, 2020. --&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Seal.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seal at Sandavágur&lt;/strong&gt; (cropped) Fuji X-T2, XF90mm F2 R LM WR, ISO 800, f/2 1/500s&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;reflections&#34;&gt;Reflections&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Studying the local guide map over coffee and a biscuit, I realise how ignorant I feel about the place and culture I am in. This, as a consequence of the pace of life I am leading, ironically to pay for the privilege of travel. I will no doubt go home full of resolutions to do something about this, which will be dragged into the quicksand of daily hustle and bustle, leaving only the guilt as trace that I ever made them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;sandavagur_1&#34;&gt;Sandavágur&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We drove down to Sandavágur for the sunrise, which was wintery. Kara played with waves and the seals and I took a photo of the floodlit church which didn&#39;t turn out the way I hoped. This is the church, taken the next day with Fuji Pro 400H.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Fuji-Pro-400H-2.2.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sandavágur Church&lt;/strong&gt; Fuji Pro 400H, second roll, frame 2&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;trllkonufingur&#34;&gt;Trøllkonufingur&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We drove to the Witch&#39;s Finger (Trøllkonufingur) and walked along far enough to see the stack and promised to return to catch the sun rising here tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Fuji-Pro-400H-1.8.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trøllkonufingur&lt;/strong&gt; Fuji Pro 400H, post processed in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.iridientdigital.com/&#34;&gt;Iridient&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;torshavn&#34;&gt;Tórshavn&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;After a good breakfast we headed for the Streymoy tunnel and Tórshavn, where we ate extremely expensive sushi. One of the delights of the Faroes is that they have not learned how to do tourism yet, with its expected levels of service. Certainly our waitress hadn&#39;t done the course. I&#39;m not complaining - it&#39;s nice to have the feeling that you&#39;re not just following in the footsteps of 80 million people before you, taking the same photos. I didn&#39;t take many photos in the town: it&#39;s nice, and there is a harbour and some old buildings but it was raining and I was happy just experiencing the place.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;fuji-pro-400h-exposures&#34;&gt;Fuji Pro 400H exposures&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I used 2 rolls of Fuji Pro 400H in different contexts: starting with the Trøllkonufingur, the town of Tórshavn, and at Gasadalur, the iconic lake over the sea.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;Frame&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Image&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Aperture&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Shutter&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Comment&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;1.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Trøllkonufingur&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The &#34;witchs fingers&#34;. Hand held.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;2.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Waterfall&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;3. &amp;amp; 4.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Tórshavn alley&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/60s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;5. &amp;amp; 6.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;No record&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Next day (9th)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;7.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Trøllkonufingur&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/32&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/4s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Portrait&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;8.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Trøllkonufingur&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/32&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/4s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Landscape&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;Frame&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Image&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Aperture&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Shutter&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Comment&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;1.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Day 4, Yellow cottage near Miðvágur&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/60s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Hand held.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;2.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Sandavágur Church&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/16&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;3.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Sandavágur Church&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/16&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/250s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Portait&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;4.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Over village&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/16&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;5.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Gasadalur&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;6.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Gasadalur&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/32&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/30s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;7.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Slave cliff&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/32&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/30s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;8.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Slave cliff&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/32&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/30s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Portrait&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-4&#34;&gt;Day 4&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;!-- Sunday morning, the 9th February. --&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Fuji-Acros-II-2.2-sm.jpg&#34; /&gt;My wife, photographer &lt;a href=&#34;https://wildaye.co.uk/&#34;&gt;Kara Mudie&lt;/a&gt;, at work at the Bøsdalafossur falls. Acros&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;bsdalafossur&#34;&gt;Bøsdalafossur&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We went out for sunrise at the Witch&#39;s Finger (Trøllkonufingur) which was unspectacular due to clouds obstructing the sun but still fun. After breakfast, we headed out to find the lake above the sea. We did, but not before shelling out 200 Króna each for the privilege of access to the footways. A nicely spoken local girl was manning the barricade and promising tea and coffee when we returned from our hike. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF7255.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bøsdalafossur&lt;/strong&gt; Fuji X-T2 XF16mm ISO 200 f/16 1/50s, some post processing in Capture One Pro 20&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of course, she wasn&#39;t there when we returned after sunset. We didn&#39;t care much, having had around 10km and 120m of elevation to stretch our muscles on. Leitisvatn / Sørvágsvatn lake (&#34;the lake above the sea&#34;) pours over the Bøsdalafossur waterfall 30 metres into the sea below, which crashes dramatically against the cliff edges as if it were trying to get back up into the peaceful waters of the lake, where people were kayaking when we were there.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;trlanipan-slave-cliff&#34;&gt;Trælanípan (Slave Cliff)&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/R0000482.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trælanípan&lt;/strong&gt; Ricoh GRIII ISO 200 f/5 1/400s, some post processing in Capture One Pro 20&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The cliffs on the walk to the lake are several hundred metres above the sea and even on a fairly calm day, as today was, the thought of a sudden gust or a seagull with a sense of humour kept us focused and not too close to the edge. We met a local near the top of the walk who chatted in good English about the Scottish fishermen who threw chocolate to the local kids, who in turn sold lighters to the fishermen. My wife&#39;s grandfather was one of those fishermen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;yellow-cottage-near-mivagur&#34;&gt;Yellow cottage near Miðvágur&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/yellow-cottage.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yellow cottage near Miðvágur&lt;/strong&gt; Fuji Pro 400H&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We passed this little shed-cum-cottage several times as we explored the area around Miðvágur. I had to stop to capture this scene with the Fuji Pro film I was carrying. I love the colours and would love to come back to see it again in the summer light.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;nix-the-faroese-kelpie&#34;&gt;Nix: the Faroese Kelpie&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF7204.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nix&lt;/strong&gt; X-T2 XF16mm ISO 400 f/2.8 1/500s pp and cropped in Capture One Pro 20&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We found this artsy sculpture near the roadside that runs by Lake Sørvágsvatn. It represents a Nykur, a mythical Scandinavian creature that drags children down to the bottom of the icy waters. Saying the name of the creature makes it lose all of its powers. I wonder if someone said the name of the sculptor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;fuji-acros-100-ii&#34;&gt;Fuji Acros 100 II&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;First time out with Acros was in the early morning as the sun came up over the Trøllkonufingur. In retrospect, this is probably not the best situation to use this legendary contrasty film. The results were not stunning, in my view, and certainly not as good as I expected, but that&#39;s operator error and not a problem with the film stock. Notice the first few exposures are all long, but get less long as the Northern winter light improved.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;Frame&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Image&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Aperture&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Shutter&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Comment&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;1.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Trøllkonufingur&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/32&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Portrait&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;2.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Trøllkonufingur&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/32&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Portrait, yellow filter&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;3.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Trøllkonufingur&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/32&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Landscape&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;4.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Trøllkonufingur&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/32&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/2s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Landscape&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;5.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Fence&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/32&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/4s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Landscape&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;6.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Shed, river&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/4s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;7.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Trøllkonufingur&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/32&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/8s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;8.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Trøllkonufingur and fence&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/32&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/8s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;Frame&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Image&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Aperture&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Shutter&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Comment&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;1.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Sea stacks&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/32&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/4s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Portrait&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;2.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Sea stacks&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/32&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/4s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Landscape&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;3.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Bøsdalafossur falls&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/32&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/4s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;4-8.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Bøsdalafossur falls&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/32&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/2s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;ilford-ortho-plus-80&#34;&gt;Ilford Ortho Plus 80&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Same applies to this film as the Acros. I&#39;m not giving up on it, because I&#39;ve seen good results elsewhere but I&#39;m not sufficiently expert to get the most out of orthographic film yet. This point is emphasised by the fact that I left the lens cap on for frames 2 and 3. My notes suggest I had an ND filter on for these pictures. That possibly didn&#39;t help much either.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;Frame&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Image&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Aperture&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Shutter&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Comment&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;1.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Bøsdalafossur&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/32&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/8s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Cliffs&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;4., 5.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Diptych of cliffs&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/32&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/4s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;6.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Sea stacks&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/32&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/2s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;7., 8.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Sea stacks&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/32&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/4s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-5&#34;&gt;Day 5&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;!-- Monday 10th February, 2020. --&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Portra-160-2.4-Feb-13-2020-1-sm.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Huts near Vágar Airport&lt;/strong&gt; Portra, second roll, frame 4&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;coming-home&#34;&gt;Coming home&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;No early adventures for us today but we didn&#39;t have to leave the house to see a range of weather, including a gorgeous sunrise and snow from the lounge window. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/R0000500.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sunrise&lt;/strong&gt; Ricoh GRIII ISO 800 f/16 1/30s, pp in Capture One Pro 20&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We packed and I loaded my last roll of film, a Kodak Portra 160. Replenishing the hire car&#39;s tank with about 20 litres of petrol cost about 200 Króna, the same as a single adult ticket to walk on the land nearby. We stopped at the huts in the place Kara had seen from that walk yesterday, and I ran off the final frames before packing the exposed rolls into a poly bag for easy security inspection at the airport.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Check in made us feel like children again as a nice lady talked us through getting a luggage tag printed at the self-service machines, and loading our bags onto the automatic conveyor. Duty-free was actually cheap and I couldn&#39;t resist buying a pack of &lt;em&gt;Kvikk Lunsj&lt;/em&gt;. Interestingly, security did a visual check of the bag of film stock at my request (once the supervisor had OK&#39;d it), so the only scan my rolls have had was at the grumpy airport at Edinburgh. I think I&#39;m going to have to try to find out what the rules are on this - were the Faroese just being nice, reasonable people, or were the Scots just being bastards? I&#39;d like to know but from a Kodak article I read yesterday the hand luggage scanners at airports are of too low a power to affect film stock significantly, even with multiple scans.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;later&#34;&gt;Later&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;At home, I packed the rolls off to AG Photo in Birmingham using their pre-paid mailer. Grand total of the processing costs from the trip is just under forty quid.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;kodak-portra-160-2&#34;&gt;Kodak Portra 160 2&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The second roll of Portra I used on the last day, as we cleared out of the house and hit the road for the airport. On the way there, we stopped at the roadside to capture the fishing huts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;Frame&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Image&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Aperture&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Shutter&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Comment&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;1., 2.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;View from the house&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/60s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;3.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Huts near Vágar Airport&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/60s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;4.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Huts near Vágar Airport&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/60s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;5-8.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Huts near Vágar Airport&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/32&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/8s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;film-costs&#34;&gt;Film costs&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Total film stock cost £83.00, plus processing costs £38.80 (£3.49 C-41, £3.99 BW, £4.89 pp, AG Photolabs). Total costs £121.80 for 70 frames (2 were spoilt - lens cap on), or about £1.74 per frame on average. Breakdown by film:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;Qty.&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Brand&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Type&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;ISO&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;per roll&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;inc. pp&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;per frame&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Fujifilm Pro 400 H&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Colour&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;400&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;£ 8.30&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;£ 12.33&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;about £1.55&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Kodak Portra&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Colour&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;160&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;£ 8.80&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;£ 12.83&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;about £1.60&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Kodak T-Max&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;BW Pan&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;400&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;£ 6.40&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;£ 10.93&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;about £1.37&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Ilford Ortho Plus&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;BW Ortho&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;80&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;£ 8.00&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;£ 12.53&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;about £1.57&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Fujifilm Neopan Acros II&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;BW Pan&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;100&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;£ 14.00&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;£ 18.53&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;about £2.32&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:fw&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The other one of these was sent unexposed to AG for processing although who knows how I managed that. They processed it, of course, but without telling me. I just got 8 clear frames back.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:fw&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 1 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;There hasn&#39;t been, as far as I can tell. None of the film rolls were over ISO 400, and the airport scanners nowadays seem to be quite low energy, although there is some concern, especially with the increase in the use of CT scanners at airports, mainly in the US. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://petapixel.com/2020/01/27/kodak-warns-users-new-ct-scanners-at-airports-will-ruin-your-film/&#34;&gt;this post from Petapixel&lt;/a&gt;, for example, which reports on advice from Kodak that there is evidence of significant damage to film every time it is scanned. Caveat emptor, and tie up your camel.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 2 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-02-06-faroes-trip/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_created.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-02-06-faroes-trip/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-02-06-faroes-trip/</guid> </item> </channel></rss>