<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"> <channel><title>Niximagery</title><description>Stories and images</description><link>https://niximagery.com/</link><atom:link href="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_created.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><managingEditor>Nick Hood</managingEditor><docs>https://github.com/NixImagery</docs><language>en</language> <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 12:37:13 -0000</pubDate> <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 12:37:13 -0000</lastBuildDate> <ttl>1440</ttl> <generator>MkDocs RSS plugin - v1.5.0</generator> <image> <url>https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/4/43/Feed-icon.svg/128px-Feed-icon.svg.png</url> <title>Niximagery</title><link>https://niximagery.com/</link> </image> <item> <title>School Sketches</title> <category>Sketch</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;school-sketches&#34;&gt;School sketches&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;During late November and early December, my job has required me to make visits to schools. The schedule can be challenging so I always try to arrive around 20 minutes early so as to check any messages, and enter the school with grace and dignity. On this cycle of visits, I thought I&#39;d use the extra time to also practice some sketching.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/sketches/22-11-15-Linlithgow.JPG&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Linlithgow Academy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is a rationale for this habit. Sketching is a deliberate, mindful process, even when done quickly. I helps you see what is there, and the looking doesn&#39;t stop when the sketchbook is closed. At Linlithgow, I found myself studying wall displays, people, the dynamic of school reception spaces, looking at shapes and patterns as much as inscriptions. I even got the chance to assist some not-yet-detective material police officers in their hunt for the reception desk, being able to indicate the huge sign that my fine-tuned sketcher&#39;s observational skills had spotted in the lobby.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;admonition info inline&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/sketches/22-11-08-DeansCHS.JPG&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Deans Community High School&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;We continue to invest in building new schools to replace older, more out of date infrastructure. This is a good thing for many reasons including sending a message to the country that education is important and valuable to us all. Whilst every school is different, design features and material choices appear in as many of the recent builds, perhaps dating them. This is not to say they look the same -- they do, in some respects, but each has its own features according to the perceived needs of the community they serve.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;admonition info inline end&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/sketches/22-11-16-KirkcaldyHS.jpeg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kirkcaldy High School&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I taught Physics and Mathematics at Kirkcaldy High School for a number of years before replacing my own tutor at Moray House. I&#39;m not going to reminisce about this old place but it was nice to go back for a visit and see friends and former colleagues again. I was reminded that cultures are slow to change and that whilst rolling stones may gather no moss, they do gather experience you don&#39;t get standing still.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bunsen burners, magnesium strips and good dialogic pedagogy made my job easy at Preston Lodge today. All the nicer to see more old friends, too. Education is a village, and once you&#39;ve been at it a while, it can feel like going home when you meet again, people who have shared different parts of your journey. Conversations pick up where they left off, friendship hugs shock the pupils, and mutual respect is grown and shared from stories of careers unfolding. I love it when new teachers see that: they are enculturated into their vocation through the modelled behaviours of those that go before them, and shape them. There&#39;s more to this than Vygotksy, or Bruner, or the latest educational fad.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;admonition info inline&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/sketches/22-11-23-PrestonLodge.jpeg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Preston Lodge High School&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;admonition info inline end&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/sketches/22-11-25-PortobelloHS.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Portobello High School&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Preston Lodge and Portobello sketches are not the best likeness to the &lt;em&gt;real thing&lt;/em&gt;, for similar reasons. At Preston Lodge, my view from the car was obscured by a large van and so I had to interpret and sketch what I &lt;em&gt;felt&lt;/em&gt; was there. Isn&#39;t that the point, though? The American photographer David Alan Harvey said, &#34;Don&#39;t shoot what it looks like. Shoot what it feels like.&#34; This is my motivation in photography as much as in sketching, and exploring that idea is the principal reason for me wanting to sketch more often. At Portobello, a different large van also obscured the view, and I don&#39;t have the confidence quite to stand in a car park sketching, in full view of the CCTV. I had a call to go in to school anyway, so I took a quick photo on my phone and sketched it up later in a café over lunch. From this experience, I think I do a better job sketching live, &lt;em&gt;en plein air&lt;/em&gt;, than from a photo. Something seems to be missing in my drawing from a photo, at least where my skills are at present. Perhaps that will change with practice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/sketches/22-11-28-LeithAc.jpeg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;The lorry at Leith, with a fast rat&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Leith Academy has a nice front façade but you can&#39;t see it from where I parked, and the back of the building is ugly, so I sketched the random lorry in the car park instead. I did not find out what the vehicle does, or why it&#39;s there, but it looks arty to me, even if seems past its best service days. Leith has always felt like an arty school: it has interesting shaped science labs which are full of scope and character, even if some of the electrical infrastructure also seems past its best service days. The teachers are anything but, of course, nor the businesslike head teacher who introduced himself as I was preparing to leave for my next appointment. It&#39;s great that there are schools like Leith who put the effort and investment into new teachers, for the wider good of Scottish education. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;admonition info inline&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/sketches/22-11-28-MusselburghGS.jpeg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Musselburgh Grammar School&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is a &lt;em&gt;quid pro quo&lt;/em&gt;, of course, in the benefit that mentors and other colleagues get from watching rookies make naïve mistakes and offering guidance and advice from experience, at the same time tapping in to new ideas and reconnecting to the principles of pedagogy that are fresh in the student teachers&#39; thinking. This was articulated in both schools I visited today by the supporting teachers who played their important part in bringing about fair and just evaluation of how their charges have progressed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;admonition info inline end&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/sketches/22-11-29-QueensferryHS.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Queensferry CHS, in the fog&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;There was a thick fog for my journey across the Forth to Queensferry and I almost bottled doing the sketch because I don&#39;t know how to draw fog. I had a word with myself and thought, &#34;just put the pen marks where it&#39;s dark, and don&#39;t put them where it&#39;s light&#34;. Easier said than, done, I think, so I diverted myself by trying to capture a couple of figures approaching the pool of light from the lamp. I remember a sketcher artist I follow said that figures add interest to a sketch. I think they are right, but I prefer the Leith rat, if I&#39;m honest.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;admonition info inline&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/sketches/22-11-29-DeansCHS.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Deans CHS again&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Back to Deans again and a view from a different part of the car park. It&#39;s interesting how varied these buildings can look, depending on where you look from. My wife calls my style &#34;Roobarb&#34;, for the unsteady hand that wiggles the lines. I did get an &#39;O&#39; level many years ago in technical drawing, so I do know how to use a ruler but when I&#39;m trying to work quickly -- none of these sketches took more than 10 minutes -- the look is more one of impression than technical accuracy. I was conscious that I was cold sitting in the car at Deans and so the lines were more Roobarb than usual, perhaps. More figure suggestions, though, and they seem to be growing on me. I&#39;m quite pleased with the silver birch, too, given that I&#39;m not giving myself time to make 10,000 strokes for the leaves.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/sketches/22-11-30-DingwallAc.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dingwall&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A long but pleasant drive up beyond Inverness took me to new territory, and once more found me shaking hands with colleagues who had passed through my tutorials at Moray House. It&#39;s lovely to see the products of my labour thriving and making their mark on young people across the country. I am taking all the credit, of course, as I will for the superb teacher whose lesson on nuclear fission was one of the best I have ever seen. It&#39;s not all me, of course: a lot of work goes in to becoming a teacher, especially a good one, and you have to bring a lot of things, too. Attitude, aptitude, wit, intelligence, humour, resilience, just to mention a few. Those who bring all of that with them perhaps don&#39;t need much from me to succeed, but I do like to tell myself that I help them excel.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;admonition info inline end&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/sketches/22-12-01-BroxburnAc.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Broxburn Academy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the weeks of touring schools come to an end for this session at least, I feel that I have been inspired by students, colleagues and the young people in schools. The student teachers have a steep learning curve, especially on their first school placement. Workload can be an issue, and both schools and the university urge the students to try to find a good, healthy, sustainable balance. I asked some of them what their &#34;secret&#34; is for managing this. All said that the balance is crucial to survival, and that part of that is remaining physically active through sport or exercise. Some of them run; others swim or play a sport. This advice I took myself today by going for a run in the early morning darkness. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Vehicles are often a challenge for schools at the beginning and end of the day, even more so when parking is limited, so the final visit of the tour found me arriving at my destination later than planned. I parked in a quiet residential area and enjoyed a walk through the catchment instead of having time to sketch. By now, I was thinking that although every school is different, I had probably sketched enough fairly-recently-built school buildings to have a good appreciation for their character. &lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-12-05-school-sketches/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_created.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-12-05-school-sketches/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-12-05-school-sketches/</guid> <enclosure url="https://niximagery.com//img/sketches/22-11-15-Linlithgow2.JPG" type="image/jpeg" length="None" /> </item> <item> <title>The Summer House</title> <category>Fuji X</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-summer-house&#34;&gt;The Summer House&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF0360_Panorama.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Summer House towards the lake&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We took a weekend off for our anniversary, heading to a beautiful retreat in the Borders within the grounds of Chisholme House estate. We have not often chosen the Borders over our more usual favourite direction of North but wanted, as usual, a decent distance from hustle and bustle, nature and a wood-burning stove to curl up in front of at the end of the day. A place to read, reflect, walk and enjoy life together. Not far from Hawick, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.summerhousestays.co.uk/&#34;&gt;the Summer House&lt;/a&gt; offers all of that and more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF0022.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Summer House from the lake&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This place has been fairly recently renovated and is cosy, warm and spacious enough for families and small groups to enjoy the stunning countryside here. There is a lake close by with swans and moorhens. A young deer met us on the driveway as we headed on to the estate. Owls serenaded the night. An otter played chicken with us in the road and then blew otter raspberries from the safety of a hedge.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;chisholme-house&#34;&gt;Chisholme House&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF0373_Panorama.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chisholme House&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We did not go for (or know about) the retreats offered by the school at Chisholme but were intrigued and perhaps focused a little by the environment. From &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.chisholme.org/&#34;&gt;their website&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;admonition quote&#34;&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;admonition-title&#34;&gt;Dedicated to the art of self discovery&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chisholme offers an education for those who are convinced of our potential as human beings for goodness and positive effect on this earth, and who wish to be of service to it, to love and to learn.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-sense-of-sufism&#34;&gt;A sense of Sufism&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;There seems to be no particular religion behind the philosophy at Chisholme but the school considers writings of great scholars of Islam, in particular those in the Sufi tradition such as Rumi and Ibn&#39;Arabi. The Summer House includes artefacts of the three Abrahamic faiths of Islam, Christianity and Judaism. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF0417.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF0377.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Basmala&lt;/strong&gt; appears at threshholds to the old and new summerhouse. The older summer house is in the walled garden, which is well tended by the gardner and a team of volunteers who give service as a form of study and reflection. Quotes from Bulent Rauf and others suggest that central to the teachings of the Institute is unity of life and self discovery. On the hill above the house is the Monument to Man:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF0169_Panorama.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Monument to Man&lt;/strong&gt; above the estate has engraved around the circumference, &#34;ALL ARE FROM HIM AND TO HIM THEY RETURN&#34;, resonant with similar phrases in the Bible (e.g. Romans 11:36) and the Qu&#39;ran (e.g. Surah Al-Baqarah 2:156). In the ground near to the monument, with its four pillars representing Chisholme&#39;s own pillars of &lt;em&gt;work&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;study&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;meditation&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;zikr&lt;/em&gt;, is a circular stone bearing the inscription:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;O CONFIDENT SOUL, RETURN TO YOUR LORD, AGREEING AND AGREED TO ENTER AMONG MY SERVANTS AND ENTER MY PARADISE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a variation of another well known passage from the Qu&#39;ran, Surah 89, Al-Fajr (Dawn, verses 26 -- 30).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;time-travel-to-tushielaw&#34;&gt;Time Travel to Tushielaw&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We didn&#39;t stay in the house for the whole weekend, and ventured out on a trip to Tushielaw for Sunday lunch. Despite high expectations for nice country pub food, instead it became more of a journey in time back to the 1970s. You had to have been there, of course, to fully appreciate the standard of service and fag reek over the sausage, egg &#39;n&#39; chips with a choice of two sauces. And the footie on the telly. And the time it took for &lt;em&gt;mine host&lt;/em&gt; to work out by hand, calculator, pen and paper in hand, the bill. And the landlady&#39;s omnidirectional blather at anyone, or no-one, in the lounge. Such experience serves to remind us of how fortunate we are to be who we are.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;reflection&#34;&gt;Reflection&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF0070.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cygnet on the lake&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It takes little reflection on life to see this ugly duckling as the gracious beauty he is becoming. Our weekend at the summer house gave us time and space to discuss things that concern us and things that make us. We took time and space to see ourselves more clearly and shared life and laughter. We resolved to act, and to not act, on these things. Chisholme draws on Lao Tsu for some of its teaching, describing it:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The philosophy of Lao Tsu is simple: Accept what is in front of you without wanting the situation to be other than it is. Study the natural order of things and work with it rather than against it, for to try to change what is only sets up resistance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think this understates Lao Tsu&#39;s recognition of man&#39;s free will and ability to use it. On the way home, we took advice from the Hadith:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anas ibn Malik reported: A man said, “O Messenger of Allah, should I tie my camel and trust in Allah, or should I leave her untied and trust in Allah?” The Prophet, peace and blessings be upon him, said, “Tie her and trust in Allah.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Source: Sunan al-Tirmidhī 2517&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes-on-camera-equipment&#34;&gt;Notes on camera equipment&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;All of the pictures on this page were made with a Fuji X-T2 camera, and either the Fujifilm Fujinon XF16mmF1.4 R WR wide-angle lens, the 100-400 or my old Nikon 85mm Ai-S f/1.4. They were post-processed in Capture One Pro. There are other pictures yet come, taken on Lomo Babylon ISO 13 black &amp;amp; white film with Nikon FM SLR.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-10-16-summer-house/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_created.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-10-16-summer-house/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-10-16-summer-house/</guid> <enclosure url="https://niximagery.com//img/DSF0022.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="None" /> </item> <item> <title>The Glen</title> <category>Fuji X</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-glen&#34;&gt;The Glen&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;admonition quote&#34;&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;admonition-title&#34;&gt;Diane Arbus&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A photograph is a secret about a secret. The more it tells you the less you know.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaking of Kings, we went for a walk in Pittencrieff Park (known locally as &#34;The Glen&#34;). We were hunting for autumn leaves for an artsy project, specifically Oak. A walk in a park is never a bad idea in my book, and it gave me a chance to re-introduce myself to the big Fuji XF100-400mm zoom lens that I got back from service and repair this week.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9730.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dunfermline Abbey&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;King Charles III recently formally conferred city status on Dunfermline, during his first joint royal visit with the Queen Consort since the death of Queen Elizabeth. The townsfolk &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2022/oct/03/king-charles-confers-city-status-on-dunfermline-scotland&#34;&gt;turned out for the occasion&lt;/a&gt;, which is nice, even if some were apparently a little unkind to our First Minister. I couldn&#39;t possibly comment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9732.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Abbey and Abbey Church&lt;/strong&gt; were basking in the early autumn glow. I love how the light played around the buttresses of this old place, which has &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.undiscoveredscotland.co.uk/dunfermline/abbeypalace/index.html&#34;&gt;quite a history&lt;/a&gt;. Walking down into the Glen, the colurs in the Japanese Garden were no less magical.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9739.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Japanese Acer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The contrast was strong as we explored some of the nooks and crannies. Sunlight danced on water and dappled through the leaves, reflecting and re-reflecting greens and reds, oranges and yellows between dark and mysterious Tolkienesque shadows.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9742.jpg&#34; /&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Waterfall&lt;/strong&gt; on Tower Burn.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;audio controls=&#34;controls&#34;&gt; &lt;source type=&#34;audio/mp3&#34; src=&#34;/audio/Pittencrieff%20Park.mp3&#34;&gt; &lt;source type=&#34;audio/ogg&#34; src=&#34;/audio/Pittencrieff%20Park.ogg&#34;&gt;&lt;/audio&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9763.jpg&#34; /&gt;What the Americans call &lt;strong&gt;a Sqrl&lt;/strong&gt;. There are plenty of these in and around Dunfermline (squirrels, although there are a fair number of Americans, even at this time of year). They have a sense of humour, of course, and will run right across the feet of anyone with a camera just to watch them fumble for focus and fail.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9819.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alliums&lt;/strong&gt; in the formal garden. We walked here after pausing for a breakfast roll at the Peacock Room, and chatting to an old friend I hadn&#39;t seen for 20 years. That was a pleasant surprise and oddly, enabled me to fill in a couple of gaps from a particular period in my life. Nothing major, more an ironing out of wrinkles in a shirt I haven&#39;t worn for a while, but a resolution nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9861.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This iconic peacock&lt;/strong&gt; is one of a number in the park. There is a new enclosure following the recent mindless attack that resulted in the injury of one bird and the death of another, Malcolm, named for the King whose wife Margaret established the Abbey. More help is needed to support the volunteers who put heart and soul into caring for these beautiful creatures. If you can help, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.paypal.com/paypalme/pittencrieffpark?country.x=GB&amp;amp;locale.x=en_GB&#34;&gt;please drop them a few quid&lt;/a&gt;. Thank you, and thanks for reading.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;camera-gear&#34;&gt;Camera gear&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;All of the pictures on this page were made with the Fuji XF100-400mm F4.5-5.6 R LM OIS WR lens and my brilliant digital Fuji X-T2 camera. They were tastefully post-processed in Capture One Pro.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-10-08-the-glen/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_created.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-10-08-the-glen/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-10-08-the-glen/</guid> <enclosure url="https://niximagery.com//img/DSF9730.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="None" /> </item> <item> <title>Dysart</title> <category>Fuji X</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;dysart&#34;&gt;Dysart&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;admonition quote&#34;&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;admonition-title&#34;&gt;Robert Bresson&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Make visible, what without you, might perhaps never have been seen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;After lunch, we had an errand to run in the Lang Toun which gave us an excuse to take another walk, this time around the harbour at Dysart. There is a huge wall there which is home to various pigeons, and tells quite a story of how this place has changed over the years. Part of the cliff at the end of the harbour is no longer safe to walk along but it is easy to access the coastal walk through a short tunnel in the cliff at the end of the wall.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9879.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dysart Harbour Wall&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9878.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A shed&lt;/strong&gt; by the harbour was eclectically decorated with harboury stuff, and really set the feel of the place.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9882.jpg&#34; /&gt;We arrived at feeding time for the boats, and they seemed to think we had treats for them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9886.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The wall again&lt;/strong&gt;, because it is fascinating. The landscape of it seemed other-worldly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9885.jpg&#34; /&gt;Plenty of things to look at in a harbour. There were people working, moving boats, furling sails and so on, and just as many sitting on benches. There were benches everywhere we looked today and I think I like that. Perhaps we are becoming more reflective.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;camera-gear&#34;&gt;Camera gear&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;All of the pictures on this page were made with the Fujifilm Fujinon XF16mm F1.4 R WR prime lens and the Fuji X-T2 camera. They were post-processed in Capture One Pro.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-10-08b-dysart/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_created.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-10-08b-dysart/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-10-08b-dysart/</guid> <enclosure url="https://niximagery.com//img/DSF9879.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="None" /> </item> <item> <title>Lower Largo</title> <category>Fuji X</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;lower-largo&#34;&gt;Lower Largo&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the day of the King&#39;s proclamation, and in need of some sea air, we took a run up the coast to Lower Largo. It&#39;s been a challenging week for us in one way and another, not least for the depth of emotion we felt at the death of the Queen. There have been other losses, of course, but this one seems to have brought home Joni Mitchell&#39;s statement of the obvious: &lt;em&gt;you don&#39;t know what you&#39;ve got &#39;til it&#39;s gone&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9639Panorama.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We walked along the upper path, it being near high tide, to a favourite spot on the beach beside what looks like a rockery arrangement for a garden. The waters swirled around the rocks and the sun passed slowly, ever lower in the sky as autumn progresses, reminding us again of the relentless march of time. Not yet ready to forget the dog days of summer, the sun shone warmly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9628Panorama.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We sat for a while, the tide shifting the shapes and scenery with sand and seaweed. Sea kayaks passed out in the Forth, with the dead offshore platform Sedco 711 breaking up the horizon. Sunlight sparkled and shimmered on the water as time, &lt;em&gt;ralenti&lt;/em&gt;, became all but suspended in the reverie.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9626.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s nothing like a beach, and no better beach than a Scottish beach, to purge stress and anxiety, those corrosive curses of the contemporary condition. After the passage of some indeterminate time, things are just better than they were; big things smaller; a feeling of coming home settles.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9641.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As we walked along the path, the soothing splash of the waves on the shore below provided headspace in which to process and park our reflections on the week&#39;s events and resolutions were quietly packed in their pockets, ready for when we will need them. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9652.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teasels&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’ve learned that home isn’t a place, it’s a feeling. — &lt;em&gt;Cecelia Ahern in&lt;/em&gt; Love, Rosie&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-09-10-lower-largo/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_created.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-09-10-lower-largo/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-09-10-lower-largo/</guid> <enclosure url="https://niximagery.com//img/DSF9654.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="None" /> </item> <item> <title>An afternoon at Stronachie and Loch Leven</title> <category>Fuji X</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;an-afternoon-at-stronachie-and-loch-leven&#34;&gt;An afternoon at Stronachie and Loch Leven&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Saturday afternoon, for no good reason and many, we jumped in the car with some snacks and went hunting for fresh air and ice cream. We went for a stroll down at Loch Leven. Walking out on the jetty, we saw the light was perfect and a heron was posing nicely along the shore. Of course, by the time we walked back to the car for our cameras, he was gone. The ice cream was easy, Giacopazzi&#39;s in Kinross providing a very nice solution. Cookies and Cream for him, Peach Melba for her. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9458_Panorama.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loch Leven&lt;/strong&gt; Fuji X-T2, 35mm f/2. Stitch of four images.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Onwards to a partly aimless drive to explore some favourite roads: through Milnathort, out by Tillyrie and Athron Hill where we had a look at a housing development seriously out of our range. Who needs a house that big anyway?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9479.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stronachie Forest&lt;/strong&gt; X-T2, Nikon 85mm f/1.4&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On an easy walk at Stronachie, all of our senses were exercised. The air was rich in oxygen from the forest, perfumed with heather; the air crackled as the broom seed pods burst open in the warm late summer sun.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9561.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Broom seed pods&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I changed the lens on the Fuji for the Stronachie walk, having started with the compact and versatile Fuji 35mm f/2, for my Nikon 85mm f/1.4. This is a difficult lens to focus wide open but it makes quite creamy bokeh washes from the background colours, even in low light. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9508.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plenty of room in the forest&lt;/strong&gt; f/1.4 at 1600 ISO&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Nikon lens is well known for its flare, too. This rainbow effect from shooting into the light is caused by internal flare in the lens.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9495.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rainbow flare&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Fuji X equivalent lens, the 90mm f/2, doesn&#39;t have the same flare or bokeh as the much older Nikon. It&#39;s not reasonable to compare them, perhaps, because of their age difference. Both are designed as portrait lenses.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9512.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stronachie Forest&lt;/strong&gt; X-T2, Nikon 85mm f/1.4&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;How fortunate we are to live within reach of such wonders of nature.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-08-27-stronachie/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_created.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-08-27-stronachie/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-08-27-stronachie/</guid> <enclosure url="https://niximagery.com//img/DSF9458_Panorama.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="None" /> </item> <item> <title>East Neuk Day Trip</title> <category>Fuji X</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;east-neuk-day-trip&#34;&gt;East Neuk Day Trip&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;We took a holiday hurl up the coast, just to take some air and not do the things that seem to have eaten the summer. We were lucky enough to get to the Hebrides, of course, but have managed to do other things too. Today was about switching off for a wee road trip along the fabulous Fife coast.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;st-monans-church&#34;&gt;St Monans Church&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;St Monans Church&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9295Panorama.jpg&#34; /&gt;I am particularly pleased with this 87 megapixel image of the church that is connected so intimately with my wife&#39;s family and her heritage. She has family in the church yard here and the iconic church deserves a decent place in our gallery. I hope to print this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-fife-machair&#34;&gt;The Fife Machair&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;The Fife Machair&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9355.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Fife Machair&lt;/strong&gt; is out in full bloom, with flowers of all colours basking in the sunshine. There seem to be fewer poppies than usual, for some reason, but we found a few near Kilconquhar.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All of the images in this post, except the St Monan&#39;s beach steps below, were taken with my lightweight kit of the Fuji X-T2 and the amazing XF 35mm f2 lens. I&#39;ve been making more large images recently, when using the digital kit, by stitching several images together, not unlike the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brenizer_Method&#34;&gt;Brenizer method&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;St. Monans beach steps&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9337Panorama.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;St. Monans beach steps&lt;/strong&gt; For this image, taken as we returned from a walk along the path above the beach at St Monans, I used my old Nikon 85mm lens, stitching two images for a nice large square printable photo.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;poppies&#34;&gt;Poppies&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Poppies&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9420.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Poppies&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9414.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Poppies&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9413.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Poppies&lt;/strong&gt; are the flowers of remembrance and I can&#39;t spend time with poppies without feeling the emotions they invoke and what they signify. That culture is fading, I think, even as we are today, in time of war. People in some of my circles seem to be offended by remembrance and what used to be the importance of it. So long as I am able, I will not forget. So long as there are poppies, we will all be reminded, even if we choose to forget.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ice-cream-at-pittenweem&#34;&gt;Ice cream at Pittenweem&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Pittenweem Harbour&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9397Panorama.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pittenweem Harbour&lt;/strong&gt;, X-T2, XF35mm. We stopped for an ice-cream on the way home, and enjoyed a cone in the famous fishing town of Pittenweem. This is 3 images, edited a little (as they all are) in Capture One.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-08-07-east-neuk/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_created.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-08-07-east-neuk/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-08-07-east-neuk/</guid> <enclosure url="https://niximagery.com//img/DSF9397Panorama.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="None" /> </item> <item> <title>The colours of Portra</title> <category>Kodak Portra</category> <category>Nikon FM</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-colours-of-portra&#34;&gt;The colours of Portra&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Slowly getting my head around analogue photography... a roll of 800 in my old Nikon FM. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/FM-Kodak-Portra-800-20210110_15053096.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trees at Glendevon in the snow&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I recently wrote about a trip to &lt;a href=&#34;/Stories/2020/2020-11-28-Kilminning/&#34;&gt;Kilminning&lt;/a&gt; up the Fife coast and the images I made with a Fuji GW690ii. Well, I also had with me a Nikon FM 35mm camera with some Kodak Portra 800 in it. This is a colour negative film, which cost £12.50 per roll from Analog Wonderland, and was eventually processed by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ag-photolab.co.uk/&#34;&gt;AG Photolab&lt;/a&gt; once I&#39;d finished it. I&#39;m not processing my own colour film just yet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/FM-Kodak-Portra-800-20210110_14310009.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sunset at Lower Largo&lt;/strong&gt;. Obviously right down at f/22 and 1/1000s of a second, but still produced a flare at the top of the image (which I cropped out). Who points a camera at the sun?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What I am finding is that I am preferring medium format for no other reason than it takes &lt;em&gt;forever&lt;/em&gt; to finish a roll of 36 frames. If it&#39;s a colour film, it can be literally months between closing the shutter and seeing the result, by which time my photography has moved on, or at least, I&#39;ve forgotten what I was thinking at the time. It&#39;s as if I become detached from the image: quite the reverse of my intention in returning to film. Perhaps I ought to up my game a bit: perhaps I&#39;m over diverse. On most of our recent outings, I&#39;ve had at least three cameras with me. I don&#39;t think this is helping me much. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/FM-Kodak-Portra-800-20210110_15094070.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lower Largo&lt;/strong&gt;. I like the sky.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Accurate metering still evades me, but I feel I am getting a clearer understanding of this: I&#39;ve started Ansel Adams&#39; &lt;em&gt;The Negative&lt;/em&gt; in which he describes his &lt;em&gt;Zone System&lt;/em&gt; for proper evaluation of a frame. With some understanding of this, maybe I&#39;ll be less reliant on the &#34;magic&#34; of my phone&#39;s app, or the little red LEDs in my Nikon, which rarely agree on what the correct exposure settings are.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/FM-Kodak-Portra-800-20210110_15155136.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Castle Hill reservoir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Portra emulsions have a characteristic colour palette that I like. It&#39;s almost pastel: I think it&#39;s probably more suited to brighter light than I have exposed it in this roll, which are mostly wintery scenes, most recently taken on a walk out at Glenquey reservoir. The top image, of trees at Glendevon in the snow, gains very little from the colours of Portra, for example.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/FM-Kodak-Portra-800-20210110_15195895.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bridge at Glendevon&lt;/strong&gt;. White balance adjusted from the scanner&#39;s default in Capture One. A bit more Portra-like, in my view.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another aspect of this workflow that is bothering me is what the scanner assumes in the process. The colours and contrast often seem unimpressive. I can&#39;t tell if it&#39;s me or the device: I&#39;m assuming it&#39;s me at the moment, because I want to not overdo the post-processing. Here&#39;s one that I adjusted white balance, a little clarity, and added just a touch of sharpening to. I quite like it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/FM-Kodak-Portra-800-20210110_15350082.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glendevon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The whole point of analogue photography is that you fiddle as little as possible in the digital space. That sounds like something that should be on a T-shirt.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Brand&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Type&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;ISO&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Format&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Exposures&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Camera&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Lens&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Kodak&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Portra&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;800&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;35mm&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;36&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Nikon FM&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Nikon AI-s 28mm f/2.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2021/2021-01-10-Kodak-Portra-800-FM/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 21:08:12 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_created.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2021/2021-01-10-Kodak-Portra-800-FM/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2021/2021-01-10-Kodak-Portra-800-FM/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Portra 160 in the snow</title> <category>Fuji GW690ii</category> <category>Kodak Portra</category> <category>Nikon FM</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;portra-160-in-the-snow&#34;&gt;Portra 160 in the snow&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;35mm and 120 Portra 160 in winter. &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/GW690ii-Kodak-Portra-160-20210222_20055951.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pattiesmuir. Fuji GW690ii&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/GW690ii-Kodak-Portra-160-20210222_19423865.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thomas and his gate. Fuji GW 690ii&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Winter brings many charms, not the least of which is snow. There&#39;s a smell to it that takes me back to childhood. With the COVID restrictions, we can&#39;t go far, but we are lucky enough to have nearby places that keep us within travel limits and yet at a distance from other people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/FM-Kodak-Portra-160-20210223_08513917.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Moon over farm gate. Nikon FM&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This picture and those that follow were taken on a walk up Common Hill near Glendevon. We took poles with us, and crampons on our boots, to make the climb and descent more pleasant and less like hard work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/FM-Kodak-Portra-160-20210223_09083923.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;From Common Hill, Glendevon. Nikon FM&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/FM-Kodak-Portra-160-20210223_09104630.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Poles at the top of Common Hill. Nikon FM&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/FM-Kodak-Portra-160-20210223_09145060.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Frandy Tree. Nikon FM&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Blow, blow, thou winter wind,&lt;br /&gt; Thou art not so unkind as man’s ingratitude;&lt;br /&gt; Thy tooth is not so keen, because thou art not seen,&lt;br /&gt; Although thy breath be rude.&lt;/em&gt; -- William Shakespeare&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Brand&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Type&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;ISO&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Format&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Exposures&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Camera&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Lens&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Kodak&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Portra&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;160&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;120&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Fuji GW690ii&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;90mm&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Kodak&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Portra&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;160&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;35mm&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;36&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Nikon FM&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Nikon AI-s 28mm f/2.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2021/2021-02-23-Kodak-Portra-160-snow/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 21:08:12 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_created.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2021/2021-02-23-Kodak-Portra-160-snow/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2021/2021-02-23-Kodak-Portra-160-snow/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Dumglow</title> <category>Fuji X</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;dumglow&#34;&gt;Dumglow&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF7743.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Moss&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We took a walk up a local hill to clear our heads of work matters, get some exercise, and connect with nature and bigger things. It was exactly a year since my Mum had left this mortal coil and we had woken at the same time as we had a year ago when the call came. It seemed appropriate to be occupied with the world in a less worldly way, yet we packed ourselves a healthy lunch, boots and cameras.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF7767.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Loch Leven&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I took my digital Fuji X-T2 and a favourite 35mm f/2 lens for its versatility. There was a film camera in my backpack but I didn&#39;t think too much about photography, to be honest. It was nice to walk in the sunshine, through cool forest with the soft humus, springy beneath our feet and the birdsong all around us. As ever, it was windy near the top of Dumglow: the final climb up the forest path is accompanied by the sound of it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF7748.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dappled forest light&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scotland. There&#39;s no place quite like it for your mental wellbeing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Image&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Camera&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Lens&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;ISO&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Format&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Aperture&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Shutter&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Comment&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Header&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Fuji X-T2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Fujinon XF35mm F2 R WR&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;ISO 200&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Digital&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/1000s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Loch Leven&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Fuji X-T2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Fujinon XF35mm F2 R WR&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;ISO 200&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Digital&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/400s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Loch Leven&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Forest light&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Fuji X-T2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Fujinon XF35mm F2 R WR&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;ISO 200&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Digital&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/250s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2021/2021-03-21-fuji-xt2/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 21:08:12 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_created.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2021/2021-03-21-fuji-xt2/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2021/2021-03-21-fuji-xt2/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Three 120 films</title> <category>Hasselblad V</category> <category>Kodak E100</category> <category>Kodak Portra</category> <category>Kodak T-Max</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;three-120-films&#34;&gt;Three 120 films&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Kodak-Ektachrome-E100-20210729_20494968-1.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kinghorn beach, Fife&lt;/em&gt; Hasselblad, E100&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I sort of lost track of photography in the first part of this year, not least film photography. There were 3 120 films kicking about for a while, which I eventually sent to AG on 3rd April 2021 for developing and scanning. The negatives came back all square, with telltale Hasselblad notches that told me they were taken in my 503CW.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Brand&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Type&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;ISO&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Format&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Exposures&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Camera&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Lens&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Kodak&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;T-Max BW Pan&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;400&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;120&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;12&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Hasselblad 503CW&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Zeiss 80mm F2.8 C&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Kodak&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Portra&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;160&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;120&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;12&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Hasselblad 503CW&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Zeiss 80mm F2.8 C&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Kodak&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Ektachrome E100&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;100&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;120&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;12&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Hasselblad 503CW&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Zeiss 80mm F2.8 C&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;I hadn&#39;t been in the habit of recording exposure details this year, either, so there&#39;s a bit of guesswork in identifying the subject of the images. From a digital note on my phone:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;TMY BW - From the Agfa?&lt;br /&gt;Portra 160 maybe Hasselblad&lt;br /&gt;E100 — Hasselblad on Kinghorn / Burntisland beach 3 April&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Possibly — Hasselblad Portra Crail&lt;br /&gt;1 rock at f/16 about 1/8s&lt;br /&gt;2 same Lee 10 stop 2 1/2 min inc 30 sec for rf &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scanned results were disappointing: dust on the BW, dust and only 11 frames on the Portra, and bands/rainbow stripes on the E100. AG said the dust wasn’t their problem, nor was the fact that I thought I had ordered TIFFs and received jpegs. I certainly won’t be using them again for this service, which was 35 quid on top of processing. They did offer to rescan the slides.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I bought some &lt;em&gt;Digitaliza&lt;/em&gt; negative holders from Lomography over the summer and tried them rescanning some of these images. I had to fight a bit with the Epson website to download the driver for the MacBook Air I am using, which runs macOS Big Sur 11.4 but the first scan out at 600 dpi wasn&#39;t bad, and was certainly better than the scans I had from AG.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next strip -- the Digitaliza does a whole strip at a time -- was from the Portra and was also OK. This image was an experiment with the super-dark Lee neutral density filter and a long exposure. It&#39;s OK, and proves it can be done but it seems tasteless to me, to use film this way. I probably won&#39;t do it again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Kodak-Portra-160-20210729_20341321.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Crail beach. Hasselblad 503CW with Lee Big Stopper&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The last strip was of Kodak Ektachrome E100, for which I switched the scanner&#39;s colour management off. These were very nice indeed, with just a trace of banding visible in the sky on a sunny walk on Kinghorn beach (see header image).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Kodak-Ektachrome-E100-20210729_20494968.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kinghorn Beach. Hasselblad 503CW hand held&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One thing I am sure of, is that I don&#39;t look after my film stock particularly well: it goes nowhere near a fridge, spending much of its life bashing around in a tin box in the boot of my car. I&#39;m going to try to do something about that, maybe, before getting stressed out about the banding here: I did better than a professional scanning service.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2021/2021-07-29-three-films/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 21:08:12 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_created.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2021/2021-07-29-three-films/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2021/2021-07-29-three-films/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Berlin at Dunkeld in October</title> <category>Agfa Isolette</category> <category>Lomo Berlin</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;berlin-at-dunkeld-in-october&#34;&gt;Berlin at Dunkeld in October&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Berlin-400-Afga-20201031_12343959.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Hermitage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My wife and I celebrated our first anniversary by returning to Dunkeld, where we were married. We had time, this time, to walk more slowly, considering only ourselves, and to enjoy the nature of the place. We both took cameras and enjoyed playing in the outdoors, visiting favourite places and just breathing the air.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Berlin-400-Afga-20201031_12034276.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Tayside walk by Dunkeld House Hotel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I took my little old Afga Isolette, a ridiculously cheap camera (some of the film I put through it costs more than the camera did) that has no meter or gadgets to tell you where to set the dials. You have no choice but to figure it out according to the light and the film parameters, and what you&#39;re trying to achieve. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Berlin-400-Afga-20201031_12353688.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At the Hermitage, looking towards the bridge.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have ditched the neurotic habit of writing down every exposure setting of every frame. Consequently, I&#39;ve enjoyed my photography more, although I am less certain of good results. One benefit of living in the modern age is that we have tools to make adjustments after scanning to yield something not unpleasing. These were tweaked a little in Capture One to try and retain the character of the film, as well as trying to achieve a reasonable photograph. This example features a little colour toning in the highlights and shadows:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Berlin-400-Afga-20201031_12134961 1.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Killiekrankie shore, cropped and split toning in Capture One&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All a bit of fun.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes-on-the-film&#34;&gt;Notes on the film&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first time I tried this film, I wrecked it with a stupid mistake in developing. This time, I sent it to AG photo for processing, not so much because I was afraid to develop it myself, but more because I have been too busy to do my own processing. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This roll I put through my little old Afga Isolette. Not much detail in the exposure list below because I have ditched the neurotic habit of writing down every exposure setting of every frame. I&#39;ve enjoyed my photography more, although I am less certain of good results. Hopefully my success rate will improve with practice, if I learn anything as I go.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These were scanned on my Epson V600 and post processed in Capture One for levels, colour and cropping.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Brand&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Type&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;ISO&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Format&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Exposures&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Camera&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Lens&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Lomography&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Berlin&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;400&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;120&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;12&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Agfa Isolette I&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Agfa Agnar 1:4.5/85&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;Frame&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Image&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Comment&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;1.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Killiecrankie waterside&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;2.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Killiecrankie Bridge&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;3.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Killiecrankie shore&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;4.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Tay shore&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Above&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;5.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Tayside tree&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;6.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The dookit&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Focus poor&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;7.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The Hermitage&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;8.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The Hermitage&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;9.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The Hermitage&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Tree stump&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;10.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The Hermitage&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The actual hermitage (header image)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;11.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The Hermitage&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Bridge&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;12.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The Hermitage&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Waterfall&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-10-30-Berlin-400-Isolette/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 17:24:20 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_created.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-10-30-Berlin-400-Isolette/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-10-30-Berlin-400-Isolette/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Five frames of Ilford SFX IR Film</title> <category>Fuji GW690ii</category> <category>Ilford SFX</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;five-frames-of-ilford-sfx-ir-film&#34;&gt;Five frames of Ilford SFX IR Film&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Ilford-SFX-200-20201106_18490187.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On a weekend break in Perthshire, I tried my hand at infra-red by dropping a roll of Ilford SFX 200 film in my Fuji GW690ii &#34;Texas Leica&#34; rangefinder camera. My wife and I were in Dunkeld celebrating our first anniversary, returning to where we were married. This year, autumn was on time and the Hermitage forest was just magnificent and we had time to enjoy it properly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve never used infra-red sensitive film before so I did a bit of reading about it before the trip: on the day, I put a Neewer IR720 filter on and took about 6 stops off the exposure estimates. I metered at ISO 200, which is the box speed for this film in visible light. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Ilford-SFX-200-20201106_18411489.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Hermitage forest&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The exposures looked a couple of stops under when I got the film back from AG Labs, but there was plenty of detail available in the negatives to lift out. I had intended to develop the film at home but life&#39;s a bit busy at the moment for such pleasures. I scanned the film on an Epson V600 and made adjustments in Capture One Pro.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Ilford-SFX-200-20201106_18432539.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The river Braan above the Tay&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have ditched my neurotic habit of writing down every exposure setting for every frame. Consequently, I&#39;ve enjoyed my photography more, although I am less certain of good results. One benefit of living in the modern age is that we have tools to make adjustments after scanning to yield something not unpleasing. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Ilford-SFX-200-20201106_18465341.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At the Hermitage, looking towards the bridge.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The image at the top of the page is of the waterfall by Ossian’s Hall, which can just bee seen at the right of the frame. I cropped this down but kept the others on this page at the full size.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Ilford-SFX-200-20201106_18374061.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hermitage forest trails. Long exposures revealed in the movement.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m quite pleased with the results from my first time out with near-infra-red film. There&#39;s a slightly timeless look to the pictures caused by the rendering of foliage in infra-red wavelengths. Next time, maybe I&#39;ll seek brighter light and try longer exposures using the 850nm or 950nm filter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Infra red sensitive black and white film, cost £12.50 per roll from Analog Wonderland. Developed by AG photographic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Brand&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Type&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;ISO&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Format&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Exposures&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Camera&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Lens&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Ilford&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;SFX&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;200&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;120&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Fuji GW 690 ii&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Fixed Fuji 90mm&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-11-06-Five-frames-SFX/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 17:24:20 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_created.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-11-06-Five-frames-SFX/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-11-06-Five-frames-SFX/</guid> </item> <item> <title>The final frames</title> <category>Kodak GC</category> <category>Premier PC-645D</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-final-frames&#34;&gt;The final frames&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I lost my mum in March this year, just as COVID was descending on the world. As long as I remember, she had always been keen, sometimes too keen, to capture a moment in a photograph. I inherited a rich and wonderful collection of albums and shoe-boxes full of family memories, and of quite a lot of people I don&#39;t recognise.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Amongst her possessions was a little point-and-shoot automatic 35mm camera, a Premier PC-645D. It still had a film in it. I took the camera with me on a couple of trips, including our anniversary weekend to Dunkeld, where we had been married the year before. In some sense, it was a way of making up for her not being able to travel up to Scotland for our wedding: we had taken her the albums of the wedding to see before she was admitted to hospital on Christmas Eve 2019. For a short while this year, it was as if she was with us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Her final pictures were typical. This one, evidence of a mystery. A bungee strap had suddenly appeared with a clatter on the roof of her cottage one day, on the day a stowaway&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-london-48830212&#34;&gt;body was found&lt;/a&gt; in a Clapham garden. Mum was convinced that this strap had something to do with it and alerted the authorities, who took no interest. I told her that I thought it entirely feasible that the strap might be connected to the tragedy somehow.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Kodak-GC-400-20201108_09280128.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bungee from the sky&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The second is of three visitors to her little house in Letchworth, Michelle, Marilyn and Tracey, cousins on the Brennan side (my grandmother&#39;s). Mum often had visitors; Michelle wrote of this visit:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;admonition quote&#34;&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;admonition-title&#34;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I lost her phone number and we just went unannounced, but she still made us welcome. I&#39;m so grateful we decided to go anyway as this was to be the last time we saw her. Letchworth captured my heart, and from the first time I went with my mum to re-unite with the cousins Audreys, I absolutely adored your mum, such a beautiful and fascinating lady. I will never forget all her advice, she taught me so much that I didn&#39;t know about our family on the Brennan side, especially the ones that emigrated to Canada.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Kodak-GC-400-20201108_09232103.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Three visitors&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We took a trip along the coast near us, to Crail. Here&#39;s my wife at work, and the kind of place mum would have enjoyed being if she were able to travel. Her health wasn&#39;t the best, it never had been, but she never offered it as an excuse or let it prevent her from living the most fruitful and interesting life. The crashing waves on this rocky coast would have been right up her street.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Kodak-GC-400-20201108_09413090.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crail&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, on the weekend to Dunkeld, I took a selfie for mum of my wife and I in the mirror in our suite, not taking into account the flash on this little point-and-shoot, &#34;focus free&#34; camera. I can&#39;t help thinking that the flare somehow indicates her presence with us on that day as we celebrated our anniversary, and remembered a remarkable woman.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Kodak-GC-400-20201108_09460354.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is that you?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-11-07-Last-frames/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 17:24:20 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_created.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-11-07-Last-frames/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-11-07-Last-frames/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Kosmo Foto 100 35mm</title> <category>Kosmo Foto</category> <category>Nikon FM</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;kosmo-foto-100-35mm&#34;&gt;Kosmo Foto 100 35mm&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Kosmot-Foto-100-20201108_18385924.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Black and white panchromatic film, cost £5.25 per roll from Analog Wonderland. Loaded August 2020, in camera until October 2020. Used with a yellow filter, the ISO on camera meter was set to 64 ASA to compensate 2/3 stop for it. Developed at AG labs, 36 exposures, last exposure details not recorded, but they were taken mostly at Braefoot Bay terminal, Fife, and included images of a building at Charles Hill Battery. The image of that building shown here was cropped slightly and adjusted in Capture One.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Kosmot-Foto-100-20201108_18373029.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beach at Crail&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Kosmot-Foto-100-20201108_18104115.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thistles, Crail&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Kosmot-Foto-100-20201108_19205709.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tracks in the sand, Braefoot Bay&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Kosmot-Foto-100-20201108_19254649.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Charles Hill Battery, Fife&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Brand&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Type&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;ISO&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Format&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Exposures&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Camera&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Lens&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Kosmo&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Kino BW&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;100&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;35mm&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;36&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Nikon FM&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Nikon AI-s 28mm f/2.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;Black and white panchromatic film, cost £5.25 per roll from Analog Wonderland. Loaded August 2020, in camera until October 2020. Used with a yellow filter, the ISO on camera meter was set to 64 ASA to compensate 2/3 stop for it. Developed at AG labs, 36 exposures, last exposure details not recorded, but they were taken mostly at Braefoot Bay terminal, Fife, and included images of a building at Charles Hill Battery. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;Frame&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Image&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Aperture&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Shutter&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Comment&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;1, 2.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Fidra&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Beach picnic, Yellowcraigs 1 August&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;3.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Shells&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;4.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Rocks, waves&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125 s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Crail 22 August 20&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;5.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/2.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/1000 s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;6.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Thistles&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/60 s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;7.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125 s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;8.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Shore&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125 s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;9.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Shore&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/2.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/1000 s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;10.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Waves&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/5.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125 s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;11–13.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Cows&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125 s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Dunning 20th September&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;14.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Rural tree&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/60 s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Header&lt;/strong&gt;, cropped&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;15.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Rural tree&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/30 s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Hand held&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;16.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Rural tree&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/30 s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;ditto, portrait&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;17.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Crail&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125 s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Crail trip 26th September&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;18 -- 19.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Sea Horses&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/2.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/1000 s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;20.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;ATC Tower&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125 s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;21.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Log&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/2.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/60 s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-11-08-Kosmo-100/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 17:24:20 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_created.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-11-08-Kosmo-100/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-11-08-Kosmo-100/</guid> </item> <item> <title>The Hermitage on Portra 800</title> <category>Kodak Portra</category> <category>Nikon FM</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-hermitage-on-portra-800&#34;&gt;The Hermitage on Portra 800&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Kodak-Portra-800-20201109_09424821.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The unmistakable bridge at Ossian&#39;s Hall&lt;/strong&gt;, which runs over the river Braan. Autumn&#39;s colours were everywhere on this trip.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;More images from our recent anniversary trip to Dunkeld in October. These are from a roll of Kodak Portra 800 taken with my Nikon FM. This is my second roll of Kodak&#39;s pastelly colour negative film&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:aw&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:aw&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; in a 35mm camera&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:fm&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:fm&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, after a service by Cameratiks in Morningside. I didn&#39;t record exposure settings for this film, having got out of the habit -- for deliberate mindfulness in my photography, rather than laziness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Brand&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Type&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;ISO&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Format&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Exposures&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Camera&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Lens&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Kodak&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Portra&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;800&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;35mm&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;36&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Nikon FM&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Nikon AI-s 28mm f/2.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Kodak-Portra-800-20201109_09004793.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Killiecrankie&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Kodak-Portra-800-20201109_09022596.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stone towers at Killiecrankie. Why do people do that?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Kodak-Portra-800-20201109_09145595.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The little place on the Tay where we were married.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Kodak-Portra-800-20201109_09323769.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A portrait of Ossian&#39;s Hall from the bridge&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Kodak-Portra-800-20201109_09454798.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Landscape of Ossian&#39;s Hall from the bridge&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:aw&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This roll cost £12.50 per roll from Analog Wonderland. The roll was sent to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ag-photolab.co.uk/&#34;&gt;AG Photolab&lt;/a&gt; for processing at about £3.49 plus P&amp;amp;P. About 45p per image.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:aw&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 1 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:fm&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;I bought this, my first film SLR camera back in the 1970&#39;s, second-hand, for about £125 including a 50mm Nikon lens. That lens is long gone -- part-exchanged, maybe, for the Tamron 80--200mm zoom that was on this camera for much of its first life.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:fm&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 2 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-11-09-Kodak-Portra-800/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 17:24:20 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_created.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-11-09-Kodak-Portra-800/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-11-09-Kodak-Portra-800/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Yester Castle</title> <category>Agfa Isolette</category> <category>Fujifilm Pro</category> <category>Ilford Delta</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;yester-castle&#34;&gt;Yester Castle&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Ilford-Delta-3200-20201127_20295583.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The castle wall&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Ilford Delta 3200&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We went down to Gifford, in East Lothian, to find that the new owners of the farm have made walkers on the land very unwelcome. I wasn&#39;t in the mood for a fight, so we took a drive down to the golf club, where we were welcome to park, provided that we let them know in the clubhouse. It&#39;s nice to know there are still public-spirited folk out there.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I decided not to be burdened with camera gear, so just took my little Afga Isolette, which had a few frames left in it of a roll of Fuji Pro400H, and a roll of Ilford Delta 3200 in my pocket.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Ilford-Delta-3200-20201127_20085880.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Part of the keep remains&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Ilford Delta 3200&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A walk alongside the bunkers and greensward took us to one of our favourite haunts, Goblin Ha&#39;. This magical place has been here for almost a thousand years and is full of stories and little hidey-places. The remains of the castle and keep are here, along with a subterranean crypt that can be accessed with care: the path is slippery and dangerous at the best of times, let alone in the wet seasons.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Ilford-Delta-3200-20201127_20114793.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The underground crypt from outside&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Ilford Delta 3200&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Fuji 400H came back from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ag-photolab.co.uk/&#34;&gt;AG Labs&lt;/a&gt; absolutely flat, which makes it easier to scan. I&#39;d struggled recently with film stock curling in the scanner, spoiling my efforts to make nice, in-focus images. The images themselves were more contrasty and emotive in the Ilford photographs, in my view. Compare the above image with this one:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Fujifilm-Pro400H-20201207_18485469.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The crypt from outside&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Fujifilm Pro 400H&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This was a family outing: a chance for some of us to spend quality time together in this natural and mystical place, right for reflection. The setting was good for clearing heads and strengthening bonds. Little discoveries and the distraction of mindful photography made for a perfect autumnal break from the madness. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Ilford-Delta-3200-20201127_20271449.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A portal in the old castle wall&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Ilford Delta 3200&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I developed the Delta 3200 film in 1:150 Rodinal R09 for an hour and scanned both on my Epson V600 at 4800 dpi. Most of the images are about 100 Mega pixels at that resolution and the negatives are nice and sharp. Not bad for a fifty-year old folder that cost me about the same as each roll of film did.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Brand&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Type&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;ISO&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Format&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Exposures&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Camera&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Lens&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Ilford&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Delta&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;3200&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;120&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;12&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Agfa Isolette I&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Agfa Agnar 1:4.5/85&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Fuji&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Pro 400H&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;400&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;120&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;12&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Agfa Isolette I&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Agfa Agnar 1:4.5/85&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-11-27-Ilford-Delta-3200/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 17:24:20 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_created.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-11-27-Ilford-Delta-3200/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-11-27-Ilford-Delta-3200/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Lower Largo</title> <category>Fuji GW690ii</category> <category>Fujifilm Acros II</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;lower-largo&#34;&gt;Lower Largo&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Fujifilm-Neopan-Acros-II-100-20201127_21154833.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We took a weekend run up the coast to Crail and the Kilminning nature reserve, and we played on the beach at Lower Largo. I used up my last roll of Acros in my GW690ii rangefinder -- I thought it was polite to put Fuji in Fuji.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Fujifilm-Neopan-Acros-II-100-20201127_20404271.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Forth Estuary&lt;/strong&gt; Acros II&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The estuary is wide at this point, and the North Sea lies beyond to the East. Oil rigs work the natural resources. Shipping passes and wildlife abounds as the waves are expressive and sincere in their tidal cadence. The people love the beaches, where cares are blown away and life slows to reveal its meaning.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Fujifilm-Neopan-Acros-II-100-20201127_21014664.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Half Moon&lt;/strong&gt; Acros II&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I developed the Acros film at home in Rodinal R09 for an hour, turning once half-way, which I regret. The highlights might have been less bright if I hadn&#39;t, and retained more detail.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Camera&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Lens&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Film&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Comment&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Fuji GW690ii&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;90mm&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Fuji Acros 100 II&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Yellow filter&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-11-28-Kilminning/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 17:24:20 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_created.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-11-28-Kilminning/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-11-28-Kilminning/</guid> </item> <item> <title>First experiences with Ilford Delta 400 35mm film.</title> <category>Ilford Delta</category> <category>Nikon FM</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;first-experiences-with-ilford-delta-400-35mm-film&#34;&gt;First experiences with Ilford Delta 400 35mm film.&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/20-3-22-Delta-400-5.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Earlsferry, Fife.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ilford Delta is a well-known black and white film from the famous UK manufacturer that has been around for almost 30 years. I put a roll of 400 through a Nikon FM. This post describes some of the images I made and what I did with them. The film was exposed over the first few weeks of 2020 and sent to AG Photographic in Birmingham for developing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;harlow-water&#34;&gt;Harlow Water&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We had to take a trip to Essex in January and had time to take a walk along the River Stort that runs through a generic-looking town on the outskirts of London. The river seems clean enough to sustain life, as there were people fishing along the banks. The first image here is a crop: bottom right you can see fading from what looks like a light leak in the camera. I think it&#39;s something to do with the back plate. I bought this camera from eBay to replace my original 1970s Nikon FM that has a condemned shutter, and the back doesn&#39;t shut cleanly with the satisfying click of my original.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/20-3-22-Delta-400-18.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Harlow Water&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not sure I&#39;d be eating any of the fish they caught, as there were dog walkers kicking their poochy-poo directly from where it was dropped on the tow path into the river. I asked one of the fishermen if this is normal behaviour round here. He said everybody did it. I was disappointed with that level of cultural disrespect amongst the dog-walking people of this town towards their environment. Despite being in the middle of an industrial estate, this little stretch of river, with its abandoned house-boats, is pretty, and no doubt home to a lot of life. It&#39;s worth exploring - there&#39;s more information &lt;a href=&#34;https://canalrivertrust.org.uk/places-to-visit/harlow&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/20-3-22-Delta-400-19.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Harlow Water&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next image has been adjusted for tone in Capture One for a more vintage look. This might offend some &#34;analogue&#34; purists but I&#39;m just playing here. There aren&#39;t any rules, and Capture One is a nice tool for messing about with images that might otherwise be considered uninteresting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/20-3-22-Delta-400-20.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Harlow Mill&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-fife-coast&#34;&gt;The Fife Coast&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I next picked up the camera, we were up the &lt;a href=&#34;/2020/03/08/the-east-neuk.html&#34;&gt;East Neuk&lt;/a&gt;. I continued the split toning exercise with the next two frames, toning the shadows blue and the highlights in the complementary yellow.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/20-3-22-Delta-400-22.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bass Rock&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here, the Forth River basks in sunrays from an approaching storm. The toning enhances, I think the menacing clouds and waters. For monochrome images, it might seem weird to re-introduce colour but I think as an artistic technique, it enhances these shore photos. It didn&#39;t work for me with the Harlow Water images.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/20-3-22-Delta-400-26.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Forth River&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;kinghorn-beach&#34;&gt;Kinghorn Beach&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The last of these photographs was taken a few days later, down on the beach at Kinghorn. It is untoned but suffers with the same light leak problem I talked about above. This image was taken in portrait orientation and cropped slightly to make use of the false flare. I think it looks OK.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/20-3-22-Delta-400-34.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kinghorn&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary-of-the-results&#34;&gt;Summary of the results&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reviews of this film suggest that it is very sharp, although I am sure that this is true only when in better hands. I am not convinced that I get the best results by sending it to AG Photographic, although I don&#39;t doubt they are the best of the labs out there. Perhaps this is just a manifestation of the Dunning-Kruger effect and I&#39;ll change my mind once I learn more about it. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I took a roll of photographs back in the 1970&#39;s and 1980&#39;s, I would consider it a success if I got one or two good frames from a roll of 135. I think I have half a dozen here that I&#39;m pleased with, despite the leaky light problem. A significant factor in this increased success rate must be the greater opportunity there is to work with the images post-processing. Even the scanning tool &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:SF8&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:SF8&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; allows me to straighten the horizon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;next-steps&#34;&gt;Next steps&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I will try this film again and process it myself to see if I get better results, but also maybe I ought to stop buying old cameras online and expecting them to perform optimally without at least letting someone who knows what they are doing check them over for me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/20-3-22-Delta-400-24.jpg&#34; /&gt;Frame 24 &lt;em&gt;Bass Rocks&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This film was in my Nikon FM between 10th January and 14th March 2020. It was processed by AG Photolab. I switched lens part way through this film to a new 28mm f/2.8 Nikon which is very much better than the E series lens I had been using. At the same time, I added a Tiffen Yellow filter which made sky contrast much better too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Brand&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Type&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;ISO&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Format&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Exposures&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Camera&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Lens&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Ilford&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Delta&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;400&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;35mm&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;36&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Nikon FM&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Frames 1 - 20 Nikon 50mm f/1.8 Series E&lt;br/&gt;Frames 20 - 36 Nikon AI-s 28mm f/2.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;Frame&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Image&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Aperture&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Shutter&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Comment&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;1.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Euston&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/2s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;10 Jan. Hand held&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;2.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Preston station&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/4s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;3.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Preston station&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/15s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;4.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Preston station&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/1.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;5.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Earlsferry&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/16&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;12th Jan.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;6.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Shore&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;7.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Waves&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/1000s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;8.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/15s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;9.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/250s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;10.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/16&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/60s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Hand held&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;11.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Sunset&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;12-13.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Birds&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/250s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;14.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/250s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;15-17.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Crashing waves&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/2.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/1000s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;18.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Harlow water&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/60s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;18th Jan&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;19.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Harlow water&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/30s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;20.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Harlow mill lock 8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;River stort&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;21.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Culross sunset&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/5.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;26 Feb 28mm lens yellow filter&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;22.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Bass rock thru wall&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;8 March 28mm lens yellow filter - The East Neuk&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;23.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;KM at work&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/60s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Hand held&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;24.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Bass rocks&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/16&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;25-6.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Shafts/Edinburgh&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/16&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;27.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Shafts&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/60&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;28-30.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;shafts and rainbow&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/60s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;31-36.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Kinghorn Beach&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/16&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/500s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;14th March&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:SF8&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;SilverFast 8, which is actually bloody awful software with a functionality and interface from the 1990&#39;s. This software came with the Epson V600 scanner I bought from Wex and was provided by Epson because their own software doesn&#39;t work at all with OSX.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:SF8&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 1 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-03-22-delta-400/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 15:16:46 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_created.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-03-22-delta-400/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-03-22-delta-400/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Lost and found: Images recovered from found film</title> <category>Coronet Consul</category> <category>Kodak Verichrome</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;lost-and-found-images-recovered-from-found-film&#34;&gt;Lost and found: Images recovered from found film&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/20-4-4-Kodak-Verichrome-1.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Unknown family group&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, my wife was given a box of cameras and bits, including an old Coronet Consul box camera. Recently, we dug it out and I had a play around with it. It was absolutely goosed&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:fubar&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:fubar&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, but it did contain a roll of exposed film. Having recently started playing with home development, I binned the camera and processed the roll in Rodinal R09, just to see what we might find. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I thought we might find some pictures of my wife&#39;s family back in the day, but it seems the uncle who gifted the box had picked the camera up at a car boot sale. I scanned a couple of frames and put them into Capture One to tweak the exposure and try to recover as much as I could. The header on this page is an example, and I have no idea who these people are. It looks like a nice family enjoying a proper British 1960&#39;s holiday on the Costa Brava.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Brand&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Type&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;ISO&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Format&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Exposures&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Camera&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Kodak&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Verichrome Pan&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;125&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;120&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Coronet Consul&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;Frame&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Image&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Aperture&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Shutter&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;1-4.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Family group&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;unknown&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;unknown&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;5-6.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Garden images&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;unknown&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;unknown&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;7-8.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Blank&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:fubar&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;FUBAR, BER, FBR, knackered, broken, done for, deid.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:fubar&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 1 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-04-11-lost-and-found/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 15:16:46 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_created.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-04-11-lost-and-found/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-04-11-lost-and-found/</guid> <enclosure url="https://niximagery.com//img/20-4-4-Kodak-Verichrome-1.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="None" /> </item> </channel></rss>