<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"> <channel><title>Niximagery</title><description>Stories and images</description><link>https://niximagery.com/</link><atom:link href="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_updated.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><managingEditor>Nick Hood</managingEditor><docs>https://github.com/NixImagery</docs><language>en</language> <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 19:43:02 -0000</pubDate> <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 19:43:02 -0000</lastBuildDate> <ttl>1440</ttl> <generator>MkDocs RSS plugin - v1.5.0</generator> <image> <url>https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/4/43/Feed-icon.svg/128px-Feed-icon.svg.png</url> <title>Niximagery</title><link>https://niximagery.com/</link> </image> <item> <title>RPS Distinction</title> <category>Fuji X-T2</category> <category>RPS</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;rps-distinction&#34;&gt;RPS Distinction&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/47090179834_cb210348da_b.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03 Julian Alps, one of the images in my LRPS Panel.&lt;/strong&gt; Fuji X-T2 16mm ISO 200 f/11&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Royal Photographic Society has recommended a panel of my photographs for the distinction of Licentiate (LRPS). This, some 8 months after my wife and I first submitted, with one of us being awarded LRPS immediately. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-lrps-panel&#34;&gt;The LRPS Panel&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had to make changes to one of my images (09 Fenchurch Street) to remove distracting lines that were at first taken to be a printing error. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;panel-layout&#34;&gt;Panel Layout&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes called the eleventh image, the layout of the panel of photographs is an important aspect for the assessors. There has to be a pleasing aesthetic to the arrangement and balance of the images when displayed as a complete body. I spent far too long worrying about details of aspect ratio and colour balance across the panel, I think. The advisory day was useful to get a sense of what the assessors like. These are things like the two faces looking inwards, similar colours at each end of a row, those kinds of spectrumy details that provide satisfaction for a critical viewer, and they are, critical.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;next-steps&#34;&gt;Next steps&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am pleased to have finally achieved this distinction which I take to be an acknowledgement that I am learning something about photography. I&#39;d like to continue my artistic journey by developing my knowledge and skills of the photographic process. I have continued this through making the improvements required to the panel first submitted, and by exploring composition using medium format film, for example.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;RPS Logo&#34; src=&#34;/img/RPS_LRPS_RGB.PNG&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-02-06-lrps/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 16:08:37 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_updated.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-02-06-lrps/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-02-06-lrps/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Beach Stories</title> <category>Fuji X-T2</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;beach-stories&#34;&gt;Beach Stories&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Imagined back stories of things found on the beach&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/beach-stories/breakwater.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;The famous breakwater at St. Monans, Fife.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most of these images were made in November 2019 at Clashnessie, in the Assynt, and all of them were made with the Fuji X-T2 camera and the Fujinon XF16mm F1.4 R WR lens at ISO 200.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-backwards-aerial-with-half-twist&#34;&gt;The backwards aerial with half twist&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/beach-stories/the-backwards-aerial-with-half-twist.jpg&#34; /&gt;A difficult manoeuvre to perform with grace, it can be done with concentration and a great deal of practice. She had thought mindfully all morning as she prepared, emptying her head of distractions and day to day concerns. When the moment came, she was ready: time stood still and the crowd were hushed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;epsilon&#34;&gt;Epsilon&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/beach-stories/epsilon.jpg&#34; /&gt;Berry-like prophecies of Christmas coming, arms reaching forward in time. I thought I could see the shape of a letter E, moving to the right of frame.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-argentine-tango&#34;&gt;The Argentine Tango&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/beach-stories/the-argentine-tango.jpg&#34; /&gt;Carlos and Eva seemed to defy the laws of gravity as they danced their contragiros. Onlookers would gasp as she poured herself over his limbs in a steamy, sensuous, syncopated embrace.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;kestrel&#34;&gt;Kestrel&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/beach-stories/kestrel.jpg&#34; /&gt;He glides, and hovers on the imperceptible breeze, scanning for little violet trickles and traces that betray the poor vole, scurrying, hopping, scampering along, cursing his evolutionary luck.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Image&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Camera&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Lens&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Film/ISO&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Aperture&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Shutter&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Comment&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;St. Monans breakwater&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Fuji X-T2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Fujinon XF16mm F1.4 R WR&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;ISO 200&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/60s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The backwards aerial&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Fuji X-T2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Fujinon XF16mm F1.4 R WR&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;ISO 200&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/5.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/200s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Epsilon&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Fuji X-T2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Fujinon XF16mm F1.4 R WR&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;ISO 200&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/5.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The Argentine Tango&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Fuji X-T2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Fujinon XF16mm F1.4 R WR&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;ISO 200&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/320s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Kestrel&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Fuji X-T2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Fujinon XF16mm F1.4 R WR&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;ISO 200&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/5.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/200s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;All images on this page were processed from the RAW file in Capture One Pro 20.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-03-16-beach-stories/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 16:08:37 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_updated.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-03-16-beach-stories/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-03-16-beach-stories/</guid> </item> <item> <title>A few days in Assynt</title> <category>Apple iPhone</category> <category>Bergger Panchro</category> <category>Fuji GW690ii</category> <category>Fuji X-T2</category> <category>Ilford Ortho</category> <category>Lomo Berlin</category> <category>Nikon FM</category> <category>Ricoh GRIII</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-few-days-in-assynt&#34;&gt;A few days in Assynt&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Holiday how the Scots do it&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF7259.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Achmelvich beach&lt;/strong&gt;, X-T2 XF35mm, ISO 1600 f/2 at 1/1000s&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Emerging confidently from weeks of COVID-19 lockdown and the sting of a cancelled Hebridean trip at Easter, we consoled ourselves with a few days immersed in the beauty of the Sutherland Assynt.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I went armed with a full complement of cameras (five - count them. Who needs five cameras?), most of which I now fit into a new kitBrick which I picked up at Tiso in Perth on the way up. Finally, I have a camera kit bag solution that works for all the gear I carry on a trip like this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;achmelvich&#34;&gt;Achmelvich&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The drive was long but pleasant, in a new (to us) Mercedes GLA, which is much more suited to the kind of driving one does on a trip to the Northwest of Scotland than the saloon it replaced. We took a look at Achmelvich beach after settling in to the apartment we had AirBnB&#39;d for a few nights. Everything seems booked up, which seems weird, given that there are almost no overseas visitors to these shores at present and the roads are almost utterly empty.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF7264.jpg&#34; title=&#34;Achmelvich beach&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Achmelvich beach&lt;/strong&gt; X-T2 XF35mm, ISO 1600 f/2 at 1/1000s&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We returned to Achmelvich a couple of times, well, because we love it, even if the weather doesn&#39;t always love us. The machair is in full bloom at the moment. The local people care for it by mowing swards through the meadow-like grass to encourage visitors not to trample randomly over the new growth. There are visitors here apart from ourselves: I edited out the tent on the beach in the next photo, because camping isn&#39;t allowed on the beach at Achmelvich.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF7292.jpg&#34; title=&#34;Achmelvich again&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Achmevlich beach&lt;/strong&gt; (long exposure) X-T2 XF16mm, ISO 200 f/16 at 20 s&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/img20200716_02.jpg&#34; title=&#34;Achmelvich again&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Achmevlich beach&lt;/strong&gt; (Panchro 400). The figure in the grass is Kara. Fuji GW690ii f/11 at 1/30s. Toning in Capture One. You can read more about this roll and how I developed it &lt;a href=&#34;/Exposures/2020/2020-07-12-Bergger-Panchro-400/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;stac-pollaidh&#34;&gt;Stac Pollaidh&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We took the walking route around Stac Pollaidh. There&#39;s a new, lottery-funded, improved path here to protect the slopes and give the old well-trodden path a chance to recover. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF7274-DSF7276.jpg&#34; title=&#34;Going up Stac Pollaidh&#34; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Going up Stac Pollaidh, looking East&lt;/strong&gt; X-T2 XF16mm, ISO 200 f/11 at 1/250s. Stitch of 3 images (Hugin)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/IMG_8838.jpg&#34; title=&#34;Going up Stac Pollaidh&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Going up Stac Pollaidh, looking South back towards the car park&lt;/strong&gt; iPhone 11 wide-angle&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although we hadn&#39;t really intended to, we took the higher path, and reached the ridge near the top, which in retrospect, is something we feel good about. Going the last few metres higher required better climbing experience, gear, or stupidity. Fortunately, we had left ours at the fork in the lower path.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/R0000589.jpg&#34; title=&#34;On the ridge&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On the ridge on Stac Pollaidh&lt;/strong&gt; Ricoh GRIII, taken by Kara&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-coigach-peninsula&#34;&gt;The Coigach peninsula&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;On a long meandering drive around the Coigach peninsula, the light changed constantly. Waze told us we were 2 hours from our apartment as we turned for home, yet only 37 km distant. This is because, perhaps, the twisty single-track roads ought to be driven only at 20 kph. The streams and foliage, deer and passing places pass by the window even at that speed, every now and then opening up wide open skies, the cotton grass stretching to the distant hills.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF7286-DSF7288.jpg&#34; title=&#34;Road to Achnahaird Bay&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Road to Achnahaird Bay&lt;/strong&gt; X-T2 XF16mm, ISO 320 f/16 at 1/125s. Stitch of 3 images (Hugin), cropped and coloured in Capture One Pro 20&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;... and the ever-present sheep.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/IMG_8855.jpg&#34; title=&#34;Two wanderers&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Two wanderers&lt;/strong&gt; iPhone 11 wide-angle&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;stoer-and-clachtoll&#34;&gt;Stoer and Clachtoll&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This holiday was a good way to get familiar with a new car and I felt comfortable enough after a day or so to take it off-road down to a fisheries bothy at Stoer. We got chatting to a ranger when were here last October about whales and dolphins. We had promised to send the Mercedes dealer a picture of the car from our trip.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/R0000623.jpg&#34; title=&#34;Mercedes GLA at Stoer&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The new Merc looking moody at Stoer&lt;/strong&gt; Ricoh GRIII, Silver Efex Pro 2.0&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of our favourite places (of all the favourite places we have around this part of Scotland) is Clachtoll beach, which at the time we visited, was at high tide. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/R0000611.jpg&#34; title=&#34;Clachtoll beach&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clachtoll beach&lt;/strong&gt; Ricoh GRIII, Capture One colour adjustments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;glencoe&#34;&gt;Glencoe&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The final day of our holiday was spent much further South, in Glencoe, stopping on the way down to make a brew and eat BLT sandwiches and cheese&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:cheese&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:cheese&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; on the gravelly beach at Loch Lochy. Even with a wind, that was paradise.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/IMG_8857.jpg&#34; title=&#34;Loch Lochy&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loch Lochy&lt;/strong&gt; iPhone 11 wide-angle&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We checked in to The Corran by the ferry terminal and headed straight out for a walk along the Coupall to catch some time with Buachaille Etive Mòr.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF7297.jpg&#34; title=&#34;The Buachaille&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buachaille Etive Mòr&lt;/strong&gt; X-T2 XF16mm, ISO 200 f/16 at 0.4 s&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a magical place, even in the rain. Actually, probably &lt;em&gt;especially&lt;/em&gt; in the rain. The heather and harebells, dancing in the wind to the syncopation of the river rushing over the rocks, flail and flutter, the great herdsman above, indifferent to their earnest performance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/R0000639.jpg&#34; title=&#34;Harebells&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harebells at Etive Mòr&lt;/strong&gt; Ricoh GRIII, ISO 400 f/16 at 1/40s&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The day&#39;s adventure concluded with a flaccid fish supper from the Quarrier&#39;s Kitchen in Ballachulish, before heading back to Corran to journal the day. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;home&#34;&gt;Home&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The drive home was wet but not without adventure as we stopped at Tindrum, more to support the business than to buy stuff we actually needed. We marvelled at how busy it was, and how heavy the Northbound traffic was, caravans and campers heading in droves for the NC500 and the midges.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We stopped briefly at Achnambeithatch, the little white cottage below Bidean nam Bian on the A82, to watch the weather for a while. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/R0000643.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Achnambeithatch&lt;/strong&gt; Ricoh GRIII, ISO 400 f/16 at 1/60 s&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We decided that the rain was in for the day, so headed South, and lunched at the King&#39;s House, as much to their delight as ours, emerging as they were for the first day back in business after months of COVID-19 closure. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are more images associated with this post, taken with the Nikon FM using &lt;a href=&#34;/Exposures/2020/2020-11-07-Ilford-orthochrome-80&#34;&gt;Ilford Orthochromatic film&lt;/a&gt;. I am a bit disappointed with the film photos on this trip. I hoped for better, sharper, images but am just not getting that with the big Fuji GW690ii at the moment. I am making errors, &lt;a href=&#34;/Exposures/2020/2020-06-07-Lomography-Potsdam-100&#34;&gt;losing an entire roll&lt;/a&gt; from an earlier trip by using stop bath instead of developer, and the &lt;a href=&#34;/Exposures/2020/2020-07-13-Lomography-Berlin-400&#34;&gt;Lomo Berlin&lt;/a&gt; film I had in the GW690iii on this trip, which I ruined by using the wrong developer. You live and learn. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:cheese&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cashel Blue, bought at the House of Bruar on the way up.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:cheese&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 1 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-07-14-assynt/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 16:08:37 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_updated.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-07-14-assynt/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-07-14-assynt/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Belhaven Beach</title> <category>Apple iPhone</category> <category>Fuji X-T2</category> <category>Ilford Ortho</category> <category>Nikon FM</category> <category>Ricoh GRIII</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;belhaven-beach&#34;&gt;Belhaven Beach&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;More local exercise&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF7302.jpg&#34; /&gt;X-T2 XF16mm, ISO 400 f/11 at 1/500s using Velvia film simulation&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s nothing like a walk on a beach, especially when it&#39;s one of the long, windy, sea-birdy beaches like you find along the coast near Dunbar. We took ourselves off to Belhaven beach for such a walk, to clear the head, and to reset our fish supper metrics after a bad experience at Ballachulish.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m finding myself using a mix of digital and film cameras when I&#39;m out. When I need to shoot quickly, it&#39;s more likely that I&#39;ll grab the Ricoh in my pocket, like when I noticed a figure walking across the scene before us:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/R0000655.jpg&#34; title=&#34;Lone figure walking&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Socially distant&lt;/strong&gt; Ricoh GRIII, cropped and desaturated&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I keep the Ricoh in aperture-priority mode at f/16 when shooting landscape, if the light is OK. It really is a fabulous camera, and more than once I&#39;ve thought that if I could only have one camera, it would be this one. If I could only have no cameras, I&#39;d still have my phone, which is a pretty amazing piece of kit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/IMG_8861.jpg&#34; title=&#34;Belhaven beach&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Belhaven beach&lt;/strong&gt; (iPhone)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;also&#34;&gt;Also&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I also took some photos with my Nikon FM, on Ilford Ortho Plus 80 film. Read about those exposures &lt;a href=&#34;/Exposures/2020/2020-11-07-Ilford-orthochrome-80/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-07-18-belhaven-beach/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 16:08:37 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_updated.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-07-18-belhaven-beach/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-07-18-belhaven-beach/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Resolutions, some photographic</title> <category>Fuji X-T2</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;resolutions-some-photographic&#34;&gt;Resolutions, some photographic&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;December, 2020. After Christmas. Some thoughts at the end of an interesting year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF7687.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glenquey reservoir&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Like many people, I don&#39;t see the point of making resolutions at the end of the year, only to break them within a few days of returning to normal life, its pressures and temptations. This year, the (first?) year of pandemic restrictions, has given us all opportunities to reflect a little: the reflection necessarily includes looking at oneself. Here is where we see ourselves more objectively -- in the moments of noticing just how we change as we get older. Perhaps also, we observe how we have &lt;em&gt;not changed&lt;/em&gt; when we ought to have.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-old-year&#34;&gt;The old year&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF7648.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glendevon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Well, there&#39;s been COVID, of course, but there have been other things going on. We lost my Mum in March, after a 3-month circus tour of various hospitals and the lottery of the NHS that began on Christmas Eve 2019. Others left us too, and there is sadness more than usual this Christmas as we remember them. Without diminishing our losses, there has also been much joy: weddings, our own first anniversary which was spent in favourite places around Dunkeld; and the last instalments of our honeymoon with friends in the North, and then even further North in the Faroes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-new-year&#34;&gt;The new year&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF7674.jpg&#34; /&gt;This image of a bridge at Glendevon&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:covid-1&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:covid-1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; suggests that as we cross into the New Year, the road may be slippery at times. We probably need to lose a bit of weight (I feel like I am 7ft 6in wide in places), and we certainly ought to slow down a bit. Working life, not to be ungrateful for my exciting and challenging job&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:rgu-1&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:rgu-1&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, has been more challenge than excitement in 2020. I have &lt;em&gt;COVID back&lt;/em&gt; from &lt;em&gt;Zooming&lt;/em&gt; too much from the couch, suffered nightmares from stress anxiety and have more than once drafted a desperate resignation letter. The Christmas break has reminded me of the blessings proper sleep brings. I resolve to sleep better. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Beyond the bridge, we are advised that we must not park in passing places, so as to not be a nuisance to others and obstruct their passage. This year, I have noticed even more that I have not been quite who I was before becoming an educator: ever since that career move in 2003, I have had an insidious, creeping feeling that I don&#39;t belong, that I am somehow in the way. I resolve to assert with confidence and authority, as I spent so long learning, my confidence and authority. May I not overdo that resolution. Or, may I do it so well I have to return to a more lucrative profession.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Or, maybe something else entirely. Not photography, perhaps, there&#39;s no money in that&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:nwmt&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:nwmt&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;photography&#34;&gt;Photography&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The last sign to heed in our bridge image is &lt;strong&gt;&#34;Danger of death&#34;&lt;/strong&gt;. Susan Sontag said, &lt;em&gt;&#34;All photographs are memento mori&#34;&lt;/em&gt; and she is right, even outwith the context she said that in. Photography reminds us that time passes and we all tread steadfastly towards our own demise with each snap of the shutter. This is reason to be cheerful, isn&#39;t it? Death is inevitable, so there&#39;s no point in being sad about it. I am expecting something to fall off a shelf as I type that&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:audrey-1&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:audrey-1&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been (re-)learning how to take photographs on film, and now feel confident enough to invest in my first Hasselblad, which will be here in a week or so. Clearly, I resolve to take many images with that, and to not neglect the other cameras I am privileged enough to own. Film photography, it is often said, requires a slower, more thoughtful approach than the spray-and-pray approach of digital. I can&#39;t disagree, and I have loved the more considered captures I have taken on 35mm and medium format film this year. My best images are often digital, though, so I am not going to &lt;em&gt;try not to&lt;/em&gt; favour one format over the other.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF7637.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fujica Pro 400H&lt;/strong&gt;, taken on a Fuji X-T2 camera but with a Nikon 50mm E-series lens, reverse mounted on an adaptor. A proper example of analogue meets digital photography. Notice, however, the square format, presaging the arrival of more 6x6 images.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;so-come-on-2021&#34;&gt;So, come on, 2021&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do your worst. No, wait. Don&#39;t do that. Do what you have to, to enjoy each day as if it&#39;s your last. To fill it with &lt;em&gt;joie-de-vivre&lt;/em&gt;. To make music. To create. To love, and if possible, to be loved. Everything else is irrelevant.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unless otherwise stated, the images on this page were taken with a Fuji X-T2 camera fitted with a Fujinon XF100-400mm F4.5-5.6 R LM OIS WR lens.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Image&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Focal length&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;ISO&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Aperture&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Shutter&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Glendevon reflections&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;235mm&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;2000&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/250s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Glendevon&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;160mm&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;3200&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/5.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/250s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Glendevon Bridge&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;235mm&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;3200&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/5&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/250s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;All were tastefully post-processed using Capture One Pro 21.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:covid-1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Taken on a walk that started within 5 miles of the county border, officer. I take it you have caught all the criminals, then?&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:covid-1&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 1 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:rgu-1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;at a Russell Group University, don&#39;t you know? Dahling, it doesn&#39;t get better than &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt;, surely?&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:rgu-1&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 2 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:nwmt&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not with my talent and business skills, anyway.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:nwmt&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 3 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:audrey-1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is an in-joke. My dear, departed mother was a believer in the paranormal and would often tell stories of her out-of-body experiences and the materialisation of random objects. Since she loosed the silver cord in March, there have been one or two inexplicable, or at least unexplained incidents. I am a scientist, therefore am ruling nothing out.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:audrey-1&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 4 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-12-28-Resolutions/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 16:08:37 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_updated.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-12-28-Resolutions/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-12-28-Resolutions/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Dumglow</title> <category>Fuji X-T2</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;dumglow&#34;&gt;Dumglow&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF7743.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Moss&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We took a walk up a local hill to clear our heads of work matters, get some exercise, and connect with nature and bigger things. It was exactly a year since my Mum had left this mortal coil and we had woken at the same time as we had a year ago when the call came. It seemed appropriate to be occupied with the world in a less worldly way, yet we packed ourselves a healthy lunch, boots and cameras.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF7767.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Loch Leven&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I took my digital Fuji X-T2 and a favourite 35mm f/2 lens for its versatility. There was a film camera in my backpack but I didn&#39;t think too much about photography, to be honest. It was nice to walk in the sunshine, through cool forest with the soft humus, springy beneath our feet and the birdsong all around us. As ever, it was windy near the top of Dumglow: the final climb up the forest path is accompanied by the sound of it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF7748.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dappled forest light&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scotland. There&#39;s no place quite like it for your mental wellbeing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Image&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Camera&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Lens&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;ISO&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Format&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Aperture&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Shutter&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Comment&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Header&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Fuji X-T2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Fujinon XF35mm F2 R WR&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;ISO 200&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Digital&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/1000s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Loch Leven&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Fuji X-T2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Fujinon XF35mm F2 R WR&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;ISO 200&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Digital&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/400s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Loch Leven&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Forest light&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Fuji X-T2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Fujinon XF35mm F2 R WR&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;ISO 200&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Digital&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/250s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2021/2021-03-21-fuji-xt2/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 16:08:37 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_updated.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2021/2021-03-21-fuji-xt2/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2021/2021-03-21-fuji-xt2/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Coigach and Assynt</title> <category>Fuji X-T2</category> <category>Hasselblad V</category> <category>Ilford PanF Plus</category> <category>Kodak E100</category> <category>Kodak Portra</category> <category>Kodak T-Max</category> <category>Nikon FM</category> <category>Sketch</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;coigach-and-assynt&#34;&gt;Coigach and Assynt&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few days in the North West&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF8005.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thistles. Fuji X-T2&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For our summer trip North this year, I took the Hasselblad 503CW and my Nikon FM with digital backup from a Ricoh GRIII and my Fuji X-T2. The Agfa stayed in the bag and the GW690ii stayed at home. There&#39;s only so much gear one can carry.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the first beaches we headed for was Acheninver, a short walk from the hostel where we spent the first couple of nights. It was overcast for the first few days of our break, which was a blessing for us because the mobs were elsewhere. At the beach was a man filling builder&#39;s bags with seaweed: curious, I asked him why. Crofter Steve Husband explained that there is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.islemartin.org/isle-martin-seaweed-festival-home/&#34;&gt;seaweed festival&lt;/a&gt; on Isle Martin in September and that a dry run of glassmaking had used the entire stock of seaweed, so he was replenishing. The seaweed is dried and burned with sand to make artisan glass, and burning kelp is an ancient tradition in the North. Some of the seaweed Steve had gathered looked good enough to eat, and indeed, it can be used for culinary purposes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF7975.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Steve in his tractor with his Gaelic-speaking dog. Fuji X-T2&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next day, we tried out a new camping stove on Achmelvich beach, pushing the culinary boundaries by heating up a tin of sausages and beans. Classy. On our meander around the Coigach and Drumbeg, I tried a bit of sketching. Some way to go, I think.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/IMG_9378.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Achnahaird beach, sketch&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The last few days were spent in Drumbeg House, or at least, in a self-contained house within the grounds of said House. This was a perfectly peaceful place to escape for a few days with its own cairn at the side of its own loch and a decent deer population to get us close to that Highland feeling.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF8099.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Young stag. Fuji X-T2&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We were treated to a close encounter with one of these stags, at the point we were ready to give up hope of seeing the wildlife without a telephoto lens, when one wandered through the bracken and paused on the grass between the house and the loch, to gaze at us, neither of us knowing whether to grab a camera or just experience the moment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Kodak-TMY-400-20210912_17513046.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keeper&#39;s shed. Hasselblad 503CW, Kodak TMY 400&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The old house has been renovated, we think under new ownership, perhaps to return to its former glory as an exclusive dining experience for those who do that kind of thing. Traces of a more private small estate are still seen in the grounds.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Kodak-TMY-400-20210912_19434344.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;1907. Hasselblad 503CW, Kodak TMY 400&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We went along the coast to explore the peninsula of Culkein and Stoer, where there are wild rocks and waves from the Northern Minch, and hidden caves.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Kodak-TMY-400-20210912_20371219.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;A cave at Stoer. Hasselblad 503CW, Kodak TMY 400&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kylesku is a wonderful place and we visited, travelling home past the Sàil Gharb and Sàil Ghórm corbetts. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Kodak-Portra-800-20211010_12151225.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sàil Gharb and Sàil Ghórm. Nikon FM, Kodak Portra 800&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The roads were pretty much deserted around here, even in the post-COVID mad summer of 2021 when all of England discovered Scotland.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Kodak-Portra-800-20211010_12192098.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Passing place. Nikon FM, Kodak Portra 800, f/11 1/250s&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Detailed exposure logs for this post are &lt;a href=&#34;/Exposures/2021/2021-07-22-coigach-assynt/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Image&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Camera&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Lens&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;ISO&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Format&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Aperture&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Shutter&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Comment&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Thistles&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Fuji X-T2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;XF35mm F2 R WR&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;ISO 800&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Digital&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/250s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Adjusted in Capture One.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Tractor&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Fuji X-T2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;XF90mm F2 R LM WR&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;ISO 800&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Digital&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/500s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Cropped &amp;amp; adjusted in Capture One.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Young stag&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Fuji X-T2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;XF100-400mmF4.5-5.6 R LM OIS WR&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;ISO 1600&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Digital&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/10&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/500s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Cropped &amp;amp; adjusted in Capture One.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Shed&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Hasselblad 503CW&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Zeiss 80mm f/2.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;400&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;120&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/8s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;1907&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Hasselblad 503CW&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Zeiss 80mm f/2.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;400&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;120&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/4s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Cropped&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Caves&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Hasselblad 503CW&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Zeiss 80mm f/2.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;400&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;120&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/8s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Sàil Gharb and Sàil Ghórm&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Nikon FM&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Nikon AI-s 28mm f/2.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;800&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;135&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/250s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Passing place&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Nikon FM&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Nikon AI-s 28mm f/2.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;800&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;135&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/250s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2021/2021-07-22-coigach-assynt/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 16:08:37 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_updated.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2021/2021-07-22-coigach-assynt/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2021/2021-07-22-coigach-assynt/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Ard Daraich Anniversary trip</title> <category>Agfa Isolette</category> <category>Fuji X-T2</category> <category>Hasselblad V</category> <category>Ricoh GRIII</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ard-daraich-anniversary-trip&#34;&gt;Ard Daraich Anniversary trip&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF8178.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sanna Bay, the small isles&lt;/strong&gt; Fuji X-T2 XF16mm ISO800 f/16 at 1/125s&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We took a trip to the Ardnamurchan peninsula for our anniversary and enjoyed the pleasures of that with some photography. The sun shone on the first day, and took a jigsaw puzzle day on the second, giving us time for proper rest and relaxation. We stayed at Ard Daraich, home of the artist &lt;a href=&#34;https://arddaraich.co.uk/anna-raven-artist/&#34;&gt;Anna Raven&lt;/a&gt; and her husband, film-maker &lt;a href=&#34;https://ardgour-selfcatering.co.uk/norrie-maclaren/&#34;&gt;Norrie MacLaren&lt;/a&gt;. The house and gardens are &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.countrylife.co.uk/gardens/country-gardens-and-gardening-tips/ard-daraich-was-the-holiday-home-of-constance-spry-155070&#34;&gt;well known&lt;/a&gt; as the former home of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Constance_Spry&#34;&gt;Constance Spry&lt;/a&gt;, famed as the creator of Coronation Chicken for the Queen. Our accommodation was the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ardgour-selfcatering.co.uk/accommodation/the-garden-studio/&#34;&gt;Garden Studio&lt;/a&gt;, former garage to the larger house and nestled between the house and Anna&#39;s studio which houses a substantial printing press which she uses to create some of her work. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On this trip I finished a roll of Portra 160 in a Hasselblad 503CW and Kodak 400 Tri-X in the amazing little Agfa Isolette. The exposures in those two rolls are included further below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/R0001106.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bridge over the river Gour, Ricoh GRiii&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The house sits on a lane that leads to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ardgourholidays.co.uk/ardgour-house-&#34;&gt;Ardgour House&lt;/a&gt;, an altogether grander holiday destination, beyond our means and expectations. The lane passes over the river Gour by way of this bridge, which lit up in the unexpected sunshine of our first day, throwing reflections and patterns from the cool waters.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF8155.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reflection 1, Fuji X-T2&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF8163.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reflection 2, Fuji X-T2&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF8164.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reflection 3, Fuji X-T2&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF8169.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reflection 4, Fuji X-T2&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the other direction, the lane ends at Loch Linnhe, which like all of Highland Scotland is alive with russets, rubies, rusty maroons, cardinals, carmines and ambers. The beach is striped with sea salad, echoing the leaves on the trees in heralding the fall of summer&#39;s gaudy sparkle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/R0001110.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Beach salad, Ricoh GR-III&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our too-short sojourn at Ard Daraich was surely a rehearsal for a return to Ardgour and the stunning Ardnamurchan peninsula. A restful reconnaissance, well-earned and thoroughly appreciated as other duties call us back to the routine rumpus of that which pays us. We will be mellow, perhaps, as we savour the memories of the recent weekend.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!-- These are some of the digital images captured on the trip, but I also carried film cameras (Hasselblad and Agfa) with me and will be posting more from those and the trip home through Glen Coe and Glen Etive soon. --&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;hasselblad-images&#34;&gt;Hasselblad images&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I feel I have to show you some comparatives, starting with this image. Compare it with the first image in this post.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Kodak-Portra-160-503CW-20220306_17083822.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Kodak-Portra-160-503CW-20220306_16530161.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Beach salad, Hasselblad 503CW&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This image is quite different from the russet reds of the digital capture I made at the same time: here, no adjustments were made after scanning other than a slight crop adjustment. I think it&#39;s just as strong in rendering the emotion of the moment. You can almost smell it. This is my favourite image from the roll and one I might print.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Kodak-Portra-160-503CW-20220306_17400952.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Frandy Tree, Glendevon, Hasselblad 503CW&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a famous tree to those who walk near Glendevon, as we did shortly after we got home. We know it as the Frandy Tree, named for the nearby fishery. It stands alone at the foot of Common Hill and strikes one of those poses that looks different at different times and seasons but also from different directions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can see some of the digital images captured on the trip are in the &lt;a href=&#34;/2021/10/18/ard-daraich&#34;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;, but I also carried my Agfa and will be posting images from that when I can.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Brand&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Type&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;ISO&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Format&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Exposures&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Camera&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Lens&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Kodak&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;T-Max BW Pan&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;400&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;120&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;12&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Agfa Isolette I&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Agfa Agnar 1:4.5/85&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Kodak&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Portra&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;160&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;120&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;12&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Hasselblad 503CW&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Zeiss 80mm F2.8 C&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Portra was sent to AG Labs 18 October 21 for C-41 processing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;hasselblad-portra-160-exposures&#34;&gt;Hasselblad Portra 160 Exposures&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;Frame&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Image&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Aperture&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Shutter&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Comment&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Frandy Tree&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/16&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/60s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;18 Sep 21&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/3.2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/500s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/16&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/500s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Sheep&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/10.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/60s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Sanna, Ardnamurchan Lighthouse&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/13&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/15s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;16 October&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The Small Isles&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/16&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/15s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Ard Daraich loch&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/18&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/8s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;17 Oct&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Kara’s composition of 7&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/6s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;9 (header image)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Beach salad&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/15s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Jetty stakes&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/8s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Glen Coe in mist&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/4s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Loch Tula 18 Oct&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;12&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;ditto&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;agfa-isolette-kodak-t-max-400-exposures&#34;&gt;Agfa Isolette Kodak T-Max 400 Exposures&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This film was stand developed in Rodinal R09 in August 2022.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!-- Waiting to be scanned --&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;Frame&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Image&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Aperture&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Shutter&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Comment&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Frandy Tree&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Glendevon 25 September 21&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Dunning Road from Common Hill climb&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/50&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Frandy Tree from CH summit&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/50&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Lower Glendevon Reservoir&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/16&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/50s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Lochans on Common Hill&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/4.5&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/200s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Wispy grass&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/4.5&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/200s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Small isles&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/22 1/50s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;16 Oct sanna&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;House on Sanna beach&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/16&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/50s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;9&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Phone box and coo&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/50s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Jetty posts&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/50s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;17 Oct Ard Daraich&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Twat, scrolled by&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;12&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Loch and jetty posts&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/16&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/50s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2021/2021-10-18-ard-daraich/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 16:08:37 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_updated.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2021/2021-10-18-ard-daraich/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2021/2021-10-18-ard-daraich/</guid> </item> <item> <title>A Summer Hebridean trip</title> <category>Fuji X-T2</category> <category>Ricoh GRIII</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-summer-hebridean-trip&#34;&gt;A Summer Hebridean trip&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9085.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cuillins&lt;/strong&gt;, X-T2, Nikon 85mm&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s been a long time since there has been time for photography: life, COVID, and other everyday challenges have conspired to distract us from our one-time major non-work activity. A trip to the Hebrides for a short summer break demanded at least some effort, so I took my &lt;a href=&#34;/_cameras/fuji-x-t2.md&#34;&gt;Fuji X-T2&lt;/a&gt; and three lenses; the &lt;a href=&#34;/_cameras/ricoh-gr-iii.md&#34;&gt;Ricoh GR-III&lt;/a&gt;; and one concession to analogue photography, the &lt;a href=&#34;/_cameras/afga-isolette.md&#34;&gt;Agfa Isolette&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;skye&#34;&gt;Skye&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We drove cross-country from the Forth to Skye Bridges, taking our time to shop a little at the House of Bruar (one &lt;em&gt;has to&lt;/em&gt;, surely) and dally at Sligachan bridge, an old favourite of ours with a newish statue to the mountaineers Prof. Norman Collie and John Mackenzie.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9090.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Statue of Collie and Mackenzie&lt;/strong&gt; at Glen Sligachan. X-T2 with a Nikon 85mm f/1.4 lens.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The 50-year-old Nikon lens holds up nicely on the Fuji. Wide-open at f/1.4 I find it very hard to get the focus exact -- the depth of field is very narrow -- but it is still a very nice lens for softening the background. It performs better on the Nikon it was designed for, being quite dark on the Fuji compared to the Fuji XF 90mm f/2.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9086.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glen Sligachan&lt;/strong&gt;, X-T2, Nikon 85mm f/1.4 lens at about f/4.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The header image of Collie and Mackenzie&#39;s Cuillins was also taken with the same camera and lens and shows off, in my view, the distinct colour profile of the Nikon glass. Make your own mind up whether you prefer the filmic shades of the Nikon over the technically superior and brilliant Fuji lenses.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/R0001279.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The iconic Portree harbour houses&lt;/strong&gt;, Ricoh GR III at f/11, cropped.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overnighting at a Hostel in Portree, we took the early ferry from Uig to Loch Maddy. I am always impressed with CalMac&#39;s well-oiled operation, especially compared to the sometimes stressful experience of air travel. The 90 minute crossing was smooth and only slightly disappointing for not spotting seals at Vaternish Point. We consoled ourselves with a bacon and egg banjo in the &#34;Mariners&#34; café.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;five-islands&#34;&gt;Five Islands&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9112.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first couple of days in our remote &#34;pod&#34; were quite overcast with an ever-present wind between 20 and 40 mph, as the rest of the UK was baking in a record-breaking heat wave. It was nice, actually, and gave us a chance to explore comfortably and get a feel for the local group of islands. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9100.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;East Beach, Berneray&lt;/strong&gt; Fuji X-T2, XF16mm f/1.4 lens at f/11, 1/250s, ISO 200.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The colours of the water and the machair were striking, different at every location and under the changing light. The sands are also rich with pattern and shade (below). The header image on this page was taken at Traigh Lar on North Uist which became one of our favourite places on our short trip. It was captured with the Fuji X-T2 and the XF16mm f/1.4 lens at f/16 to get the depth of field required to keep the grass in focus as well as the horizon. 1/1000s to freeze the waves, ISO 1000. There was a steep drop of about 20 m to the beach from this point.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9095.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;East Beach sands, Berneray&lt;/strong&gt; Fuji X-T2, XF16mm f/1.4 lens at f/8, 1/1250, ISO 200.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Back on East Beach, the sands are also rich with pattern and texture. The countryside is rich with signs that it is expensive to dispose of old machinery and vehicles. Some effort seems to be made to at least gather the wreckage together. At Baleshare, a small collection of refrigerated trailers was forming. This one has signs of another era, like you see when shops change hands and ancient signwriting appears for a while.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/R0001290.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dead trailer&lt;/strong&gt; Ricoh GR III, processed in Capture One.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These two at least look like they&#39;re trying to keep out of sight. The wheels stick out like shoes from under a curtain.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/R0001293.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hidden trailers&lt;/strong&gt; Ricoh GR III, a similar process in Capture One.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;to-eriskay-and-back&#34;&gt;To Eriskay and back&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We drove the length of the Outer Hebrides, at least without leaving the land. There are many causeways now connecting the various island communities and making commerce and life in general much easier for the people who live and work here. We visited five islands: North and South Uist, Berneray, Benbecula and Eriskay. We&#39;re not counting Baleshare, although it connects to North Uist by another causeway. Most of the time one side of the causeway is all sand, and when it&#39;s not, you could probably still wade across. We didn&#39;t test that theory.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9117.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Howmore Bothy&lt;/strong&gt; (Fuji, Nikon 85mm lens)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Everywhere there are what seems like abandoned or derelict buildings. This example I photographed with both the Fuji (above) and the Ricoh (below) to create a different mood. I&#39;m not sure how successful it is: the wider angle of the Ricoh allows more context to create a story with.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/R0001294.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Howmore Bothy&lt;/strong&gt; (Ricoh, 18mm lens)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What really captured my heart during our leisurely and unstructured schlep around these islands was the sheer loveliness of the flowers that are just everywhere, clearly loved and protected by the local people. The wildflower meadowland that edges the beaches and reaches inland is diverse and colourful. I took far too many photographs of these flowers but will not tire of them as they adorn my desktop and walls in the coming months. Here, from the beach at Eriskay, right by the Barra Ferry terminal, is Sea Rocket:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9127.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fuday Island from Prince Charles&#39; Beach, Eriskay&lt;/strong&gt; Sea Rocket, Fuji X-T2, Nikon 85mm lens.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Back &#34;home&#34; to the bothy and a walk after dinner on our own beach on the doorstep, entertained on the way by rabbits and various birds playing and raising families in the meadowland.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9140.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The beach at Baleshare&lt;/strong&gt;, Fuji X-T2, Nikon 85mm lens.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Along the way, we met many of the residents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;residents&#34;&gt;Residents&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9159.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Locals&lt;/strong&gt; Fuji X-T2, Nikon 85mm&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The islands have a thriving farming sector and there are sheep on every single-track road personally introducing themselves to foreign visitors. Birds are many and diverse: it is easy to see a host of sea birds in and around the machar and on the hillsides are Golden Eagles, Hen Harriers and short-eared owls hunting in the daytime.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!-- Local drivers are used to them and know how much care is required: visitors must err on the side of caution or display the appropriate yellow sticker in the back window to warn other road users. --&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9157.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Locals&lt;/strong&gt; Fuji X-T2, Nikon 85mm&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The diversity of the wildlife is noticeable for visitors like us from the central belt of Scotland. We seem to have a disproportionate seagull population and we can probably do with less of the fat pigeons and magpies, frankly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9149.jpg&#34; /&gt;Where once working families lived, now stand more mechanised, efficient farming practices that make use of the land by fewer humans. A still nascent tourism industry is booked to capacity and locals still wave as visitors yield the right of way in the passing places. There is potential for development of abandoned plots and buildings across the islands. I hope that never comes to spoil the place.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/R0001301.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The roadside food wagon&lt;/strong&gt; is no innovation nor is it a quaint enterprise: the food is home-made, delicious and locally sourced. You have to try the scallops and black pudding roll. Radio buzzers notify in your car when your lunch is ready and yes, they take contactless American Express. Check out the recycling bins. Even the coffee-cup lids are made of paper pulp. The Outer Hebrideans are right on trend when it comes to sustainable service.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9180.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sea birds&lt;/strong&gt; abound along the shorelines and there are &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Sites_of_Special_Scientific_Interest_in_Western_Isles_South&#34;&gt;sites of special scientific interest&lt;/a&gt; intended to protect the diverse species, not least those that depend on the environment to breed and thrive. There are as many halfwits who will open gates to drive their SUVs across these spaces to access their picnics, of course but we think we saw at least one person openly challenge such behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9166.jpg&#34; /&gt;Most precious and beautiful of the environmental backdrop here is the machair. It is looked after and protected, as far as one can protect from human activity. Here may be common buttercups and clover but if you look, you can see many kinds of orchid.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;au-revoir&#34;&gt;Au Revoir&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9206_Panorama.jpg&#34; /&gt;This image will give you a sense of what we had hoped for when we headed North on our holiday. That image is actually a stitch of 8 images taken with the X-T2 and 35mm f/2 lens. Each image was exposed at f/8, 1/125s at ISO 200 and assembled into a panorama in Capture One. It should make a nice print about 50 inches x 20 inches if I ever get around to that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our sixth island of the trip was Skye, of course, our gateway to the Outer Hebrides. The hills and skies of Skye are something to behold: a mere photograph, least of all a digital image on a computer screen, can&#39;t give you anything like the sense of &lt;em&gt;being there&lt;/em&gt;. I tried with images like this pano, taken from the side of the road on the way from Carbost, not far from Sligachan where this series of posts began.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9283_Panorama.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Broadford Co-Op was full of surprises. The cheapest diesel I&#39;ve bought for weeks, and the right range of snacks for the rest of the journey home. Oh, and this view from the car park:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9289_Panorama.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What we got from our trip was much better than we had hoped for, of course. We had the chance to explore and learn, visit and revisit under changing skies and light. We left with just the tip of a toe dipped in Hebridean life. In the end, I only took one photo with the Agfa. I forget what it was but no doubt it will pop out in a few months.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-07-12-hebridean-trip/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 16:08:37 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_updated.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-07-12-hebridean-trip/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-07-12-hebridean-trip/</guid> <enclosure url="https://niximagery.com//img/DSF9206_Panorama.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="None" /> </item> <item> <title>East Neuk Day Trip</title> <category>Fuji X-T2</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;east-neuk-day-trip&#34;&gt;East Neuk Day Trip&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;We took a holiday hurl up the coast, just to take some air and not do the things that seem to have eaten the summer. We were lucky enough to get to the Hebrides, of course, but have managed to do other things too. Today was about switching off for a wee road trip along the fabulous Fife coast.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;st-monans-church&#34;&gt;St Monans Church&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;St Monans Church&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9295Panorama.jpg&#34; /&gt;I am particularly pleased with this 87 megapixel image of the church that is connected so intimately with my wife&#39;s family and her heritage. She has family in the church yard here and the iconic church deserves a decent place in our gallery. I hope to print this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-fife-machair&#34;&gt;The Fife Machair&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;The Fife Machair&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9355.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Fife Machair&lt;/strong&gt; is out in full bloom, with flowers of all colours basking in the sunshine. There seem to be fewer poppies than usual, for some reason, but we found a few near Kilconquhar.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;All of the images in this post, except the St Monan&#39;s beach steps below, were taken with my lightweight kit of the Fuji X-T2 and the amazing XF 35mm f2 lens. I&#39;ve been making more large images recently, when using the digital kit, by stitching several images together, not unlike the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brenizer_Method&#34;&gt;Brenizer method&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;St. Monans beach steps&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9337Panorama.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;St. Monans beach steps&lt;/strong&gt; For this image, taken as we returned from a walk along the path above the beach at St Monans, I used my old Nikon 85mm lens, stitching two images for a nice large square printable photo.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;poppies&#34;&gt;Poppies&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Poppies&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9420.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Poppies&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9414.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Poppies&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9413.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Poppies&lt;/strong&gt; are the flowers of remembrance and I can&#39;t spend time with poppies without feeling the emotions they invoke and what they signify. That culture is fading, I think, even as we are today, in time of war. People in some of my circles seem to be offended by remembrance and what used to be the importance of it. So long as I am able, I will not forget. So long as there are poppies, we will all be reminded, even if we choose to forget.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ice-cream-at-pittenweem&#34;&gt;Ice cream at Pittenweem&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Pittenweem Harbour&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9397Panorama.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pittenweem Harbour&lt;/strong&gt;, X-T2, XF35mm. We stopped for an ice-cream on the way home, and enjoyed a cone in the famous fishing town of Pittenweem. This is 3 images, edited a little (as they all are) in Capture One.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-08-07-east-neuk/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 16:08:37 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_updated.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-08-07-east-neuk/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-08-07-east-neuk/</guid> <enclosure url="https://niximagery.com//img/DSF9397Panorama.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="None" /> </item> <item> <title>An afternoon at Stronachie and Loch Leven</title> <category>Fuji X-T2</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;an-afternoon-at-stronachie-and-loch-leven&#34;&gt;An afternoon at Stronachie and Loch Leven&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Saturday afternoon, for no good reason and many, we jumped in the car with some snacks and went hunting for fresh air and ice cream. We went for a stroll down at Loch Leven. Walking out on the jetty, we saw the light was perfect and a heron was posing nicely along the shore. Of course, by the time we walked back to the car for our cameras, he was gone. The ice cream was easy, Giacopazzi&#39;s in Kinross providing a very nice solution. Cookies and Cream for him, Peach Melba for her. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9458_Panorama.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loch Leven&lt;/strong&gt; Fuji X-T2, 35mm f/2. Stitch of four images.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Onwards to a partly aimless drive to explore some favourite roads: through Milnathort, out by Tillyrie and Athron Hill where we had a look at a housing development seriously out of our range. Who needs a house that big anyway?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9479.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stronachie Forest&lt;/strong&gt; X-T2, Nikon 85mm f/1.4&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On an easy walk at Stronachie, all of our senses were exercised. The air was rich in oxygen from the forest, perfumed with heather; the air crackled as the broom seed pods burst open in the warm late summer sun.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9561.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Broom seed pods&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I changed the lens on the Fuji for the Stronachie walk, having started with the compact and versatile Fuji 35mm f/2, for my Nikon 85mm f/1.4. This is a difficult lens to focus wide open but it makes quite creamy bokeh washes from the background colours, even in low light. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9508.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plenty of room in the forest&lt;/strong&gt; f/1.4 at 1600 ISO&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Nikon lens is well known for its flare, too. This rainbow effect from shooting into the light is caused by internal flare in the lens.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9495.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rainbow flare&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Fuji X equivalent lens, the 90mm f/2, doesn&#39;t have the same flare or bokeh as the much older Nikon. It&#39;s not reasonable to compare them, perhaps, because of their age difference. Both are designed as portrait lenses.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9512.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stronachie Forest&lt;/strong&gt; X-T2, Nikon 85mm f/1.4&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;How fortunate we are to live within reach of such wonders of nature.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-08-27-stronachie/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 16:08:37 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_updated.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-08-27-stronachie/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-08-27-stronachie/</guid> <enclosure url="https://niximagery.com//img/DSF9458_Panorama.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="None" /> </item> <item> <title>Lower Largo</title> <category>Fuji X-T2</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;lower-largo&#34;&gt;Lower Largo&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the day of the King&#39;s proclamation, and in need of some sea air, we took a run up the coast to Lower Largo. It&#39;s been a challenging week for us in one way and another, not least for the depth of emotion we felt at the death of the Queen. There have been other losses, of course, but this one seems to have brought home Joni Mitchell&#39;s statement of the obvious: &lt;em&gt;you don&#39;t know what you&#39;ve got &#39;til it&#39;s gone&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9639Panorama.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We walked along the upper path, it being near high tide, to a favourite spot on the beach beside what looks like a rockery arrangement for a garden. The waters swirled around the rocks and the sun passed slowly, ever lower in the sky as autumn progresses, reminding us again of the relentless march of time. Not yet ready to forget the dog days of summer, the sun shone warmly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9628Panorama.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We sat for a while, the tide shifting the shapes and scenery with sand and seaweed. Sea kayaks passed out in the Forth, with the dead offshore platform Sedco 711 breaking up the horizon. Sunlight sparkled and shimmered on the water as time, &lt;em&gt;ralenti&lt;/em&gt;, became all but suspended in the reverie.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9626.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s nothing like a beach, and no better beach than a Scottish beach, to purge stress and anxiety, those corrosive curses of the contemporary condition. After the passage of some indeterminate time, things are just better than they were; big things smaller; a feeling of coming home settles.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9641.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As we walked along the path, the soothing splash of the waves on the shore below provided headspace in which to process and park our reflections on the week&#39;s events and resolutions were quietly packed in their pockets, ready for when we will need them. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9652.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teasels&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’ve learned that home isn’t a place, it’s a feeling. — &lt;em&gt;Cecelia Ahern in&lt;/em&gt; Love, Rosie&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-09-10-lower-largo/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 16:08:37 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_updated.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-09-10-lower-largo/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-09-10-lower-largo/</guid> <enclosure url="https://niximagery.com//img/DSF9654.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="None" /> </item> <item> <title>The Glen</title> <category>Fuji X-T2</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-glen&#34;&gt;The Glen&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;admonition quote&#34;&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;admonition-title&#34;&gt;Diane Arbus&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A photograph is a secret about a secret. The more it tells you the less you know.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaking of Kings, we went for a walk in Pittencrieff Park (known locally as &#34;The Glen&#34;). We were hunting for autumn leaves for an artsy project, specifically Oak. A walk in a park is never a bad idea in my book, and it gave me a chance to re-introduce myself to the big Fuji XF100-400mm zoom lens that I got back from service and repair this week.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9730.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dunfermline Abbey&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;King Charles III recently formally conferred city status on Dunfermline, during his first joint royal visit with the Queen Consort since the death of Queen Elizabeth. The townsfolk &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2022/oct/03/king-charles-confers-city-status-on-dunfermline-scotland&#34;&gt;turned out for the occasion&lt;/a&gt;, which is nice, even if some were apparently a little unkind to our First Minister. I couldn&#39;t possibly comment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9732.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Abbey and Abbey Church&lt;/strong&gt; were basking in the early autumn glow. I love how the light played around the buttresses of this old place, which has &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.undiscoveredscotland.co.uk/dunfermline/abbeypalace/index.html&#34;&gt;quite a history&lt;/a&gt;. Walking down into the Glen, the colurs in the Japanese Garden were no less magical.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9739.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Japanese Acer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The contrast was strong as we explored some of the nooks and crannies. Sunlight danced on water and dappled through the leaves, reflecting and re-reflecting greens and reds, oranges and yellows between dark and mysterious Tolkienesque shadows.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9742.jpg&#34; /&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Waterfall&lt;/strong&gt; on Tower Burn.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;audio controls=&#34;controls&#34;&gt; &lt;source type=&#34;audio/mp3&#34; src=&#34;/audio/Pittencrieff%20Park.mp3&#34;&gt; &lt;source type=&#34;audio/ogg&#34; src=&#34;/audio/Pittencrieff%20Park.ogg&#34;&gt;&lt;/audio&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9763.jpg&#34; /&gt;What the Americans call &lt;strong&gt;a Sqrl&lt;/strong&gt;. There are plenty of these in and around Dunfermline (squirrels, although there are a fair number of Americans, even at this time of year). They have a sense of humour, of course, and will run right across the feet of anyone with a camera just to watch them fumble for focus and fail.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9819.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alliums&lt;/strong&gt; in the formal garden. We walked here after pausing for a breakfast roll at the Peacock Room, and chatting to an old friend I hadn&#39;t seen for 20 years. That was a pleasant surprise and oddly, enabled me to fill in a couple of gaps from a particular period in my life. Nothing major, more an ironing out of wrinkles in a shirt I haven&#39;t worn for a while, but a resolution nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9861.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This iconic peacock&lt;/strong&gt; is one of a number in the park. There is a new enclosure following the recent mindless attack that resulted in the injury of one bird and the death of another, Malcolm, named for the King whose wife Margaret established the Abbey. More help is needed to support the volunteers who put heart and soul into caring for these beautiful creatures. If you can help, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.paypal.com/paypalme/pittencrieffpark?country.x=GB&amp;amp;locale.x=en_GB&#34;&gt;please drop them a few quid&lt;/a&gt;. Thank you, and thanks for reading.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;camera-gear&#34;&gt;Camera gear&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;All of the pictures on this page were made with the Fuji XF100-400mm F4.5-5.6 R LM OIS WR lens and my brilliant digital Fuji X-T2 camera. They were tastefully post-processed in Capture One Pro.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-10-08-the-glen/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 16:08:37 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_updated.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-10-08-the-glen/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-10-08-the-glen/</guid> <enclosure url="https://niximagery.com//img/DSF9730.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="None" /> </item> <item> <title>Dysart</title> <category>Fuji X-T2</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;dysart&#34;&gt;Dysart&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;admonition quote&#34;&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;admonition-title&#34;&gt;Robert Bresson&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Make visible, what without you, might perhaps never have been seen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;After lunch, we had an errand to run in the Lang Toun which gave us an excuse to take another walk, this time around the harbour at Dysart. There is a huge wall there which is home to various pigeons, and tells quite a story of how this place has changed over the years. Part of the cliff at the end of the harbour is no longer safe to walk along but it is easy to access the coastal walk through a short tunnel in the cliff at the end of the wall.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9879.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dysart Harbour Wall&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9878.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A shed&lt;/strong&gt; by the harbour was eclectically decorated with harboury stuff, and really set the feel of the place.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9882.jpg&#34; /&gt;We arrived at feeding time for the boats, and they seemed to think we had treats for them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9886.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The wall again&lt;/strong&gt;, because it is fascinating. The landscape of it seemed other-worldly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF9885.jpg&#34; /&gt;Plenty of things to look at in a harbour. There were people working, moving boats, furling sails and so on, and just as many sitting on benches. There were benches everywhere we looked today and I think I like that. Perhaps we are becoming more reflective.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;camera-gear&#34;&gt;Camera gear&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;All of the pictures on this page were made with the Fujifilm Fujinon XF16mm F1.4 R WR prime lens and the Fuji X-T2 camera. They were post-processed in Capture One Pro.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-10-08b-dysart/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 16:08:37 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_updated.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-10-08b-dysart/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-10-08b-dysart/</guid> <enclosure url="https://niximagery.com//img/DSF9879.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="None" /> </item> <item> <title>The Summer House</title> <category>Fuji X-T2</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-summer-house&#34;&gt;The Summer House&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF0360_Panorama.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Summer House towards the lake&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We took a weekend off for our anniversary, heading to a beautiful retreat in the Borders within the grounds of Chisholme House estate. We have not often chosen the Borders over our more usual favourite direction of North but wanted, as usual, a decent distance from hustle and bustle, nature and a wood-burning stove to curl up in front of at the end of the day. A place to read, reflect, walk and enjoy life together. Not far from Hawick, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.summerhousestays.co.uk/&#34;&gt;the Summer House&lt;/a&gt; offers all of that and more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF0022.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Summer House from the lake&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This place has been fairly recently renovated and is cosy, warm and spacious enough for families and small groups to enjoy the stunning countryside here. There is a lake close by with swans and moorhens. A young deer met us on the driveway as we headed on to the estate. Owls serenaded the night. An otter played chicken with us in the road and then blew otter raspberries from the safety of a hedge.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;chisholme-house&#34;&gt;Chisholme House&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF0373_Panorama.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chisholme House&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We did not go for (or know about) the retreats offered by the school at Chisholme but were intrigued and perhaps focused a little by the environment. From &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.chisholme.org/&#34;&gt;their website&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;admonition quote&#34;&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;admonition-title&#34;&gt;Dedicated to the art of self discovery&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chisholme offers an education for those who are convinced of our potential as human beings for goodness and positive effect on this earth, and who wish to be of service to it, to love and to learn.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-sense-of-sufism&#34;&gt;A sense of Sufism&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;There seems to be no particular religion behind the philosophy at Chisholme but the school considers writings of great scholars of Islam, in particular those in the Sufi tradition such as Rumi and Ibn&#39;Arabi. The Summer House includes artefacts of the three Abrahamic faiths of Islam, Christianity and Judaism. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF0417.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF0377.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Basmala&lt;/strong&gt; appears at threshholds to the old and new summerhouse. The older summer house is in the walled garden, which is well tended by the gardner and a team of volunteers who give service as a form of study and reflection. Quotes from Bulent Rauf and others suggest that central to the teachings of the Institute is unity of life and self discovery. On the hill above the house is the Monument to Man:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF0169_Panorama.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Monument to Man&lt;/strong&gt; above the estate has engraved around the circumference, &#34;ALL ARE FROM HIM AND TO HIM THEY RETURN&#34;, resonant with similar phrases in the Bible (e.g. Romans 11:36) and the Qu&#39;ran (e.g. Surah Al-Baqarah 2:156). In the ground near to the monument, with its four pillars representing Chisholme&#39;s own pillars of &lt;em&gt;work&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;study&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;meditation&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;zikr&lt;/em&gt;, is a circular stone bearing the inscription:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;O CONFIDENT SOUL, RETURN TO YOUR LORD, AGREEING AND AGREED TO ENTER AMONG MY SERVANTS AND ENTER MY PARADISE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a variation of another well known passage from the Qu&#39;ran, Surah 89, Al-Fajr (Dawn, verses 26 -- 30).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;time-travel-to-tushielaw&#34;&gt;Time Travel to Tushielaw&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We didn&#39;t stay in the house for the whole weekend, and ventured out on a trip to Tushielaw for Sunday lunch. Despite high expectations for nice country pub food, instead it became more of a journey in time back to the 1970s. You had to have been there, of course, to fully appreciate the standard of service and fag reek over the sausage, egg &#39;n&#39; chips with a choice of two sauces. And the footie on the telly. And the time it took for &lt;em&gt;mine host&lt;/em&gt; to work out by hand, calculator, pen and paper in hand, the bill. And the landlady&#39;s omnidirectional blather at anyone, or no-one, in the lounge. Such experience serves to remind us of how fortunate we are to be who we are.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;reflection&#34;&gt;Reflection&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF0070.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cygnet on the lake&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It takes little reflection on life to see this ugly duckling as the gracious beauty he is becoming. Our weekend at the summer house gave us time and space to discuss things that concern us and things that make us. We took time and space to see ourselves more clearly and shared life and laughter. We resolved to act, and to not act, on these things. Chisholme draws on Lao Tsu for some of its teaching, describing it:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The philosophy of Lao Tsu is simple: Accept what is in front of you without wanting the situation to be other than it is. Study the natural order of things and work with it rather than against it, for to try to change what is only sets up resistance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think this understates Lao Tsu&#39;s recognition of man&#39;s free will and ability to use it. On the way home, we took advice from the Hadith:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anas ibn Malik reported: A man said, “O Messenger of Allah, should I tie my camel and trust in Allah, or should I leave her untied and trust in Allah?” The Prophet, peace and blessings be upon him, said, “Tie her and trust in Allah.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Source: Sunan al-Tirmidhī 2517&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes-on-camera-equipment&#34;&gt;Notes on camera equipment&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;All of the pictures on this page were made with a Fuji X-T2 camera, and either the Fujifilm Fujinon XF16mmF1.4 R WR wide-angle lens, the 100-400 or my old Nikon 85mm Ai-S f/1.4. They were post-processed in Capture One Pro. There are other pictures yet come, taken on Lomo Babylon ISO 13 black &amp;amp; white film with Nikon FM SLR.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-10-16-summer-house/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 16:08:37 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_updated.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-10-16-summer-house/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-10-16-summer-house/</guid> <enclosure url="https://niximagery.com//img/DSF0022.jpg" type="image/jpeg" length="None" /> </item> <item> <title>Dunkeld Christmas preparation</title> <category>Fuji X-T2</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;dunkeld-christmas-preparation&#34;&gt;Dunkeld Christmas preparation&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Earlier in the year, we booked a dinner-bed-and-breakfast deal for Christmas Eve&#39;s eve, as much for corporeal as spiritual health. Before he knew what was happening, the cat was dropped at his aunties&#39; place and we were in our favourite winter woodland. The intention was to unwind on the approach to Christmas Day; to hit pause on the processes of work, study, shopping and the rest. It worked a charm. We didn&#39;t book the suite we had when we were married at the Dunkeld House Hotel but our room was enough for the purpose. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF0685_Panorama.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Hermitage&lt;/em&gt; Fuji X-T2, Nikon 85mm f/1.4 lens. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There was plenty of time to enjoy a slow wander around the Hermitage before check-in. We took cameras, but not the usual paraphernalia of tripods and filters. Very soon, the life-giving oxygen of the trees respiring reached our lungs and Mother Nature &lt;em&gt;cwtched&lt;/em&gt; us both. That feeling never gets old and before long we were on speaking terms with the residents again. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;admonition info inline&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF0657.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;admonition info inline end&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF0642.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Notices seem to have discouraged the previously trending habit of visitors forcing coins into any tree stump. Like most popular excesses, it&#39;s neither healthy nor tasteful, like those repetitive memes you see. I&#39;m glad the coin habit seems to be on the wane, even if the endless banality of social media is anything but. Oh, look, there&#39;s yet another New Year&#39;s resolution. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The soundscape on a walk around the Hermitage trail is varied, especially in the winter when the River Braan is swollen with meltwater from the recent snow. I didn&#39;t record it: it&#39;s white noise in a browser. Perhaps the picture will help you hear the rushing of the whitewater over rocks on the fall by Ossian&#39;s Hall.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF0696.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;admonition info inline end&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF0695.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the other side of the A9, the Tay wanders beside the hotel, altogether a more dignified spectacle than the its manic neighbour, the Braan. Alongside that river is the &#34;dookit&#34; or stone structure where we were married in the gentle Pertshire rainfall, with poetry and music and prayer. We walked down to remind ourselves and renew the feelings of that day. It was beautiful, of course. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, now, I write this on the &#34;other side&#34; of the Christmas celebrations we were preparing ourselves for; the joys and excesses, catechisms and exchanges of gifts, avoided topics, revelations and ghosts of those departed. That one night away, to worship in the cathedral of nature, to enjoy someone else cooking, to be ourselves for ourselves, was not only the perfect preparation for the bacchanalian feast, but also a &lt;em&gt;shahada&lt;/em&gt; for the year ahead.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/DSF0690_Panorama.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nature&#39;s Cathedral&lt;/em&gt; Fuji X-T2, Nikon 85mm f/1.4 lens. &lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-12-24-dunkeld/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 16:08:37 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_updated.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-12-24-dunkeld/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-12-24-dunkeld/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Kinghorn Beach</title> <category>Agfa Isolette</category> <category>Fuji GW690ii</category> <category>Ilford PanF Plus</category> <category>Kodak Kodacolor</category> <category>Ricoh GRIII</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;kinghorn-beach&#34;&gt;Kinghorn Beach&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Saturday 14th March, 2020. With the COVID-19 pandemic evolving around us, a spot of sea air was in order, so we drove along the coast to Kinghorn.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/R0000538.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Riding the storm&lt;/em&gt; Ricoh GRIII&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;new-friends&#34;&gt;New friends&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had film to finish off in the Texas Leica, my Nikon FM&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:exp&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:exp&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and my newest and cheapest (so far) camera, an Agfa Isolette I which arrived with half a roll of (I think) unexposed Kodacolor II still in it. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.photomemorabilia.co.uk/Colour_Darkroom/Early_Kodak_CameraFilm.html#anchorK11&#34;&gt;This post&lt;/a&gt; tells me that this film was rated at 100 ASA and went out of production in 1983. I don&#39;t expect very much from the three or four images I made with it, but it was fun trying out this old toy. The lens seems a little grubby but otherwise the camera seems to be clean and in good order for its age, and worth the £18 punted on it on eBay. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/Isolette.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Isolette&lt;/em&gt; by iPhone&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;/Stories/2020/2020-03-21-1983-kodacolorII/&#34;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt; for how the images from this film turned out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;beach-life&#34;&gt;Beach life&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The sky over Edinburgh across the Forth was pretty dramatic, so we were excited to see a group of parasurfers setting up and enjoying the elements. There was a stiff breeze as the tide was coming in, so the waves were expressive and obviously not a small challenge for the boys and girls braving the wind chill. We had our own challenge with the rapidly incoming tide.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/20-3-20-Pro50-8.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Parasurfers&lt;/em&gt; Fuji GW690ii Ilford Pan F Plus 50 f/11 at 1/60s. Brightened and split toned in Capture One.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:exp&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Exposure logs &lt;a href=&#34;/Exposures/2020/2020-03-10-Ilford-Pan/&#34;&gt;here (Pan F)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;/Exposures/2020/2020-03-14-Ilford-Delta-400/&#34;&gt;here (Delta)&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:exp&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 1 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-03-14-kinghorn-beach/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 20:21:08 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_updated.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-03-14-kinghorn-beach/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-03-14-kinghorn-beach/</guid> </item> <item> <title>1983 Kodacolor II film</title> <category>Agfa Isolette</category> <category>Kodak Kodacolor</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;1983-kodacolor-ii-film&#34;&gt;1983 Kodacolor II film&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;How I got on with an old film found in a cheap camera.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;admonition quote&#34;&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;admonition-title&#34;&gt;Robert Bresson&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Make visible, what without you, might perhaps never have been seen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/20-3-20-KodacolorII-1a.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kinghorn, 2020&lt;/em&gt; f/22 at 1/200s &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;a href=&#34;/Stories/2020/2020-03-14-kinghorn-beach/&#34;&gt;recent post&lt;/a&gt;, I mentioned that I had bought a new-to-me Agfa Isolette I camera. In it, I discovered as I opened the back, was an old roll of Kodacolor II. I closed the back and rolled it on to the next frame. A couple of days later, when my wife and I went to the beach for some relief from the emerging COVID-19 situation, I took the camera along.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;exposure-heuristics&#34;&gt;Exposure heuristics&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the beach, having not really thought about it properly, I decided to finish the film off. The Isolette doesn&#39;t have a meter, and I&#39;d forgotten my Gossen, so I figured I&#39;d give the &#34;Sunny 16&#34; rule a try. This goes something like: &#34;if it&#39;s sunny, and you&#39;re shooting at f/16, then the shutter speed is the inverse of the film speed.&#34; I later discovered that this fim had a speed rating of 100 ASA, but at the time I guessed that it might be a 400, so went for a shutter speed of 1/200th of a second at f/22. This blunder might have been mitigated against by the well-known heuristic or rule-of-thumb for expired films stock, which suggests that you should treat the film as being slower by 1 stop for every decade it is out of date. So, I should have rated the original 100 ASA film at 25. If all of those estimates and rules were correct, I was effectively underexposing on the beach by about 4 stops. They weren&#39;t.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;results&#34;&gt;Results&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The film was turned round by the brilliant &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ag-photolab.co.uk/&#34;&gt;AG Photolab&lt;/a&gt; in double-quick time, and I got to the scanner to have a look at these images. I wasn&#39;t expecting stellar quality images and wasn&#39;t disappointed. I pulled the scans into Capture One to see if I could do anything but in the end, I just cropped and exported them. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-effect-of-age-on-film-emulsion&#34;&gt;The effect of age on film emulsion&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The recent exposures at Kinghorn show quite a lot of fogging and what looks to me like a fungal film over the whole frame. There is evidence of light leaking into the frame at the top and bottom. I can&#39;t explain this because the back of the camera hinges open - the central frames I inadvertently exposed when I opened the camera when I first unpacked it are as you&#39;d expect. The red fog at the edges appears across the whole film. This is one of the frames exposed last week:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/20-3-20-KodacolorII-10.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kinghorn beach&lt;/em&gt; Isolette I, f/22 at 1/200s. Recent exposure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;history-in-the-roll&#34;&gt;History in the roll&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The exposures from the beginning of the film were perhaps made when it was put into the back of the cupboard, or wherever, back in the 1980s when this little Isolette was last used before finding itself washed up on eBay. I have no idea where they were taken but the houses look familiar, as if in a garden city like Letchworth or Rosyth. The colours are endearing, unsurprisingly retro, perhaps.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/20-3-20-KodacolorII-1.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rose garden&lt;/em&gt;, one of the &#34;found&#34; exposures in the old film.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This was fun. I think I&#39;ll try to clean up the camera a bit and try another roll.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;exposure-notes&#34;&gt;Exposure notes&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Exposed on 14th March 2020, sent to AG for processing at £3.49 plus £1.17 pp.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Brand&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Type&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;ISO&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Format&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Exposures&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Camera&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Lens&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Kodak&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Kodacolor II&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;100&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;120&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;12&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Agfa Isolette I&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Agfa Agnar 1:4.5/85&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;Frame&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Image&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Aperture&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Shutter&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;1-8.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Garden images, possibly from around 1983 ?&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;unknown&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;unknown&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;9.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;I opened the back, dammit&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;10-12.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Kinghorn Beach 14th March&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;1/200s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-03-21-1983-kodacolorII/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 20:21:08 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_updated.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-03-21-1983-kodacolorII/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-03-21-1983-kodacolorII/</guid> </item> <item> <title>First experiences with Ilford Delta 400 35mm film.</title> <category>Ilford Delta</category> <category>Nikon FM</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;first-experiences-with-ilford-delta-400-35mm-film&#34;&gt;First experiences with Ilford Delta 400 35mm film.&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/20-3-22-Delta-400-5.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Earlsferry, Fife.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ilford Delta is a well-known black and white film from the famous UK manufacturer that has been around for almost 30 years. I put a roll of 400 through a Nikon FM. This post describes some of the images I made and what I did with them. The film was exposed over the first few weeks of 2020 and sent to AG Photographic in Birmingham for developing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;harlow-water&#34;&gt;Harlow Water&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We had to take a trip to Essex in January and had time to take a walk along the River Stort that runs through a generic-looking town on the outskirts of London. The river seems clean enough to sustain life, as there were people fishing along the banks. The first image here is a crop: bottom right you can see fading from what looks like a light leak in the camera. I think it&#39;s something to do with the back plate. I bought this camera from eBay to replace my original 1970s Nikon FM that has a condemned shutter, and the back doesn&#39;t shut cleanly with the satisfying click of my original.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/20-3-22-Delta-400-18.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Harlow Water&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not sure I&#39;d be eating any of the fish they caught, as there were dog walkers kicking their poochy-poo directly from where it was dropped on the tow path into the river. I asked one of the fishermen if this is normal behaviour round here. He said everybody did it. I was disappointed with that level of cultural disrespect amongst the dog-walking people of this town towards their environment. Despite being in the middle of an industrial estate, this little stretch of river, with its abandoned house-boats, is pretty, and no doubt home to a lot of life. It&#39;s worth exploring - there&#39;s more information &lt;a href=&#34;https://canalrivertrust.org.uk/places-to-visit/harlow&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/20-3-22-Delta-400-19.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Harlow Water&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next image has been adjusted for tone in Capture One for a more vintage look. This might offend some &#34;analogue&#34; purists but I&#39;m just playing here. There aren&#39;t any rules, and Capture One is a nice tool for messing about with images that might otherwise be considered uninteresting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/20-3-22-Delta-400-20.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Harlow Mill&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-fife-coast&#34;&gt;The Fife Coast&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I next picked up the camera, we were up the &lt;a href=&#34;/2020/03/08/the-east-neuk.html&#34;&gt;East Neuk&lt;/a&gt;. I continued the split toning exercise with the next two frames, toning the shadows blue and the highlights in the complementary yellow.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/20-3-22-Delta-400-22.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bass Rock&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here, the Forth River basks in sunrays from an approaching storm. The toning enhances, I think the menacing clouds and waters. For monochrome images, it might seem weird to re-introduce colour but I think as an artistic technique, it enhances these shore photos. It didn&#39;t work for me with the Harlow Water images.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/20-3-22-Delta-400-26.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Forth River&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;kinghorn-beach&#34;&gt;Kinghorn Beach&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The last of these photographs was taken a few days later, down on the beach at Kinghorn. It is untoned but suffers with the same light leak problem I talked about above. This image was taken in portrait orientation and cropped slightly to make use of the false flare. I think it looks OK.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/20-3-22-Delta-400-34.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kinghorn&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary-of-the-results&#34;&gt;Summary of the results&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reviews of this film suggest that it is very sharp, although I am sure that this is true only when in better hands. I am not convinced that I get the best results by sending it to AG Photographic, although I don&#39;t doubt they are the best of the labs out there. Perhaps this is just a manifestation of the Dunning-Kruger effect and I&#39;ll change my mind once I learn more about it. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I took a roll of photographs back in the 1970&#39;s and 1980&#39;s, I would consider it a success if I got one or two good frames from a roll of 135. I think I have half a dozen here that I&#39;m pleased with, despite the leaky light problem. A significant factor in this increased success rate must be the greater opportunity there is to work with the images post-processing. Even the scanning tool &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:SF8&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:SF8&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; allows me to straighten the horizon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;next-steps&#34;&gt;Next steps&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I will try this film again and process it myself to see if I get better results, but also maybe I ought to stop buying old cameras online and expecting them to perform optimally without at least letting someone who knows what they are doing check them over for me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/20-3-22-Delta-400-24.jpg&#34; /&gt;Frame 24 &lt;em&gt;Bass Rocks&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This film was in my Nikon FM between 10th January and 14th March 2020. It was processed by AG Photolab. I switched lens part way through this film to a new 28mm f/2.8 Nikon which is very much better than the E series lens I had been using. At the same time, I added a Tiffen Yellow filter which made sky contrast much better too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Brand&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Type&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;ISO&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Format&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Exposures&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Camera&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Lens&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Ilford&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Delta&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;400&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;35mm&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;36&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Nikon FM&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Frames 1 - 20 Nikon 50mm f/1.8 Series E&lt;br/&gt;Frames 20 - 36 Nikon AI-s 28mm f/2.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;Frame&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Image&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Aperture&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Shutter&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Comment&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;1.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Euston&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/2s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;10 Jan. Hand held&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;2.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Preston station&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/4s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;3.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Preston station&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/15s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;4.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Preston station&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/1.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;5.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Earlsferry&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/16&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;12th Jan.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;6.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Shore&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;7.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Waves&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/1000s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;8.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/15s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;9.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/250s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;10.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/16&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/60s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Hand held&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;11.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Sunset&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;12-13.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Birds&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/250s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;14.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/250s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;15-17.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Crashing waves&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/2.8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/1000s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;18.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Harlow water&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/60s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;18th Jan&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;19.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Harlow water&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/30s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;20.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Harlow mill lock 8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;River stort&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;21.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Culross sunset&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/5.6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;26 Feb 28mm lens yellow filter&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;22.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Bass rock thru wall&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;8 March 28mm lens yellow filter - The East Neuk&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;23.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;KM at work&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/60s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Hand held&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;24.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Bass rocks&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/16&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;25-6.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Shafts/Edinburgh&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/16&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/125s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;27.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Shafts&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/60&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;28-30.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;shafts and rainbow&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/60s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;31-36.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Kinghorn Beach&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;f/16&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/500s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;14th March&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:SF8&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;SilverFast 8, which is actually bloody awful software with a functionality and interface from the 1990&#39;s. This software came with the Epson V600 scanner I bought from Wex and was provided by Epson because their own software doesn&#39;t work at all with OSX.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:SF8&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 1 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-03-22-delta-400/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 20:21:08 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_updated.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-03-22-delta-400/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-03-22-delta-400/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Self Isoletting with Kodak T-Max 400</title> <category>Agfa Isolette</category> <category>Kodak T-Max</category> <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;self-isoletting-with-kodak-t-max-400&#34;&gt;Self Isoletting with Kodak T-Max 400&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;A beach walk for exercise, officer, with an old Agfa.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/2020-04-17-Kodak-TMY-9.jpg&#34; /&gt;Frame 8 &lt;strong&gt;Inside the Monk&#39;s cave&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the first roll of my own film I have put through this little Agfa Isolette (see what I did there?). My wife and I went out during the so-called lockdown for some messages and a little exercise, having heard on the news that it&#39;s OK to get in your car and take a short drive to somewhere local if it helps you remain socially distanced enough to fight the spread of COVID-19. We decided that a walk on a beach would be safer and more responsible than a walk in the local park.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;stupid-is-as-stupid-does&#34;&gt;Stupid is as stupid does&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m still not quite myself following a recent loss, but I make no excuses for myself: the first four exposures on this film in the camera were all carefully exposed without remembering to advance the film. I re-took the building (Charles Hill Battery) on frame 2 using the same settings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/2020-04-17-Kodak-TMY-2.jpg&#34; /&gt;Frame 2 &lt;strong&gt;Building&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I double-exposed again on frame 4, re-taking the shots in 5 and 6. Apparently, photography is good for mindfulness. One of the scans, of the Monk&#39;s Cave, where monks used to wait for the boat to take them to Inchcolm Island out in the Forth, I processed using the Nik Collection Silver Efex Pro 2 application to bring out the detail in the sky and foreground. I quite like it:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/2020-04-17-Kodak-TMY-6.jpg&#34; /&gt;Frame 6. &lt;strong&gt;The Monk&#39;s cave&lt;/strong&gt;, post processed in Silver Efex (Nik Collection)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;processing&#34;&gt;Processing&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I like this film, known as TMY, because it&#39;s reliably good and very tolerant of my handling. This roll I processed myself, using 50:1 Rodinal R09 for 18 minutes and Kodak Fixer/Hardener. I had the devil of a job getting the film on the Paterson Reel and got quite grumpy at myself. The development went OK once I&#39;d sorted out my fingers and thumbs. I scanned a selection of the frames on my Epson using their dreadful Silverfast 8 software and noticed that pretty much every one had a band across the top, presumably from a light leak in the camera somewhere. You can see it in the building image above, and faintly in the tree image:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/2020-04-17-Kodak-TMY-12.jpg&#34; /&gt;Frame 12. &lt;strong&gt;Dead tree&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I really don&#39;t think I am going to worry about it - this camera cost me less than twenty quid including postage so a professional CLA&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; is not economically viable. Quite probably the light seals along the bottom of the camera are just needing replaced, a job I might do in a future lock-down.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The scanned tiff files were converted in Capture One, with a bit of contrast adjustment and cropping in the header image.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary-of-the-results&#34;&gt;Summary of the results&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I notice that I didn&#39;t deviate from 1/200s shutter speed with this roll. It was quite bright and so perhaps 400 ISO wasn&#39;t right for the conditions, given that this camera&#39;s shutter doesn&#39;t go any faster than that. Even inside the Monk&#39;s cave (above), I was exposing for the surfaces lit directly from the outside.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;/img/2020-04-17-Kodak-TMY-5.jpg&#34; /&gt;Frame 5, &lt;strong&gt;Inchcolm Island&lt;/strong&gt;, cropped&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;All images on this page taken with an Agfa Isolette I fitted with the Agfa Agnar 1:4.5/85 lens. The film used was Kodak TMY, or T-Max 400 Black &amp;amp; White film, rated at EI 400. Cost £6.40 per roll from Analog Wonderland. Exposed on 4th April 2020, processed at home in Rodinal R09 one shot, works out at something like 75p per shot.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;exposure-settings&#34;&gt;Exposure settings&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;Frame&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Image&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Aperture&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Shutter&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;1.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Golf course &amp;amp; beach&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;f/16&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/200s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;1.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Terminal&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/200s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;1.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Boat&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/200s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;1.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Building&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/200s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;2.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Building&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/200s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;3.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Boat&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/200s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;4.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Inchcolm Island&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;f/32&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/200s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;4.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Monk&#39;s cave&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;f/32&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/200s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;5.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Inchcolm Island&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;f/32&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/200s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;6.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The Monk&#39;s cave&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;f/32&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/200s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;7.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Monk&#39;s cave&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;f/22&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/200s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;8.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Inside the Monk&#39;s cave&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;f/8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/200s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;9.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Monk&#39;s cave window&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;f/8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/200s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;10.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Inchcolm Island&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;f/16&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/200s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;11.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Beach&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;f/16&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/200s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;12.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Dead tree&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;f/11&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;1/200s&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Clean, lubricate and adjust.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 1 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-04-04-self-isoletting-with-Kodak-T-Max-400/?utm_source=documentation&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=feed-syndication</link> <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 20:21:08 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://niximagery.com/feed_rss_updated.xml">Niximagery</source><comments>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-04-04-self-isoletting-with-Kodak-T-Max-400/#__comments</comments><guid isPermaLink="true">https://niximagery.com/Stories/2020/2020-04-04-self-isoletting-with-Kodak-T-Max-400/</guid> </item> </channel></rss>