<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://niximagery.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://niximagery.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-07-15T22:02:57+01:00</updated><id>https://niximagery.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Niximagery | Stories and Images</title><subtitle>Stories about image making.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Hebridean trip part 4: Au Revoir</title><link href="https://niximagery.com/2022/07/15/hebridean-trip-4.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hebridean trip part 4: Au Revoir" /><published>2022-07-15T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-07-15T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://niximagery.com/2022/07/15/hebridean-trip-4</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://niximagery.com/2022/07/15/hebridean-trip-4.html"><![CDATA[<p>The header image will give you a sense of what we had hoped for when we headed North on our holiday. That image is actually a stitch of 8 images taken with the X-T2 and 35mm f/2 lens. Each image was exposed at f/8, 1/125s at ISO 200 and assembled into a panorama in Capture One. It should make a nice print about 50 inches x 20 inches if I ever get around to that.</p>

<p>Our sixth island of the trip was Skye, of course, our gateway to the Outer Hebrides. The hills and skies of Skye are something to behold: a mere photograph, least of all a digital image on a computer screen, can’t give you anything like the sense of <em>being there</em>. I tried with images like this pano, taken from the side of the road on the way from Carbost, not far from Sligachan where this series of posts began.</p>

<p><img src="/img/DSF9283_Panorama.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>The Broadford Co-Op was full of surprises. The cheapest diesel I’ve bought for weeks, and the right range of snacks for the rest of the journey home. Oh, and this view from the car park:</p>

<p><img src="/img/DSF9289_Panorama.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>What we got from our trip was much better than we had hoped for, of course. We had the chance to explore and learn, visit and revisit under changing skies and light. We left with just the tip of a toe dipped in Hebridean life. In the end, I only took one photo with the Agfa. I forget what it was but no doubt it will pop out in a few months.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Agfa" /><category term="Isolette I" /><category term="Fuji" /><category term="X-T2" /><category term="Ricoh GRIII" /><category term="Scotland" /><category term="Hebrides" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A Summer Trip, concluded]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://niximagery.com/DSF9206_Panorama.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://niximagery.com/DSF9206_Panorama.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Hebridean trip part 3: Residents</title><link href="https://niximagery.com/2022/07/15/hebridean-trip-3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hebridean trip part 3: Residents" /><published>2022-07-15T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-07-15T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://niximagery.com/2022/07/15/hebridean-trip-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://niximagery.com/2022/07/15/hebridean-trip-3.html"><![CDATA[<p>The islands have a thriving farming sector and there are sheep on every single-track road personally introducing themselves to foreign visitors. Birds are many and diverse: it is easy to see a host of sea birds in and around the machar and on the hillsides are Golden Eagles, Hen Harriers and short-eared owls hunting in the daytime.</p>

<!-- Local drivers are used to them and know how much care is required: visitors must err on the side of caution or display the appropriate yellow sticker in the back window to warn other road users. -->

<p><img src="/img/DSF9157.jpg" alt="" />
<strong>Locals</strong> Fuji X-T2, Nikon 85mm (and header image)</p>

<p>The diversity of the wildlife is noticeable for visitors like us from the central belt of Scotland. We seem to have a disproportionate seagull population and we can probably do with less of the fat pigeons and magpies, frankly.</p>

<p><img src="/img/DSF9149.jpg" alt="" />
Where once working families lived, now stand more mechanised, efficient farming practices that make use of the land by fewer humans. A still nascent tourism industry is booked to capacity and locals still wave as visitors yield the right of way in the passing places. There is potential for development of abandoned plots and buildings across the islands. I hope that never comes to spoil the place.</p>

<p><img src="/img/R0001301.jpg" alt="" />
<strong>The roadside food wagon</strong> is no innovation nor is it a quaint enterprise: the food is home-made, delicious and locally sourced. You have to try the scallops and black pudding roll. Radio buzzers notify in your car when your lunch is ready and yes, they take contactless American Express. Check out the recycling bins. Even the coffee-cup lids are made of paper pulp. The Outer Hebrideans are right on trend when it comes to sustainable service.</p>

<p><img src="/img/DSF9180.jpg" alt="" />
<strong>Sea birds</strong> abound along the shorelines and there are <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Sites_of_Special_Scientific_Interest_in_Western_Isles_South">sites of special scientific interest</a> intended to protect the diverse species, not least those that depend on the environment to breed and thrive. There are as many halfwits who will open gates to drive their SUVs across these spaces to access their picnics, of course but we think we saw at least one person openly challenge such behaviour.</p>

<p><img src="/img/DSF9166.jpg" alt="" />
Most precious and beautiful of the environmental backdrop here is the machair. It is looked after and protected, as far as one can protect from human activity. Here may be common buttercups and clover but if you look, you can see many kinds of orchid.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Fuji" /><category term="X-T2" /><category term="Ricoh GRIII" /><category term="Scotland" /><category term="Hebrides" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A Summer Trip, continued]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://niximagery.com/DSF9159.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://niximagery.com/DSF9159.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Hebridean trip part 2: Five Islands</title><link href="https://niximagery.com/2022/07/14/hebridean-trip-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hebridean trip part 2: Five Islands" /><published>2022-07-14T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-07-14T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://niximagery.com/2022/07/14/hebridean-trip-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://niximagery.com/2022/07/14/hebridean-trip-2.html"><![CDATA[<p>The first couple of days in our remote “pod” were quite overcast with an ever-present wind between 20 and 40 mph, as the rest of the UK was baking in a record-breaking heat wave. It was nice, actually, and gave us a chance to explore comfortably and get a feel for the local group of islands.</p>

<p><img src="/img/DSF9100.jpg" alt="" />
<strong>East Beach, Berneray</strong> Fuji X-T2, XF16mm f/1.4 lens at f/11, 1/250s, ISO 200.</p>

<p>The colours of the water and the machair were striking, different at every location and under the changing light. The sands are also rich with pattern and shade (below). The header image on this page was taken at Traigh Lar on North Uist which became one of our favourite places on our short trip. It was captured with the Fuji X-T2 and the XF16mm f/1.4 lens at f/16 to get the depth of field required to keep the grass in focus as well as the horizon. 1/1000s to freeze the waves, ISO 1000. There was a steep drop of about 20 m to the beach from this point.</p>

<p><img src="/img/DSF9095.jpg" alt="" />
<strong>East Beach sands, Berneray</strong> Fuji X-T2, XF16mm f/1.4 lens at f/8, 1/1250, ISO 200.</p>

<p>Back on East Beach, the sands are also rich with pattern and texture. The countryside is rich with signs that it is expensive to dispose of old machinery and vehicles. Some effort seems to be made to at least gather the wreckage together. At Baleshare, a small collection of refrigerated trailers was forming. This one has signs of another era, like you see when shops change hands and ancient signwriting appears for a while.</p>

<p><img src="/img/R0001290.jpg" alt="" />
<strong>Dead trailer</strong> Ricoh GR III, processed in Capture One.</p>

<p>These two at least look like they’re trying to keep out of sight. The wheels stick out like shoes from under a curtain.</p>

<p><img src="/img/R0001293.jpg" alt="" />
<strong>Hidden trailers</strong> Ricoh GR III, a similar process in Capture One.</p>

<h2 id="to-eriskay-and-back">To Eriskay and back</h2>

<p>We drove the length of the Outer Hebrides, at least without leaving the land. There are many causeways now connecting the various island communities and making commerce and life in general much easier for the people who live and work here. We visited five islands: North and South Uist, Berneray, Benbecula and Eriskay. We’re not counting Baleshare, although it connects to North Uist by another causeway. Most of the time one side of the causeway is all sand, and when it’s not, you could probably still wade across. We didn’t test that theory.</p>

<p><img src="/img/DSF9117.jpg" alt="" />
<strong>Howmore Bothy</strong> (Fuji, Nikon 85mm lens)</p>

<p>Everywhere there are what seems like abandoned or derelict buildings. This example I photographed with both the Fuji (above) and the Ricoh (below) to create a different mood. I’m not sure how successful it is: the wider angle of the Ricoh allows more context to create a story with.</p>

<p><img src="/img/R0001294.jpg" alt="" />
<strong>Howmore Bothy</strong> (Ricoh, 18mm lens)</p>

<p>What really captured my heart during our leisurely and unstructured schlep around these islands was the sheer loveliness of the flowers that are just everywhere, clearly loved and protected by the local people. The wildflower meadowland that edges the beaches and reaches inland is diverse and colourful. I took far too many photographs of these flowers but will not tire of them as they adorn my desktop and walls in the coming months. Here, from the beach at Eriskay, right by the Barra Ferry terminal, is Sea Rocket:</p>

<p><img src="/img/DSF9127.jpg" alt="" />
<strong>Fuday Island from Prince Charles’ Beach, Eriskay</strong> Sea Rocket, Fuji X-T2, Nikon 85mm lens.</p>

<p>Back “home” to the bothy and a walk after dinner on our own beach on the doorstep, entertained on the way by rabbits and various birds playing and raising families in the meadowland.</p>

<p><img src="/img/DSF9140.jpg" alt="" />
<strong>The beach at Baleshare</strong>, Fuji X-T2, Nikon 85mm lens.</p>

<p>Along the way, we met many of the residents.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Fuji" /><category term="X-T2" /><category term="Ricoh GRIII" /><category term="Scotland" /><category term="Hebrides" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A Summer Trip, continued]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://niximagery.com/DSF9112.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://niximagery.com/DSF9112.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Hebridean trip part 1: Skye</title><link href="https://niximagery.com/2022/07/12/hebridean-trip-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hebridean trip part 1: Skye" /><published>2022-07-12T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-07-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://niximagery.com/2022/07/12/hebridean-trip-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://niximagery.com/2022/07/12/hebridean-trip-1.html"><![CDATA[<p>It’s been a long time since there has been time for photography: life, COVID, and other everyday challenges have conspired to distract us from our one-time major non-work activity. A trip to the Hebrides for a short summer break demanded at least some effort, so I took my <a href="/_cameras/fuji-x-t2.md">Fuji X-T2</a> and three lenses; the <a href="/_cameras/ricoh-gr-iii.md">Ricoh GR-III</a>; and one concession to analogue photography, the <a href="/_cameras/afga-isolette.md">Agfa Isolette</a>.</p>

<p>We drove cross-country from the Forth to Skye Bridges, taking our time to shop a little at the House of Bruar (one <em>has to</em>, surely) and dally at Sligachan bridge, an old favourite of ours with a newish statue to the mountaineers Prof. Norman Collie and John Mackenzie.</p>

<p><img src="/img/DSF9090.jpg" alt="" />
<strong>Statue of Collie and Mackenzie</strong> at Glen Sligachan. X-T2 with a Nikon 85mm f/1.4 lens.</p>

<p>The 50-year-old Nikon lens holds up nicely on the Fuji. Wide-open at f/1.4 I find it very hard to get the focus exact – the depth of field is very narrow – but it is still a very nice lens for softening the background. It performs better on the Nikon it was designed for, being quite dark on the Fuji compared to the Fuji XF 90mm f/2.</p>

<p><img src="/img/DSF9086.jpg" alt="" />
<strong>Glen Sligachan</strong>, X-T2, Nikon 85mm f/1.4 lens at about f/4.</p>

<p>The header image of Collie and Mackenzie’s Cuillins was also taken with the same camera and lens and shows off, in my view, the distinct colour profile of the Nikon glass. Make your own mind up whether you prefer the filmic shades of the Nikon over the technically superior and brilliant Fuji lenses.</p>

<p><img src="/img/R0001279.jpg" alt="" />
<strong>The iconic Portree harbour houses</strong>, Ricoh GR III at f/11, cropped.</p>

<p>Overnighting at a Hostel in Portree, we took the early ferry from Uig to Loch Maddy. I am always impressed with CalMac’s well-oiled operation, especially compared to the sometimes stressful experience of air travel. The 90 minute crossing was smooth and only slightly disappointing for not spotting seals at Vaternish Point. We consoled ourselves with a bacon and egg banjo in the “Mariners” café.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Fuji" /><category term="X-T2" /><category term="Ricoh GRIII" /><category term="Scotland" /><category term="Hebrides" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A Summer Trip]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://niximagery.com/DSF9085.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://niximagery.com/DSF9085.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Ard Daraich</title><link href="https://niximagery.com/2022/03/06/ard-daraich.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ard Daraich" /><published>2022-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://niximagery.com/2022/03/06/ard-daraich</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://niximagery.com/2022/03/06/ard-daraich.html"><![CDATA[<p>Continuing on from the <a href="/2021/10/18/ard-daraich">last</a> post on our trip to the Ardnamurchan peninsula last October, I’ve finally had the Hasselblad film processed and scanned. I feel I have to show you some comparatives, starting with the header image above (compare it with that in the previous post).</p>

<p><img src="/img/Kodak-Portra-160-503CW-20220306_16530161.jpg" alt="" />
<em>Beach salad, Hasselblad 503CW</em></p>

<p>This image is quite different from the russet reds of the digital capture I made at the same time: here, no adjustments were made after scanning other than a slight crop adjustment. I think it’s just as strong in rendering the emotion of the moment. You can almost smell it. This is my favourite image from the roll and one I might print.</p>

<p><img src="/img/Kodak-Portra-160-503CW-20220306_17400952.jpg" alt="" />
<em>The Frandy Tree, Glendevon, Hasselblad 503CW</em></p>

<p>This is a famous tree to those who walk near Glendevon, as we did shortly after we got home. We know it as the Frandy Tree, named for the nearby fishery. It stands alone at the foot of Common Hill and strikes one of those poses that looks different at different times and seasons but also from different directions.</p>

<p>You can see some of the digital images captured on the trip are in the <a href="/2021/10/18/ard-daraich">previous post</a>, but I also carried my Agfa and will be posting images from that when I can.</p>

<h2 id="notes">Notes</h2>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: left">Image</th>
      <th style="text-align: left">Camera</th>
      <th style="text-align: left">Lens</th>
      <th style="text-align: left">ISO</th>
      <th style="text-align: left">Format</th>
      <th style="text-align: center">Aperture</th>
      <th style="text-align: center">Shutter</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left">Header (Sanna Bay, the small isles)</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Hasselblad 503CW</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Zeiss 80mm F2.8 C</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">160</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">120</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">f/16</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">1/15 sec</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left">Beach salad</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Hasselblad 503CW</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Zeiss 80mm F2.8 C</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">160</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">120</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">f/8</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">1/15 sec</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left">Frandy Tree</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Hasselblad 503CW</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Zeiss 80mm F2.8 C</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">160</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">120</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">f/16</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">1/60 sec</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Hasselblad" /><category term="503CW" /><category term="Kodak" /><category term="Portra 160" /><category term="Scotland" /><category term="Ard Daraich" /><category term="Ardnamurchan" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hasselblad images]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://niximagery.com/Kodak-Portra-160-503CW-20220306_17083822.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://niximagery.com/Kodak-Portra-160-503CW-20220306_17083822.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Ard Daraich</title><link href="https://niximagery.com/2021/10/18/ard-daraich.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ard Daraich" /><published>2021-10-18T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-10-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://niximagery.com/2021/10/18/ard-daraich</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://niximagery.com/2021/10/18/ard-daraich.html"><![CDATA[<p>We took a trip to the Ardnamurchan peninsula for our anniversary and enjoyed the pleasures of that with some photography. The sun shone on the first day, and took a jigsaw puzzle day on the second, giving us time for proper rest and relaxation. We stayed at Ard Daraich, home of the artist <a href="https://arddaraich.co.uk/anna-raven-artist/">Anna Raven</a> and her husband, film-maker <a href="https://ardgour-selfcatering.co.uk/norrie-maclaren/">Norrie MacLaren</a>. The house and gardens are <a href="https://www.countrylife.co.uk/gardens/country-gardens-and-gardening-tips/ard-daraich-was-the-holiday-home-of-constance-spry-155070">well known</a> as the former home of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Constance_Spry">Constance Spry</a>, famed as the creator of Coronation Chicken for the Queen. Our accommodation was the <a href="https://ardgour-selfcatering.co.uk/accommodation/the-garden-studio/">Garden Studio</a>, former garage to the larger house and nestled between the house and Anna’s studio which houses a substantial printing press which she uses to create some of her work.</p>

<p><img src="/img/R0001106.jpg" alt="" />
<em>Bridge over the river Gour, Ricoh GRiii</em></p>

<p>The house sits on a lane that leads to <a href="https://www.ardgourholidays.co.uk/ardgour-house-">Ardgour House</a>, an altogether grander holiday destination, beyond our means and expectations. The lane passes over the river Gour by way of this bridge, which lit up in the unexpected sunshine of our first day, throwing reflections and patterns from the cool waters.</p>

<p><img src="/img/DSF8155.jpg" alt="" />
<em>Reflection 1, Fuji X-T2</em></p>

<p><img src="/img/DSF8163.jpg" alt="" />
<em>Reflection 2, Fuji X-T2</em></p>

<p><img src="/img/DSF8164.jpg" alt="" />
<em>Reflection 3, Fuji X-T2</em></p>

<p><img src="/img/DSF8169.jpg" alt="" />
<em>Reflection 4, Fuji X-T2</em></p>

<p>In the other direction, the lane ends at Loch Linnhe, which like all of Highland Scotland is alive with russets, rubies, rusty maroons, cardinals, carmines and ambers. The beach is striped with sea salad, echoing the leaves on the trees in heralding the fall of summer’s gaudy sparkle.</p>

<p><img src="/img/R0001110.jpg" alt="" />
<em>Beach salad, Fuji X-T2</em></p>

<p>Our too-short sojourn at Ard Daraich was surely a rehearsal for a return to Ardgour and the stunning Ardnamurchan peninsula. A restful reconnaissance, well-earned and thoroughly appreciated as other duties call us back to the routine rumpus of that which pays us. We will be mellow, perhaps, as we savour the memories of the recent weekend.</p>

<h2 id="notes">Notes</h2>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: left">Image</th>
      <th style="text-align: left">Camera</th>
      <th style="text-align: left">Lens</th>
      <th style="text-align: left">ISO</th>
      <th style="text-align: left">Format</th>
      <th style="text-align: center">Aperture</th>
      <th style="text-align: center">Shutter</th>
      <th style="text-align: left">Comment</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left">Header (Sanna Bay, the small isles)</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Fuji X-T2</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">XF16mmF1.4 R WR</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">800</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Digital</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">f/16</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">1/125s</td>
      <td style="text-align: left"> </td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left">Reflections</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Fuji X-T2</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">XF100-400mmF4.5-5.6 R LM OIS WR</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">3200</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Digital</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">f/8</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">1/1000s</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">at 400mm</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left">Beach Salad</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Ricoh GR-III</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Ricoh 18.3mm</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">200</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Digital</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">f/5.6</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">1/50s</td>
      <td style="text-align: left"> </td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p>These are some of the digital images captured on the trip, but I also carried film cameras (Hasselblad and Agfa) with me and will be posting more from those and the trip home through Glen Coe and Glen Etive soon.</p>

<!--Header|Ricoh GR-III|Ricoh 18.3mm|ISO 6400|Digital|f/11|1/25s|Adjusted in Capture One.
Bark|Hasselblad 503CW|Zeiss 80mm F2.8 C|400|120|f/2.8|1/2 sec
Bark 2|Hasselblad 503CW|Zeiss 80mm F2.8 C|400|120|f/2.8|1/4 sec
Bark 3|Hasselblad 503CW|Zeiss 80mm F2.8 C|400|120|f/2.8|1/30 sec
Mushroom|Hasselblad 503CW|Zeiss 80mm F2.8 C|400|120|f/2.8|1/2 sec
Polney Loch|Hasselblad 503CW|Zeiss 80mm F2.8 C|400|120|f/22|1/3 s
House|Hasselblad 503CW|Zeiss 80mm F2.8 C|400|120|f/18|1 sec
Door|Hasselblad 503CW|Zeiss 80mm F2.8 C|400|120|f/10|1/8 s
-->]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Hasselblad" /><category term="Agfa" /><category term="Fuji" /><category term="X-T2" /><category term="Ricoh GRIII" /><category term="Scotland" /><category term="Ard Daraich" /><category term="Ardnamurchan" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Anniversary trip]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://niximagery.com/DSF8178.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://niximagery.com/DSF8178.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Polney Loch 9/11/21</title><link href="https://niximagery.com/2021/10/10/polney-loch.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Polney Loch 9/11/21" /><published>2021-10-10T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-10-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://niximagery.com/2021/10/10/polney-loch</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://niximagery.com/2021/10/10/polney-loch.html"><![CDATA[<p>We needed an escape from the madness and so jumped in the car and headed North to Tiso, the M&amp;S Foodstore and on to Dunkeld by way of the new road which is very nice, I have to say. The motive was almost a visceral need to be in the woods, and this time of year is when that experience is at its best as the colours are changing as fast as the air does: from the mouthfuls of balmy summer warmth to shorter bites of soupy vapour returned to the atmosphere as evanescent clouds. Mushroom time.</p>

<p><img src="/img/Kodak-Tri-X-400-20211010_15283019.jpg" alt="" />
<em>Fungus abounds. f/8 1/2s</em></p>

<p>I took a Hasselblad 503CW with a roll of Kodak Tri-X, and a Ricoh GRIII in my pocket for the more immediate gratification of having something to show on the day for our efforts. On this day, without explicitly talking about it, we remembered the events of 20 years ago with humility and gratitude, within one of Nature’s Cathedrals.</p>

<p><img src="/img/Kodak-Tri-X-400-20211010_14291790.jpg" alt="" />
<em>Bark on various trees. f/2.8 1/2s</em></p>

<p>In the peace and reflection of our walk, I noticed the bark patterns on the aged trees, like the scars of experience, each different from the others, each with their own stories to tell. These patterns became as faces of old men and women, taciturn yet expressive of triumph and loss, of lessons learned and not, of survival and the remembrance of those who did not.</p>

<p><img src="/img/Kodak-Tri-X-400-20211010_14325659.jpg" alt="" />
<em>Bark on various trees. f/2.8 1/4s</em></p>

<p>These were taken quite near the Cally car park where we began our stroll and I recall the steps, the birdsong and the additional aroma of the sawmill below the path, as I write this in October. A month from now is another great remembrance when I celebrate getting older, living vicariously for those who have been denied.</p>

<p><img src="/img/Kodak-Tri-X-400-20211010_14364914.jpg" alt="" />
<em>Bark on various trees. f/2.8 1/30s</em></p>

<p>The leaves on the birch trees on the far bank were turning a light golden yellow, which in this black and white image, is reminiscent of infra-red photographs I have taken. Not in this case; just gorgeous tones against the evergreen backdrop.</p>

<p><img src="/img/Kodak-Tri-X-400-20211010_15193092.jpg" alt="" />
<em>Polney Loch</em></p>

<p>At the end of the loch stands this wooden lodge – a fisherman’s howff, perhaps – that looks like it is from another age. It isn’t that old by the looks of it but we might easily be convinced that we stepped through a portal back there.</p>

<p><img src="/img/Kodak-Tri-X-400-20211010_15072703.jpg" alt="" />
<em>House at the end of the Loch</em></p>

<p>A detail of a hatch or door to the lodge reveals some old-time traditional craftsmanship, like you’d find on any great country estate. And ferns.</p>

<p><img src="/img/Kodak-Tri-X-400-20211010_15024288.jpg" alt="" />
<em>Door detail</em></p>

<p>I developed the film a couple of weeks later in Rodinal R09 using about 50:1 over 20 minutes with some agitation. I’m reasonably happy with the results but have to ask myself if the effort involved in getting these images out of an old Hasselblad is really that much superior to the almost instantaneous and high quality of the Ricoh. If it had been just the Ricoh that day, this whole story and reflection might have been consigned to history in a single, fleeting Instagram post. Perhaps it’s nothing to do with the camera.</p>

<h2 id="notes">Notes</h2>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: left">Image</th>
      <th style="text-align: left">Camera</th>
      <th style="text-align: left">Lens</th>
      <th style="text-align: left">ISO</th>
      <th style="text-align: left">Format</th>
      <th style="text-align: center">Aperture</th>
      <th style="text-align: center">Shutter</th>
      <th style="text-align: left">Comment</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left">Header</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Ricoh GR-III</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Ricoh 18.3mm</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">ISO 6400</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Digital</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">f/11</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">1/25s</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Adjusted in Capture One.</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left">Bark</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Hasselblad 503CW</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Zeiss 80mm F2.8 C</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">400</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">120</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">f/2.8</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">1/2 sec</td>
      <td style="text-align: left"> </td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left">Bark 2</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Hasselblad 503CW</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Zeiss 80mm F2.8 C</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">400</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">120</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">f/2.8</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">1/4 sec</td>
      <td style="text-align: left"> </td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left">Bark 3</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Hasselblad 503CW</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Zeiss 80mm F2.8 C</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">400</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">120</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">f/2.8</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">1/30 sec</td>
      <td style="text-align: left"> </td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left">Mushroom</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Hasselblad 503CW</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Zeiss 80mm F2.8 C</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">400</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">120</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">f/2.8</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">1/2 sec</td>
      <td style="text-align: left"> </td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left">Polney Loch</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Hasselblad 503CW</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Zeiss 80mm F2.8 C</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">400</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">120</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">f/22</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">1/3 s</td>
      <td style="text-align: left"> </td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left">House</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Hasselblad 503CW</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Zeiss 80mm F2.8 C</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">400</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">120</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">f/18</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">1 sec</td>
      <td style="text-align: left"> </td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left">Door</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Hasselblad 503CW</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Zeiss 80mm F2.8 C</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">400</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">120</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">f/10</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">1/8 s</td>
      <td style="text-align: left"> </td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Hasselblad" /><category term="503CW" /><category term="Ricoh GRIII" /><category term="Kodak" /><category term="Tri-X 400" /><category term="Scotland" /><category term="Dunkeld" /><category term="Rodinal R09" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Remembering 9/11 20 years on]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://niximagery.com/R0001067.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://niximagery.com/R0001067.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Coigach and Assynt</title><link href="https://niximagery.com/2021/10/10/coigach-assynt.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Coigach and Assynt" /><published>2021-10-10T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-10-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://niximagery.com/2021/10/10/coigach-assynt</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://niximagery.com/2021/10/10/coigach-assynt.html"><![CDATA[<p>For our summer trip North this year, I took the Hasselblad 503CW and my Nikon FM with digital backup from a Ricoh GRIII and my Fuji X-T2. The Agfa stayed in the bag and the GW690ii stayed at home. There’s only so much gear one can carry.</p>

<p>One of the first beaches we headed for was Acheninver, a short walk from the hostel where we spent the first couple of nights. It was overcast for the first few days of our break, which was a blessing for us because the mobs were elsewhere. At the beach was a man filling builder’s bags with seaweed: curious, I asked him why. Crofter Steve Husband explained that there is a <a href="https://www.islemartin.org/isle-martin-seaweed-festival-home/">seaweed festival</a> on Isle Martin in September and that a dry run of glassmaking had used the entire stock of seaweed, so he was replenishing. The seaweed is dried and burned with sand to make artisan glass, and burning kelp is an ancient tradition in the North. Some of the seaweed Steve had gathered looked good enough to eat, and indeed, it can be used for culinary purposes.</p>

<p><img src="/img/DSF7975.jpg" alt="" />
<em>Steve in his tractor with his Gaelic-speaking dog. Fuji X-T2</em></p>

<p>The next day, we tried out a new camping stove on Achmelvich beach, pushing the culinary boundaries by heating up a tin of sausages and beans. Classy. On our meander around the Coigach and Drumbeg, I tried a bit of sketching. Some way to go, I think.</p>

<p><img src="/img/IMG_9378.jpg" alt="" />
<em>Achnahaird beach, sketch</em></p>

<p>The last few days were spent in Drumbeg House, or at least, in a self-contained house within the grounds of said House. This was a perfectly peaceful place to escape for a few days with its own cairn at the side of its own loch and a decent deer population to get us close to that Highland feeling.</p>

<p><img src="/img/DSF8099.jpg" alt="" />
<em>Young stag. Fuji X-T2</em></p>

<p>We were treated to a close encounter with one of these stags, at the point we were ready to give up hope of seeing the wildlife without a telephoto lens, when one wandered through the bracken and paused on the grass between the house and the loch, to gaze at us, neither of us knowing whether to grab a camera or just experience the moment.</p>

<p><img src="/img/Kodak-TMY-400-20210912_17513046.jpg" alt="" />
<em>Keeper’s shed. Hasselblad 503CW, Kodak TMY 400</em></p>

<p>The old house has been renovated, we think under new ownership, perhaps to return to its former glory as an exclusive dining experience for those who do that kind of thing. Traces of a more private small estate are still seen in the grounds.</p>

<p><img src="/img/Kodak-TMY-400-20210912_19434344.jpg" alt="" />
<em>1907. Hasselblad 503CW, Kodak TMY 400</em></p>

<p>We went along the coast to explore the peninsula of Culkein and Stoer, where there are wild rocks and waves from the Northern Minch, and hidden caves.</p>

<p><img src="/img/Kodak-TMY-400-20210912_20371219.jpg" alt="" />
<em>A cave at Stoer. Hasselblad 503CW, Kodak TMY 400</em></p>

<p>Kylesku is a wonderful place and we visited, travelling home past the Sàil Gharb and Sàil Ghórm corbetts.</p>

<p><img src="/img/Kodak-Portra-800-20211010_12151225.jpg" alt="" />
<em>Sàil Gharb and Sàil Ghórm. Nikon FM, Kodak Portra 800</em></p>

<p>The roads were pretty much deserted around here, even in the post-COVID mad summer of 2021 when all of England discovered Scotland.</p>

<p><img src="/img/Kodak-Portra-800-20211010_12192098.jpg" alt="" />
<em>Passing place. Nikon FM, Kodak Portra 800, f/11 1/250s</em></p>
<h2 id="notes">Notes</h2>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: left">Image</th>
      <th style="text-align: left">Camera</th>
      <th style="text-align: left">Lens</th>
      <th style="text-align: left">ISO</th>
      <th style="text-align: left">Format</th>
      <th style="text-align: center">Aperture</th>
      <th style="text-align: center">Shutter</th>
      <th style="text-align: left">Comment</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left">Header</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Fuji X-T2</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">XF35mm F2 R WR</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">ISO 800</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Digital</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">f/8</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">1/250s</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Adjusted in Capture One.</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left">Tractor</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Fuji X-T2</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">XF90mm F2 R LM WR</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">ISO 800</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Digital</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">f/11</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">1/500s</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Cropped &amp; adjusted in Capture One.</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left">Young stag</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Fuji X-T2</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">XF100-400mmF4.5-5.6 R LM OIS WR</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">ISO 1600</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Digital</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">f/10</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">1/500s</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Cropped &amp; adjusted in Capture One.</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left">Shed</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Hasselblad 503CW</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Zeiss 80mm f/2.8</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">400</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">120</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">f/11</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">1/8s</td>
      <td style="text-align: left"> </td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left">1907</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Hasselblad 503CW</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Zeiss 80mm f/2.8</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">400</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">120</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">f/8</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">1/4s</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Cropped</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left">Caves</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Hasselblad 503CW</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Zeiss 80mm f/2.8</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">400</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">120</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">f/22</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">1/8s</td>
      <td style="text-align: left"> </td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left">Sàil Gharb and Sàil Ghórm</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Nikon FM</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Nikon AI-s 28mm f/2.8</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">800</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">135</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">f/11</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">1/250s</td>
      <td style="text-align: left"> </td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left">Passing place</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Nikon FM</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Nikon AI-s 28mm f/2.8</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">800</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">135</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">f/11</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">1/250s</td>
      <td style="text-align: left"> </td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Fuji" /><category term="X-T2" /><category term="Hasselblad" /><category term="503CW" /><category term="Nikon" /><category term="FM" /><category term="Ricoh" /><category term="GRIII" /><category term="Kodak" /><category term="T-Max 400" /><category term="Portra 800" /><category term="Ilford" /><category term="Pan F Plus 50" /><category term="Ektachrome E100" /><category term="Scotland" /><category term="Coigach" /><category term="Assynt" /><category term="Drumbeg" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A few days in the North West]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://niximagery.com/DSF8005.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://niximagery.com/DSF8005.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Five more films: Kodak Portra 160</title><link href="https://niximagery.com/2021/08/08/five-films-5.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Five more films: Kodak Portra 160" /><published>2021-08-08T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-08-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://niximagery.com/2021/08/08/five-films-5</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://niximagery.com/2021/08/08/five-films-5.html"><![CDATA[<p>The final post of this mini series is on Kodak’s latter-day wonder that is Portra, at 135 in my Nikon FM. Again, the wide-angle 28mm f/1.4 Nikon lens was used in all of these images.</p>

<h2 id="kodak-portra-160">Kodak Portra 160</h2>

<p>I scanned most of these at 3200 or 4800 dpi in 48-bit colour with the scanner’s colour handling switch off. The first few frames were taken at the Hermitage, near Dunkeld, during a weekend run up to one of our favourite places in May. We needed reflection time and the COVID restrictions were just so that we could do the right thing as we did The Right Thing for us.</p>

<p><img src="/img/Kodak-Portra-160-20210808_18071280.jpg" alt="" />
<em>Ossian’s Hall. Nikon FM, 28mm f/1.4 AiS</em></p>

<p>The Dunkeld weekend was not in the brightest of sunshine and that tends to wash out the colours in Portra, I think. This is a dark and moody kind of place when it’s overcast, so the image above does portray that. No marks for composition – there’s a better portrait version but that favours the bridge over the hall and I wanted to show that in this post.</p>

<p><img src="/img/Kodak-Portra-160-20210808_18071280-1.jpg" alt="" />
<em>Queensferry Crossing from St. Margaret’s Marsh, see also the header image</em></p>

<p>There was better light when we walked on the Forth Shore at St. Margaret’s Marsh, between the bridges and the dockyard. Some while later, we were at Loch Lubnaig where the colours of the greenery dominate the images taken with this film.</p>

<p><img src="/img/Kodak-Portra-160-20210808_18365655.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>I’m not such a fan of 160 in anything other than really good daylight. Composition plays a part, too, and these images aren’t my best: the last few frames of the roll were taken at Burntisland.</p>

<p><img src="/img/Kodak-Portra-160-20210808_18565359.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<!--15 May Strathyre and Lubnaig
FM 8 ff Portra

27 June Fife beach
FM still Portra 160 ff28ff
-->
<h2 id="notes">Notes</h2>

<p>In this series:</p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: left">Brand</th>
      <th style="text-align: left">Type</th>
      <th style="text-align: left">ISO</th>
      <th style="text-align: left">Format</th>
      <th style="text-align: left">Exposures</th>
      <th style="text-align: left">Camera</th>
      <th style="text-align: left">Lens</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left">Kodak</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Ektachrome E100</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">100</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">120</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">8</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Fuji GW690ii</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">90mm</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left">Cinestill</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">800 T</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">800</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">35mm</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">36</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Nikon FM</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Nikon AI-s 28mm f/2.8</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left">Lomography</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Metropolis</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">EI 400</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">120</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">12</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Hasselblad 503CW</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Zeiss 80mm F2.8 C</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left">Ilford</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Delta</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">3200</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">35mm</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">36</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Nikon FM</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Nikon AI-s 28mm f/2.8</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left">Kodak</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Portra</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">160</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">35mm</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">36</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Nikon FM</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Nikon AI-s 28mm f/2.8</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Nikon" /><category term="FM" /><category term="Kodak" /><category term="Portra 160" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[More random rolls from the COVID era]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://niximagery.com/Kodak-Portra-160-20210808_18071280-2.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://niximagery.com/Kodak-Portra-160-20210808_18071280-2.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Five more films: Ilford Delta 3200</title><link href="https://niximagery.com/2021/08/01/five-films-4.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Five more films: Ilford Delta 3200" /><published>2021-08-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-08-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://niximagery.com/2021/08/01/five-films-4</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://niximagery.com/2021/08/01/five-films-4.html"><![CDATA[<p>For the fourth post in this series, I’m looking at a roll of Ilford Delta 3200 exposed in my Nikon FM. The wide-angle 28mm f/1.4 Nikon lens lives on this FM and was used in all of these images.</p>

<h2 id="ilford-delta-3200">Ilford Delta 3200</h2>

<p>As this is a black and white film, I might have developed this myself but as with all of the films in this mini-series, I got AG Photographic to develop it for me. It was scanned at 6400, then 3200 dpi in 24-bit colour (otherwise the scanner screws up the colour profile in the output file). In post-processing, the profile is switched to black and white. The early images were not of good enough resolution to justify 6400 dpi, hence the switch to something lower.</p>

<p><img src="/img/Ilford-Delta-3200-20210801_16112152.jpg" alt="" />
<em>Edinburgh, from Fife. Nikon FM, 28mm f/1.4 AiS</em></p>

<p>Most of those early frames were quite disappointing, being underexposed and losing detail in the shadows. I’m fairly sure this was a metering issue: I rely on the built-in LED through-the-lens metering when shooting with the Nikon FM and this might be the price of laziness. Some can be recovered, though, and this image shows a sort of moody shoreline to illustrate the point.</p>

<p><img src="/img/Ilford-Delta-3200-20210801_17025154.jpg" alt="" />
<em>Edinburgh. Nikon FM, 28mm f/1.4 AiS</em></p>

<p>This is the view from my office window on the Holyrood campus. Delta 3200 might suggest a good low-light film but I think it’s more fast than it is good in the dark. It needs light to function properly. The next image also, perhaps, is more suited to the grainy emulsion of Delta 3200.</p>

<p><img src="/img/Ilford-Delta-3200-20210801_17174590.jpg" alt="" />
<em>The Palace, Rosyth. Nikon FM, 28mm f/1.4 AiS</em></p>

<p>Something more urban in flavour demands not only monochrome but also the character of a grainy film stock like this. I don’t think it handles wide dynamic range the way I had hoped, however. Shooting into the light is probably not the best idea:</p>

<p><img src="/img/Ilford-Delta-3200-20210801_17251720.jpg" alt="" />
<em>Harbour Bell, St.Monans. Nikon FM, 28mm f/1.4 AiS</em></p>

<p>Delta 3200 can perform well with good light, and yield decent contrasty images if you meter and expose correctly. The header image is of St.Monans Harbour and I think shows off the film well.</p>

<h2 id="notes">Notes</h2>

<p>In this series:</p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: left">Brand</th>
      <th style="text-align: left">Type</th>
      <th style="text-align: left">ISO</th>
      <th style="text-align: left">Format</th>
      <th style="text-align: left">Exposures</th>
      <th style="text-align: left">Camera</th>
      <th style="text-align: left">Lens</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left">Kodak</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Ektachrome E100</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">100</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">120</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">8</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Fuji GW690ii</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">90mm</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left">Cinestill</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">800 T</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">800</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">35mm</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">36</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Nikon FM</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Nikon AI-s 28mm f/2.8</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left">Lomography</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Metropolis</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">EI 400</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">120</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">12</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Hasselblad 503CW</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Zeiss 80mm F2.8 C</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left">Ilford</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Delta</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">3200</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">35mm</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">36</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Nikon FM</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Nikon AI-s 28mm f/2.8</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left">Kodak</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Portra</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">160</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">35mm</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">36</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Nikon FM</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Nikon AI-s 28mm f/2.8</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Nikon" /><category term="FM" /><category term="Ilford" /><category term="Delta 3200" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[More random rolls from the COVID era]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://niximagery.com/Ilford-Delta-3200-20210801_17251720-1.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://niximagery.com/Ilford-Delta-3200-20210801_17251720-1.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>