<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Niximagery</title>
<link>https://niximagery.com/index.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://niximagery.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description></description>
<image>
<url>https://niximagery.com/images/IMG_9378.png</url>
<title>Niximagery</title>
<link>https://niximagery.com/index.html</link>
</image>
<generator>quarto-1.3.427</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 23:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Ardnamurchan</title>
  <link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2023/2023-04-08-ardnamurchan.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="ardnamurchan-and-moidart" class="level1">
<h1>Ardnamurchan and Moidart</h1>
<p>This term has been quite a slog, and this week in particular has brought challenges both predictable and unexpected, and equally unwelcome. Very welcome, then, is a few days of retreat in one of our favourite places on this amazing planet of ours, by the Ardnamurchan peninsular.</p>
<section id="saturday" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="saturday">Saturday</h2>
<p>We arrived uncharacteristically early and so stopped to stretch our legs and lungs before heading to our cottage on Loch Shiel. We saw the steam train on the way up, and what seemed like thirty thousand people at Glenfinnan desperate to watch it go over the viaduct. We passed by that opportunity to seek the road less travelled.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/23-4-DSF1042.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <strong>Samalaman harbour</strong> X-T5, f/16 at 1/60s<sup>1</sup></p>
<p>We found Samalaman Bay, with population but a population much more at leisure. Kayakers in the water, a family playing football on the beach, others reading and idly doing the crossword in the fresh air. We wandered on the shore making photographs, watching plovers and hooded crows, studying the urchins and just breathing.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/23-4-DSF1045.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <strong>Samalaman harbour</strong> X-T5, f/16 at 1/60s<sup>2</sup></p>
<p>Further up the road, we found a nice view back toward Glen Moidart, by three stone piles marked on the OS map as <em>Captain Robertson’s Cairn</em>. I pushed my luck with an image taken hand-held at 1/30s and either I am already quite chilled now, or that image stabilisation in the X-T5 is pretty good. Click the image for a closer look.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/23-4-DSF1047.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <strong>Glen Moidart</strong> X-T5, f/16 at 1/30s<sup>3</sup></p>
</section>
<section id="sunday" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="sunday">Sunday</h2>
<p>A close encounter with geese and an eagle on the shores of Loch Shiel, then a herd of deer scampering past the cottage, were precursors to a leisurely country breakfast. We headed out to explore Ardtoe and Kentra Bay with the dynamics of Scottish weather broad-brushing new scenery as we passed through the landscape. On the road, a folorn looking phone box stood mocking the advance of technology and the flatline mobile signal here, which is actually part of the attraction.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/23-4-DSF1051.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <strong>It’s good to talk</strong> X-T5, f/11 at 1/30s<sup>4</sup></p>
<p>Although it wasn’t the weather to visit the singing sands (it apparently needs to be dry), we took a test drive to the car park at the start of the walking route that takes you there, at Arivegaig.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/23-4-DSF0993.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <strong>The family</strong> X-T2, 1/125s, f/7.1, 400mm<sup>5</sup></p>
<p>On the way down, we noted how rich the wildlife is here in comparison with other places we’ve been up and down the western highlands. After the eagle this morning, other birds had made their presence felt, as had the deer. The deer camouflage seems to make them confident and relaxed close to the fairly quiet roads. Sheep are confident, too, ambling along and disrespecting the passing places. They don’t need camouflage. They seem to think they are indestructible, like Edinburgh pedestrians. We eat a lot more lamb than we do venison, just saying.</p>
<!-- Samalaman Bay -->
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/23-4-DSF1056.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <strong>Kinlochmoidart pier</strong> X-T5, f/16 at 1/30s, ISO400</p>
<p>I couldn’t resist this photogenic old pier on the road beside Loch Moidart’s glistening green sandbanks. We may return, having overheard in a restaurant this evening that it’s a good place for otters.</p>
</section>
<section id="monday" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="monday">Monday</h2>
<p>Between heavy rain showers, we took a walk to the local beach, as much to seek out more of the wildlife as to just stretch our legs. The river Shiel runs into the loch, with other inlets feeding the waters.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/23-4-DSF1068.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <strong>Loch Shiel</strong> X-T5, f/8 at 1/500s, ISO200</p>
<p>The geese were occupying the pasture nearby, without being harrassed by the eagle today. This character quickly assumed alpha status and went through his best traffic cop routine. His pal seemed slighty embarrassed.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/23-4-DSF1115.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <strong>No, that way</strong> X-T2, 1/1000s, f/5.6, 400mm<sup>6</sup></p>
<p>Castle Tioram on Loch Moidart was built over 800 years ago by Amie of the Clanranalds <span class="citation" data-cites="Macdonald1889">(Macdonald, 1889)</span> after her husband, “Good John” of Isla had divorced her. It was torched by the clan chief Allan Macdonald during the Jacobite uprising in 1715 and has remained uninhabited since.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/23-4-DSF1083.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <strong>Castle Tioram</strong> X-T5, f/16 at 1/30s, ISO125</p>
<p>The castle is reached by walking across the sand bar at Doirlinn. It is green on account of the damp and slippery approaches that kept the castle safe for so long from attackers. The Clanranalds had plenty of those, and the Priest of Moidart, Charles Macdonald, describes many in detail, such as this account from a fight between the outnumbered Frasers and Clanranalds:</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>“… like brave men, determined to cut their way through the opposing ranks, or die in the attempt. A most furious and sanguinary hand-to-hand fight ensued. Owing to the heat of the weather, the combatants threw off their upper garments, and fought, like butchers…” <span class="citation" data-cites="Macdonald1889">(ibid., 47)</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/23-4-DSF110223-4-Panorama.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <strong>Castle Tioram</strong> X-T5, f/16 at 1/60s, ISO400, stitch of two images</p>
</section>
<section id="tuesday" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="tuesday">Tuesday</h2>
<!-- !!! info inline end "" -->
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DJI_0030.JPG" class="img-fluid"> <strong>Quite the selfie</strong> DJI, automatic jpg capture over the beach at Loch Shiel</p>
<p>Back to the shores of Loch Shiel for a walk before breakfast and a bit of drone activity. We’re still learning how to use this amazing little machine but even the practice sequences are pretty impressive: the bird’s eye view is something mankind has sought since Icarus.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DJI_0035a.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <strong>The Singing Sands</strong> DJI, DNG adjusted in Capture One</p>
<p>We pushed the advantage of our aerial platform and went on the long round trip walk to the Singing Sands at Gortenfearn to capture it. The sand doesn’t actually sing, by the way – it’s more of a squeak when you walk on dry stretches of it. From the car park by Arivegaig, the walk took us past the southern edge of Kentra Bay and through forestry and down to the beach. By the time we got there, all had left but a couple of wild campers who gave us a cheery wave from their lookout above the beach. They must have had a better handle on the weather, which turned to gusty rain for the 6km walk back to the car.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/Screenshot-2023-04-11.png" class="img-fluid"> <strong>The Singing Sands</strong> Screenshot from video playback</p>
<p>It’s no hardship: I was told by a lawyer once that in Scotland, we believe that a little suffering is good for you. I can’t argue with that; how else might you fully appreciate a nice hot bath and glass of wine once you’re back at base, toasty warm and dry again?</p>



</section>
</section>


<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section class="quarto-appendix-contents"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">References</h2><div id="refs" class="references csl-bib-body hanging-indent">
<div id="ref-Macdonald1889" class="csl-entry">
Macdonald, Rev. Charles. 1889. <em><span class="nocase">Moidart; or Among the Clanranalds</span></em>.
</div>
</div></section><section id="footnotes" class="footnotes footnotes-end-of-document"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Footnotes</h2>

<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>Fuji X-T5, XF16mmF1.4, f/16, ISO 125↩︎</p></li>
<li id="fn2"><p>Fuji X-T5, XF16mmF1.4, f/16, ISO 125↩︎</p></li>
<li id="fn3"><p>Fuji X-T5, XF16mmF1.4, f/16, ISO 125↩︎</p></li>
<li id="fn4"><p>Fuji X-T5, XF16mmF1.4, f/16, ISO 125↩︎</p></li>
<li id="fn5"><p>Fuji X-T2, XF100-400mmF4.5-5.6 R LM OIS WR, ISO 200↩︎</p></li>
<li id="fn6"><p>Fuji X-T2, XF100-400mmF4.5-5.6 R LM OIS WR, ISO 200↩︎</p></li>
</ol>
</section></div> ]]></description>
  <guid>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2023/2023-04-08-ardnamurchan.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Winter Walks</title>
  <link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2023/2023-02-05-winter-walking.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="winter-walks" class="level1">
<h1>Winter walks</h1>
<p>Winter has its attractions, even if it isn’t all frosty and picturesque by the time we’re up and about. The camera is often the excuse to get up off the couch and out of the house, side benefits being clearing of the head and lungs, stretching of muscle and tendon and general wellbeing. This is true even if the photographs don’t turn out well. Or even if no photographs are taken at all, and the cameras effectively become ballast. Professional, I am not.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF0457.jpg" class="img-fluid"> Inchcolm Abbey, <em>Fuji X-T5, XF100-400mm</em></p>
<p>That’s not to say I can’t swan about with a massive zoom lens and <em>look</em> like a professional. I did this on a short run to the Braefoot Bay marine terminal by Aberdour. We walked up to the Monk’s Cave, from where I zoomed in on the Abbey on Inchcolm island in the Forth. At 400mm, the foreshortening brings the distant ski slope much closer and amplifies the haze effect.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF0520.jpg" class="img-fluid"> Eurasian Curlew</p>
<p>The whole point of having the big lens on is to try to take photos of living things, which, being long time survivors of Man’s 7 million year evolution, know to keep a distance between themselves and a bloke in a bobble hat. I was pleased enough with this, quite possibly my first reasonable wildlife photograph. A combination of the long lens and my new X-T5’s 40MPixel file size gave scope for a crop which I think still renders nicely on screen.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF0531 1.jpg" class="img-fluid"> “Nevermore!”</p>
<p>These characters are everywhere, or at least, I hope it’s not the same one following me around. Again, a crop from a zoomed in image which allowed me to cover my composition errors. I forget who it was who said that they never crop, always capturing the intended photograph in the viewfinder. There’s elegence in that idea that I admire but I suspect that not many world-class captures use every pixel that hits the sensor. There’s legitimate art in the post-capture processing and adjustments, I think.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF0698.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>Fuji X-T2, Nikon A-iS 85mm f/1.4</em></p>
<p>I love the textures everywhere. My wife and I discussed what this image might be called and couldn’t really think of anything we could put on a public website. I’m just going to move along to the grasses at the edge of the tide’s reach along the shore, which offer movement and colour.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF0700 1.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>Fuji X-T2, Nikon A-iS 85mm f/1.4</em></p>
<p>I want to call this, “Neapolitan” for the bands of colour, like ice cream.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF0704.jpg" class="img-fluid"> The Bridges <em>Fuji X-T2, Nikon A-iS 85mm f/1.4</em></p>
<p>We meandered home past the rising tide today and, looking back towards the bridges, across the sands of Pettycur Bay, felt thankful for all the privilege we enjoy, living close by to these amazing places.</p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2023/2023-02-05-winter-walking.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Patterdale</title>
  <link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2023/2023-02-18-patterdale.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="patterdale" class="level1">
<h1>Patterdale</h1>
<p>The February half-term break gave us the opportunity to head back to the Lake District for a few days of walking and exploration. We’d been to Patterdale several times and love the care that has been given to the preservation and development of the area. The Lakes have a distinct feel to them; it’s in the stones, and the local businesses, and even the vehicles.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/2023-02/DSF0724Panorama.jpg" class="img-fluid"> Patterdale, <em>Fuji X-T2, Nikon 85mm f/1.4</em></p>
<p>!!! info inline end “” <img src="https://niximagery.com/img/2023-02/DSF0596.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>Fuji X-T5, XF16mm f/1.4 R WR</em></p>
<p>The dark skies on our first night confounded the weather forecast and were a treat, and a challenge to our photography as we wrestled with remembering how to capture a night sky. Street lamps, industry, intruder lights and the like all usually conspire to deny the humbling sight of stars and galaxies overhead, and so I was certainly out of practice. I was reasonably pleased with this image, with the Orion Nebula, or NGC 1976 clearly seen as a smudge below Orion’s belt near the centre of the picture. NGC 1976 is a region of star formation, over 1,000 light-years away from us and yet still within our own Galaxy, the Milky Way.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/2023-02/DSF0604.jpg" class="img-fluid"> Goldrill Beck river, Patterdale <em>Fuji X-T5, XF16mm f/1.4 R WR</em></p>
<p>Our home-from-home was on the road over the Goldrill Beck river on good walking routes. The bridge over the river is a classic spot to capture the iconic pastoral view looking Northwest towards Ullswater.</p>
<p>!!! info inline “” <img src="https://niximagery.com/img/2023-02/DSF0751-1.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>Fuji X-T5, XF16mm f/1.4 R WR</em></p>
<p>!!! info inline end “” <img src="https://niximagery.com/img/2023-02/DSF0764.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>Fuji X-T2, XF100-400mmF4.5-5.6 R</em></p>
<p>There were plenty of timeless sights to drink in as we walked the paths around the Southern end of Ullswater, which, if we had to state a preference, would be our favourite end. It feels more “Lake District”: walls are layered slates, buildings are, too. Raptors and smaller birds proudly converse and advertise their presence. People exchange pleasant conversation if they want to, or pass by, deep in their reveries. Others peek at you from behind walls, curious.</p>
<p>We didn’t venture too far on this trip, spending more time on our feet than in the car exploring. Sometimes we do more “drive-by shooting” in areas we don’t know too well, so as to try to get a sense of a place. That often doesn’t work but this break, we went slower, and breathed the place in better. Oh, for the life that gives the fullest opportunity for breathing places in.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/2023-02/DSF0765 1_Panorama.jpg" class="img-fluid"> Brothers Water <em>Fuji X-T5, XF16mm f/1.4 R WR</em></p>
<p>At Aira Force (meaning <em>waterfall</em>, from Old Norse), we bimbled around snatching long and short exposures, chatting to other photographers who had travelled from far to capture a memory of the place. This is the kind of place that increasingly tests my surety of foot: the rocks are wet and slippery, paths are muddy, roots are deadly cunning. The effect of this environment is to slow me down even more now I’m older and less Weeble. This is a blessing: I see more.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/2023-02/DSF0792.jpg" class="img-fluid"> Aira Force <em>Fuji X-T5, XF16mm f/1.4 R WR</em></p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/2023-02/DSF0806.jpg" class="img-fluid"> Aira Force <em>Fuji X-T5, XF16mm f/1.4 R WR</em></p>
<p>!!! info inline “” <img src="https://niximagery.com/img/2023-02/DSF0794 1.jpg" class="img-fluid"> Air Force <em>Fuji X-T2, XF100-400mm</em></p>
<p>!!! info inline end “” <img src="https://niximagery.com/img/2023-02/DSF0829.jpg" class="img-fluid"> Buzzard, <em>Fuji X-T2, XF100-400mm</em></p>
<p>This is not to say that I see very much, of course. At Aira Force we saw or rather, heard then saw, a drone overhead with the owner standing aloof from danger on a nice dry, flat rock. The point of view from the mobile platform is always going to be better than wherever I can scramble to with my gear. The cameras in many of these devices are often on a par with any digital SLR. The Devil in me wanted first to throw a rock at the drone, then at the owner. Instead, I wondered whether drone photography is something else – something different to stills photography altogether. It’s a matter of choice and opportunity, I suppose, what medium an artist uses to tell a story. Images are part of that, perhaps, no matter how obtained, but the mental imagery they invoke might be more so.</p>
<p>!!! info inline “” <img src="https://niximagery.com/img/2023-02/DSF0755.jpg" class="img-fluid"> Chaffinch <em>Fuji X-T2, XF100-400mm</em></p>
<p>!!! info inline end “” <img src="https://niximagery.com/img/2023-02/DSF0823.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>Fuji X-T2, XF100-400mm</em></p>
<p>I carried two cameras as we walked; one for landscape, wider images, with a 16mm lens, and the other, with my monster Fuji XF100-400mmF4.5-5.6 R zoom to try to capture some of the wildlife. We saw more than I captured, including a much-signposted but not often seen red squirrel. The Air Force offered me a reminder to have the correct settings on at all times by flying low over Ullswater when I hadn’t (this jet was taken at 1/125s hand held on manual focus), but which helped me be a little more ready for robins and raptors.</p>
<p>We had planned the trip, sort of, by identifying some of the interesting places others had written about or shared. One of these was The Duke of Portland’s Boathouse at the Northern end of Ullswater, once the property of the 18th Century 3rd Duke of Portland, sold to save him from bankruptcy. Now, it’s a hugely overpriced holiday rental.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/2023-02/DSF0812.jpg" class="img-fluid"> The Duke of Portland’s Boathouse <em>Fuji X-T5, XF16mm f/1.4 R WR</em></p>
<p>We delayed the journey home after check-out time in order to enjoy a little serendipity. Driving up the Kirkstone Pass, I misunderstood the navigator and instead of turning into a car park at the top of the pass, headed down the road called “the Struggle” that leads to Ambleside and Lake Windermere. I pulled off the road to give us time to decide how far we would go down that road – we were not keen on visiting the denser touristy places, even at this time of year. When we checked the view, we decided it was a good place to eat the lunch we had bought in Glenridding.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/2023-02/DSF0830 1.jpg" class="img-fluid"> The Struggle <em>Fuji X-T5, XF16mm f/1.4 R WR</em></p>
<p>We continued further to explore, finding a couple of interesting old pines at the side of the road. This is beautifully circular, as we had been staying in a place called, “<a href="https://www.wordsworthbarn-ullswater.co.uk/">Wordsworth Barn</a>”, so named for the poet who onced owned the barn that is now a holiday rental.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/2023-02/DSF0834 1.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>Wordsworth Barn was quite wonderful, although, at 6’4”, I enjoyed a close personal relationship with the old beams. That aside, the host, Joan, had thought cleverly about what her guests need to know and have when staying here. We had booked for our basic needs – wood-burning stove, self-contained, superb location and ease of access to the things we wanted to see – and Joan had taken care of all of the things we didn’t think to specify, like every kind of glass we might use; dressing gowns; a bath <em>and</em> a shower; a personal welcome; thoughtful use of space; fresh milk and a bottle of fizz. None of the usual irritations, either: fuel for the log burner is included, recycling is easy and intelligently organised, everything works (although a builder’s knack is required to unlock the front door). We will be back.</p>
<p>Wordsworth was well known for his love of trees <span class="citation" data-cites="Dale2022">(Dale and Yen, 2022)</span> and “wished to be remembered as a tree hugger” <span class="citation" data-cites="Yen2022">(Yen, 2022)</span>. It seems appropriate to end this post with something written by Wordsworth whilst in the area, that seems to connect some of our experiences over the past few days:</p>
<p>!!! info “Written in March”</p>
<pre><code>While resting on the Bridge at the Foot of Brother's Water.

The cock is crowing,  
The stream is flowing,  
The small birds twitter,  
The lake doth glitter,  
The green field sleeps in the sun;  
The oldest and youngest  
Are at work with the strongest;  
The cattle are grazing,  
Their heads never raising;  
There are forty feeding like one!  

Like an army defeated  
The snow hath retreated,  
And now doth fare ill  
On the top of the bare hill;  
The Ploughboy is whooping–anon–anon:  
There’s joy in the mountains;  
There’s life in the fountains;  
Small clouds are sailing,  
Blue sky prevailing;  
The rain is over and gone!

-- William Wordsworth</code></pre>



</section>

<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section class="quarto-appendix-contents"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">References</h2><div id="refs" class="references csl-bib-body hanging-indent">
<div id="ref-Dale2022" class="csl-entry">
Dale, Peter, and Brandon C. Yen. 2022. <em><span class="nocase">Versed in Living Nature: Wordsworth’s Trees</span></em>. Reaktion.
</div>
<div id="ref-Yen2022" class="csl-entry">
Yen, Brandon C. 2022. <span>“<span class="nocase">Forget daffodils, Wordsworth also had much to say about trees</span>.”</span> <a href="https://www.rte.ie/brainstorm/2022/1104/1333188-william-wordsworth-trees-poetry/">https://www.rte.ie/brainstorm/2022/1104/1333188-william-wordsworth-trees-poetry/</a>.
</div>
</div></section></div> ]]></description>
  <guid>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2023/2023-02-18-patterdale.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Dunkeld Christmas preparation</title>
  <link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-12-24-dunkeld.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="dunkeld-christmas-preparation" class="level1">
<h1>Dunkeld Christmas preparation</h1>
<p>Earlier in the year, we booked a dinner-bed-and-breakfast deal for Christmas Eve’s eve, as much for corporeal as spiritual health. Before he knew what was happening, the cat was dropped at his aunties’ place and we were in our favourite winter woodland. The intention was to unwind on the approach to Christmas Day; to hit pause on the processes of work, study, shopping and the rest. It worked a charm. We didn’t book the suite we had when we were married at the Dunkeld House Hotel but our room was enough for the purpose.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF0685_Panorama.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>The Hermitage</em> Fuji X-T2, Nikon 85mm f/1.4 lens.</p>
<p>There was plenty of time to enjoy a slow wander around the Hermitage before check-in. We took cameras, but not the usual paraphernalia of tripods and filters. Very soon, the life-giving oxygen of the trees respiring reached our lungs and Mother Nature <em>cwtched</em> us both. That feeling never gets old and before long we were on speaking terms with the residents again.</p>
<p>!!! info inline “” <img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF0657.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>!!! info inline end “” <img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF0642.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>Notices seem to have discouraged the previously trending habit of visitors forcing coins into any tree stump. Like most popular excesses, it’s neither healthy nor tasteful, like those repetitive memes you see. I’m glad the coin habit seems to be on the wane, even if the endless banality of social media is anything but. Oh, look, there’s yet another New Year’s resolution.</p>
<p>The soundscape on a walk around the Hermitage trail is varied, especially in the winter when the River Braan is swollen with meltwater from the recent snow. I didn’t record it: it’s white noise in a browser. Perhaps the picture will help you hear the rushing of the whitewater over rocks on the fall by Ossian’s Hall.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF0696.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>!!! info inline end “” <img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF0695.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>On the other side of the A9, the Tay wanders beside the hotel, altogether a more dignified spectacle than the its manic neighbour, the Braan. Alongside that river is the “dookit” or stone structure where we were married in the gentle Perthshire rainfall, with poetry and music and prayer. We walked down to remind ourselves and renew the feelings of that day. It was beautiful, of course.</p>
<p>So, now, I write this on the “other side” of the Christmas celebrations we were preparing ourselves for; the joys and excesses, catechisms and exchanges of gifts, avoided topics, revelations and ghosts of those departed. That one night away, to worship in the cathedral of nature, to enjoy someone else cooking, to be ourselves for ourselves, was not only the perfect preparation for the bacchanalian feast, but also a <em>shahada</em> for the year ahead.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF0690_Panorama.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>Nature’s Cathedral</em> Fuji X-T2, Nikon 85mm f/1.4 lens.</p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-12-24-dunkeld.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>School Sketches</title>
  <link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-12-05-school-sketches.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="school-sketches" class="level1">
<h1>School sketches</h1>
<p>During late November and early December, my job has required me to make visits to schools. The schedule can be challenging so I always try to arrive around 20 minutes early so as to check any messages, and enter the school with grace and dignity. On this cycle of visits, I thought I’d use the extra time to also practice some sketching.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/sketches/22-11-15-Linlithgow.JPG" class="img-fluid"> <em>Linlithgow Academy</em></p>
<p>There is a rationale for this habit. Sketching is a deliberate, mindful process, even when done quickly. It helps you see what is there, and the looking doesn’t stop when the sketchbook is closed. At Linlithgow, I found myself studying wall displays, people, the dynamic of school reception spaces, looking at shapes and patterns as much as inscriptions. I even got the chance to assist some not-yet-detective material police officers in their hunt for the reception desk, being able to indicate the huge sign that my fine-tuned sketcher’s observational skills had spotted in the lobby.</p>
<p>!!! info inline “” <img src="https://niximagery.com/img/sketches/22-11-08-DeansCHS.JPG" class="img-fluid"> <em>Deans Community High School</em></p>
<p>We continue to invest in building new schools to replace older, more out of date infrastructure. This is a good thing for many reasons including sending a message to the country that education is important and valuable to us all. Whilst every school is different, certain design features and material choices appear in many of the recent builds, perhaps dating them. This is not to say they look the same – they do, in some respects, but each has its own features according to the perceived needs of the community they serve.</p>
<p>!!! info inline end “” <img src="https://niximagery.com/img/sketches/22-11-16-KirkcaldyHS.jpeg" class="img-fluid"> <em>Kirkcaldy High School</em></p>
<p>I taught Physics and Mathematics at Kirkcaldy High School for a number of years before replacing my own tutor at Moray House. I’m not going to reminisce about this old place but it was nice to go back for a visit and see friends and former colleagues again. I was reminded that cultures are slow to change and that whilst rolling stones may gather no moss, they do gather experience you don’t get standing still.</p>
<p>Bunsen burners, magnesium strips and good dialogic pedagogy made my job easy at Preston Lodge today. All the nicer to see more old friends, too. Education is a village, and once you’ve been at it a while, it can feel like going home when you meet again, people who have shared different parts of your journey. Conversations pick up where they left off, friendship hugs shock the pupils, and mutual respect is grown and shared from stories of careers unfolding. I love it when new teachers see that: they are enculturated into their vocation through the modelled behaviours of those that go before them, and shape them. There’s more to this than Vygotksy, or Bruner, or the latest educational fad.</p>
<p>!!! info inline “” <img src="https://niximagery.com/img/sketches/22-11-23-PrestonLodge.jpeg" class="img-fluid"> <em>Preston Lodge High School</em> !!! info inline end “” <img src="https://niximagery.com/img/sketches/22-11-25-PortobelloHS.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>Portobello High School</em></p>
<p>Preston Lodge and Portobello sketches are not the best likeness to the <em>real thing</em>, for similar reasons. At Preston Lodge, my view from the car was obscured by a large van and so I had to interpret and sketch what I <em>felt</em> was there. Isn’t that the point, though? The American photographer David Alan Harvey said, “Don’t shoot what it looks like. Shoot what it feels like.” This is my motivation in photography as much as in sketching, and exploring that idea is the principal reason for me wanting to sketch more often. At Portobello, a different large van also obscured the view, and I don’t have the confidence quite to stand in a car park sketching, in full view of the CCTV. I had a call to go in to school anyway, so I took a quick photo on my phone and sketched it up later in a café over lunch. From this experience, I think I do a better job sketching live, <em>en plein air</em>, than from a photo. Something seems to be missing in my drawing from a photo, at least where my skills are at present. Perhaps that will change with practice.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/sketches/22-11-28-LeithAc.jpeg" class="img-fluid"> <em>The lorry at Leith, with a fast rat</em></p>
<p>Leith Academy has a nice front façade but you can’t see it from where I parked, and the back of the building is ugly, so I sketched the random lorry in the car park instead. I did not find out what the vehicle does, or why it’s there, but it looks arty to me, even if it seems past its best service days. Leith has always felt like an arty school: it has interesting shaped science labs which are full of scope and character, even if some of the electrical infrastructure also seems past its best service days. The teachers are anything but, of course, nor the businesslike head teacher who introduced himself as I was preparing to leave for my next appointment. It’s great that there are schools like Leith who put the effort and investment into new teachers, for the wider good of Scottish education.</p>
<p>!!! info inline “” <img src="https://niximagery.com/img/sketches/22-11-28-MusselburghGS.jpeg" class="img-fluid"> <em>Musselburgh Grammar School</em></p>
<p>There is a <em>quid pro quo</em>, of course, in the benefit that mentors and other colleagues get from watching rookies make naïve mistakes and offering guidance and advice from experience, at the same time tapping in to new ideas and reconnecting to the principles of pedagogy that are fresh in the student teachers’ thinking. This was articulated in both schools I visited today by the supporting teachers who played their important part in bringing about fair and just evaluation of how their charges have progressed.</p>
<p>!!! info inline end “” <img src="https://niximagery.com/img/sketches/22-11-29-QueensferryHS.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>Queensferry CHS, in the fog</em></p>
<p>There was a thick fog for my journey across the Forth to Queensferry and I almost bottled doing the sketch because I don’t know how to draw fog. I had a word with myself and thought, “just put the pen marks where it’s dark, and don’t put them where it’s light”. Easier said than, done, I think, so I diverted myself by trying to capture a couple of figures approaching the pool of light from the lamp. I remember a sketcher artist I follow said that figures add interest to a sketch. I think they are right, but I prefer the Leith rat, if I’m honest.</p>
<p>!!! info inline “” <img src="https://niximagery.com/img/sketches/22-11-29-DeansCHS.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>Deans CHS again</em></p>
<p>Back to Deans again and a view from a different part of the car park. It’s interesting how varied these buildings can look, depending on where you look from. My wife calls my style “Roobarb”, for the unsteady hand that wiggles the lines. I did get an ‘O’ level many years ago in technical drawing, so I do know how to use a ruler but when I’m trying to work quickly – none of these sketches took more than about 10 minutes – the look is more one of impression than technical accuracy. I was conscious that I was cold sitting in the car at Deans and so the lines were more Roobarb than usual, perhaps. More figure suggestions, though, and they seem to be growing on me. I’m quite pleased with the silver birch, too, given that I’m not giving myself time to make 10,000 strokes for the leaves.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/sketches/22-11-30-DingwallAc.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>Dingwall</em></p>
<p>A long but pleasant drive up beyond Inverness took me to new territory, and once more found me shaking hands with colleagues who had passed through my tutorials at Moray House. It’s lovely to see the products of my labour thriving and making their mark on young people across the country. I am taking all the credit, of course, as I will for the superb teacher whose lesson on nuclear fission was one of the best I have ever seen. It’s not all me, of course: a lot of work goes in to becoming a teacher, especially a good one, and you have to bring a lot of things, too. Attitude, aptitude, wit, intelligence, humour, resilience, just to mention a few. Those who bring all of that with them perhaps don’t need much from me to succeed, but I do like to tell myself that I help them excel.</p>
<p>!!! info inline end “” <img src="https://niximagery.com/img/sketches/22-12-01-BroxburnAc.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>Broxburn Academy</em></p>
<p>As the weeks of touring schools come to an end for this session at least, I feel that I have been inspired by students, colleagues and the young people in schools. The student teachers have a steep learning curve, especially on their first school placement. Workload can be an issue, and both schools and the university urge the students to try to find a good, healthy, sustainable balance. I asked some of them what their “secret” is for managing this. All said that the balance is crucial to survival, and that part of that is remaining physically active through sport or exercise. Some of them run; others swim or play a sport. This advice I took myself today by going for a run in the early morning darkness.</p>
<p>Vehicles are often a challenge for schools at the beginning and end of the day, even more so when parking is limited, so the final visit of the tour found me arriving at my destination later than planned. I parked in a quiet residential area and enjoyed a walk through the catchment instead of having time to sketch. By now, I was thinking that although every school is different, I had probably sketched enough fairly-recently-built school buildings to have a good appreciation for their character.</p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-12-05-school-sketches.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://niximagery.com/img/sketches/22-11-15-Linlithgow2.JPG" medium="image"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The Frandy Tree</title>
  <dc:creator>Norse Mythology</dc:creator>
  <link>https://niximagery.com/Moments/2022-11-02-frandy-tree.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF8829.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <strong>The Frandy Tree</strong>, an Ash at Glendevon</p>
<p>In the Norse mythology the Ash tree is known as the Yggdrasil and associated with the God Odin who is similar in some respects to the Celtic Gwydion. In order to obtain the Futhark Runes, Odin is said to have hung himself upon the Yggdrasil and received the Runes in his trance. As such, attuning to the World Tree in this fashion can bring gifts of blessing and inspiration.</p>
<p><em>from <a href="https://druidry.org/druid-way/teaching-and-practice/druid-tree-lore/ash">Druidry.org</a>.</em></p>



 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://niximagery.com/Moments/2022-11-02-frandy-tree.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF8829.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>In the Scots Pine</title>
  <dc:creator>Rody Gorman</dc:creator>
  <link>https://niximagery.com/Moments/2022-10-30-scots-pine.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF0430.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>sa ghiuthas-Albannach, eun a’ bruidhinn<br>
chan ann ann an cainnt nan eun<br>
ach anns a’ chànan aige fhèin</p>
<p>in the Scots Pine, a bird talks not in the language of the birds but in his own idiolect</p>
<p>– Rody Gorman</p>
<p><em>from the <a href="https://www.facebook.com/scottishpoetrylibrary/posts/pfbid0y2NP3Gmgi75mgBrc7RQCTJpJcxN6dwHbUmH9K73xXDU2XC66rwCBvoJSZd9WEbQMl?__cft__%5B0%5D=AZXOl2SJUyeq0q_kJ-SpPCSXOpVWOKq-damAImGoKSEv4gyk39MwYp5TyUolSJvMV71mCx7ZB6Zn4dHTqrHCSP_vDf7raJc8v87_QBwVGhG5htI7uHijnx2Zl1UBqL5LjglrpdBqdi1STytgPzDnHCwFXO3QGIOFGqbn3iMAQEaFj5Ta9P6NAsKkQV2JUAwE0gk&amp;__tn__=%2CO%2CP-R">Scottish Poetry Library</a>.</em></p>



 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://niximagery.com/Moments/2022-10-30-scots-pine.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF0430.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The Summer House</title>
  <link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-10-16-summer-house.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="the-summer-house" class="level1">
<h1>The Summer House</h1>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF0360_Panorama.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <strong>The Summer House towards the lake</strong></p>
<p>We took a weekend off for our anniversary, heading to a beautiful retreat in the Borders within the grounds of Chisholme House estate. We have not often chosen the Borders over our more usual favourite direction of North but wanted, as usual, a decent distance from hustle and bustle, nature and a wood-burning stove to curl up in front of at the end of the day. A place to read, reflect, walk and enjoy life together. Not far from Hawick, <a href="https://www.summerhousestays.co.uk/">the Summer House</a> offers all of that and more.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF0022.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <strong>The Summer House from the lake</strong></p>
<p>This place has been fairly recently renovated and is cosy, warm and spacious enough for families and small groups to enjoy the stunning countryside here. There is a lake close by with swans and moorhens. A young deer met us on the driveway as we headed on to the estate. Owls serenaded the night. An otter played chicken with us in the road and then blew otter raspberries from the safety of a hedge.</p>
<section id="chisholme-house" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="chisholme-house">Chisholme House</h2>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF0373_Panorama.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <strong>Chisholme House</strong></p>
<p>We did not go for (or know about) the retreats offered by the school at Chisholme but were intrigued and perhaps focused a little by the environment. From <a href="https://www.chisholme.org/">their website</a>:</p>
<p>!!! quote “Dedicated to the art of self discovery” Chisholme offers an education for those who are convinced of our potential as human beings for goodness and positive effect on this earth, and who wish to be of service to it, to love and to learn.</p>
</section>
<section id="a-sense-of-sufism" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="a-sense-of-sufism">A sense of Sufism</h2>
<p>There seems to be no particular religion behind the philosophy at Chisholme but the school considers writings of great scholars of Islam, in particular those in the Sufi tradition such as Rumi and Ibn’Arabi. The Summer House includes artefacts of the three Abrahamic faiths of Islam, Christianity and Judaism.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF0417.jpg" class="img-fluid"><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF0377.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <strong>The Basmala</strong> appears at threshholds to the old and new summerhouse. The older summer house is in the walled garden, which is well tended by the gardner and a team of volunteers who give service as a form of study and reflection. Quotes from Bulent Rauf and others suggest that central to the teachings of the Institute is unity of life and self discovery. On the hill above the house is the Monument to Man:</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF0169_Panorama.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <strong>The Monument to Man</strong> above the estate has engraved around the circumference, “ALL ARE FROM HIM AND TO HIM THEY RETURN”, resonant with similar phrases in the Bible (e.g.&nbsp;Romans 11:36) and the Qu’ran (e.g.&nbsp;Surah Al-Baqarah 2:156). In the ground near to the monument, with its four pillars representing Chisholme’s own pillars of <em>work</em>, <em>study</em>, <em>meditation</em> and <em>zikr</em>, is a circular stone bearing the inscription:</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p><em>O CONFIDENT SOUL, RETURN TO YOUR LORD, AGREEING AND AGREED TO ENTER AMONG MY SERVANTS AND ENTER MY PARADISE</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is a variation of another well known passage from the Qu’ran, Surah 89, Al-Fajr (Dawn, verses 26 – 30).</p>
</section>
<section id="time-travel-to-tushielaw" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="time-travel-to-tushielaw">Time Travel to Tushielaw</h2>
<p>We didn’t stay in the house for the whole weekend, and ventured out on a trip to Tushielaw for Sunday lunch. Despite high expectations for nice country pub food, instead it became more of a journey in time back to the 1970s. You had to have been there, of course, to fully appreciate the standard of service and fag reek over the sausage, egg ‘n’ chips with a choice of two sauces. And the footie on the telly. And the time it took for <em>mine host</em> to work out by hand, calculator, pen and paper in hand, the bill. And the landlady’s omnidirectional blather at anyone, or no-one, in the lounge. Such experience serves to remind us of how fortunate we are to be who we are.</p>
</section>
<section id="reflection" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="reflection">Reflection</h2>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF0070.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <strong>Cygnet on the lake</strong></p>
<p>It takes little reflection on life to see this ugly duckling as the gracious beauty he is becoming. Our weekend at the summer house gave us time and space to discuss things that concern us and things that make us. We took time and space to see ourselves more clearly and shared life and laughter. We resolved to act, and to not act, on these things. Chisholme draws on Lao Tsu for some of its teaching, describing it:</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>The philosophy of Lao Tsu is simple: Accept what is in front of you without wanting the situation to be other than it is. Study the natural order of things and work with it rather than against it, for to try to change what is only sets up resistance.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I think this understates Lao Tsu’s recognition of man’s free will and ability to use it. On the way home, we took advice from the Hadith:</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Anas ibn Malik reported: A man said, “O Messenger of Allah, should I tie my camel and trust in Allah, or should I leave her untied and trust in Allah?” The Prophet, peace and blessings be upon him, said, “Tie her and trust in Allah.”</p>
<p>Source: Sunan al-Tirmidhī 2517</p>
</blockquote>
</section>
<section id="notes-on-camera-equipment" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="notes-on-camera-equipment">Notes on camera equipment</h2>
<p>All of the pictures on this page were made with a Fuji X-T2 camera, and either the Fujifilm Fujinon XF16mmF1.4 R WR wide-angle lens, the 100-400 or my old Nikon 85mm Ai-S f/1.4. They were post-processed in Capture One Pro. There are other pictures yet come, taken on Lomo Babylon ISO 13 black &amp; white film with Nikon FM SLR.</p>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-10-16-summer-house.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF0022.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Autumn</title>
  <dc:creator>Jalal Al-din Muhammad Rumi</dc:creator>
  <link>https://niximagery.com/Moments/2022-10-15-autumn.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF0026.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>Inside each of us there’s a continual autumn.<br>
Our leaves fall and are blown out over the water,<br>
a crow sits in the blackened limbs and talks about what’s gone.<br>
There’s a necessary dying, and then we are reborn breathing again.</p>
<p>Very little grows on jagged rock.<br>
Be ground.<br>
Be crumbled<br>
so wildflowers will come up where you are.</p>
<p>– Jalal Al-din Muhammad Rumi</p>



 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://niximagery.com/Moments/2022-10-15-autumn.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF0026.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The Glen</title>
  <link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-10-08-the-glen.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="the-glen" class="level1">
<h1>The Glen</h1>
<p>!!! quote “Diane Arbus” A photograph is a secret about a secret. The more it tells you the less you know.</p>
<p>Speaking of Kings, we went for a walk in Pittencrieff Park (known locally as “The Glen”). We were hunting for autumn leaves for an artsy project, specifically Oak. A walk in a park is never a bad idea in my book, and it gave me a chance to re-introduce myself to the big Fuji XF100-400mm zoom lens that I got back from service and repair this week.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF9730.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <strong>Dunfermline Abbey</strong></p>
<p>King Charles III recently formally conferred city status on Dunfermline, during his first joint royal visit with the Queen Consort since the death of Queen Elizabeth. The townsfolk <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2022/oct/03/king-charles-confers-city-status-on-dunfermline-scotland">turned out for the occasion</a>, which is nice, even if some were apparently a little unkind to our First Minister. I couldn’t possibly comment.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF9732.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <strong>The Abbey and Abbey Church</strong> were basking in the early autumn glow. I love how the light played around the buttresses of this old place, which has <a href="https://www.undiscoveredscotland.co.uk/dunfermline/abbeypalace/index.html">quite a history</a>. Walking down into the Glen, the colurs in the Japanese Garden were no less magical.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF9739.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <strong>Japanese Acer</strong></p>
<p>The contrast was strong as we explored some of the nooks and crannies. Sunlight danced on water and dappled through the leaves, reflecting and re-reflecting greens and reds, oranges and yellows between dark and mysterious Tolkienesque shadows.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF9742.jpg" class="img-fluid"> The <strong>Waterfall</strong> on Tower Burn.</p>
<audio controls="controls">
<source type="audio/mp3" src="/audio/Pittencrieff%20Park.mp3">
<source type="audio/ogg" src="/audio/Pittencrieff%20Park.ogg">
</audio>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF9763.jpg" class="img-fluid"> What the Americans call <strong>a Sqrl</strong>. There are plenty of these in and around Dunfermline (squirrels, although there are a fair number of Americans, even at this time of year). They have a sense of humour, of course, and will run right across the feet of anyone with a camera just to watch them fumble for focus and fail.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF9819.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <strong>Alliums</strong> in the formal garden. We walked here after pausing for a breakfast roll at the Peacock Room, and chatting to an old friend I hadn’t seen for 20 years. That was a pleasant surprise and oddly, enabled me to fill in a couple of gaps from a particular period in my life. Nothing major, more an ironing out of wrinkles in a shirt I haven’t worn for a while, but a resolution nonetheless.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF9861.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <strong>This iconic peacock</strong> is one of a number in the park. There is a new enclosure following the recent mindless attack that resulted in the injury of one bird and the death of another, Malcolm, named for the King whose wife Margaret established the Abbey. More help is needed to support the volunteers who put heart and soul into caring for these beautiful creatures. If you can help, <a href="https://www.paypal.com/paypalme/pittencrieffpark?country.x=GB&amp;locale.x=en_GB">please drop them a few quid</a>. Thank you, and thanks for reading.</p>
<section id="camera-gear" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="camera-gear">Camera gear</h2>
<p>All of the pictures on this page were made with the Fuji XF100-400mm F4.5-5.6 R LM OIS WR lens and my brilliant digital Fuji X-T2 camera. They were tastefully post-processed in Capture One Pro.</p>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-10-08-the-glen.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2022 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF9730.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Dysart</title>
  <link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-10-08b-dysart.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="dysart" class="level1">
<h1>Dysart</h1>
<p>!!! quote “Robert Bresson” Make visible, what without you, might perhaps never have been seen.</p>
<p>After lunch, we had an errand to run in the Lang Toun which gave us an excuse to take another walk, this time around the harbour at Dysart. There is a huge wall there which is home to various pigeons, and tells quite a story of how this place has changed over the years. Part of the cliff at the end of the harbour is no longer safe to walk along but it is easy to access the coastal walk through a short tunnel in the cliff at the end of the wall.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF9879.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <strong>Dysart Harbour Wall</strong></p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF9878.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <strong>A shed</strong> by the harbour was eclectically decorated with harboury stuff, and really set the feel of the place.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF9882.jpg" class="img-fluid"> We arrived at feeding time for the boats, and they seemed to think we had treats for them.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF9886.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <strong>The wall again</strong>, because it is fascinating. The landscape of it seemed other-worldly.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF9885.jpg" class="img-fluid"> Plenty of things to look at in a harbour. There were people working, moving boats, furling sails and so on, and just as many sitting on benches. There were benches everywhere we looked today and I think I like that. Perhaps we are becoming more reflective.</p>
<section id="camera-gear" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="camera-gear">Camera gear</h2>
<p>All of the pictures on this page were made with the Fujifilm Fujinon XF16mm F1.4 R WR prime lens and the Fuji X-T2 camera. They were post-processed in Capture One Pro.</p>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-10-08b-dysart.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2022 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF9879.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Lower Largo</title>
  <link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-09-10-lower-largo.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="lower-largo" class="level1">
<h1>Lower Largo</h1>
<p>On the day of the King’s proclamation, and in need of some sea air, we took a run up the coast to Lower Largo. It’s been a challenging week for us in one way and another, not least for the depth of emotion we felt at the death of the Queen. There have been other losses, of course, but this one seems to have brought home Joni Mitchell’s statement of the obvious: <em>you don’t know what you’ve got ’til it’s gone</em>.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF9639Panorama.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>We walked along the upper path, it being near high tide, to a favourite spot on the beach beside what looks like a rockery arrangement for a garden. The waters swirled around the rocks and the sun passed slowly, ever lower in the sky as autumn progresses, reminding us again of the relentless march of time. Not yet ready to forget the dog days of summer, the sun shone warmly.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF9628Panorama.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>We sat for a while, the tide shifting the shapes and scenery with sand and seaweed. Sea kayaks passed out in the Forth, with the dead offshore platform Sedco 711 breaking up the horizon. Sunlight sparkled and shimmered on the water as time, <em>ralenti</em>, became all but suspended in the reverie.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF9626.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>There’s nothing like a beach, and no better beach than a Scottish beach, to purge stress and anxiety, those corrosive curses of the contemporary condition. After the passage of some indeterminate time, things are just better than they were; big things smaller; a feeling of coming home settles.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF9641.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>As we walked along the path, the soothing splash of the waves on the shore below provided headspace in which to process and park our reflections on the week’s events and resolutions were quietly packed in their pockets, ready for when we will need them.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF9652.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <strong>Teasels</strong></p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>I’ve learned that home isn’t a place, it’s a feeling. — <em>Cecelia Ahern in</em> Love, Rosie</p>
</blockquote>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-09-10-lower-largo.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF9654.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The Rose</title>
  <dc:creator>George Herbert</dc:creator>
  <link>https://niximagery.com/Moments/2022-08-28-rose.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF9572.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>So this flower doth judge and sentence<br>
Worldly joyes to be a scourge:<br>
For they all produce repentance,<br>
And repentance is a purge.</p>
<p>– George Herbert, “The Rose” (1633)</p>



 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://niximagery.com/Moments/2022-08-28-rose.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2022 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF9572.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>An afternoon at Stronachie and Loch Leven</title>
  <link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-08-27-stronachie.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="an-afternoon-at-stronachie-and-loch-leven" class="level1">
<h1>An afternoon at Stronachie and Loch Leven</h1>
<p>On Saturday afternoon, for no good reason and many, we jumped in the car with some snacks and went hunting for fresh air and ice cream. We went for a stroll down at Loch Leven. Walking out on the jetty, we saw the light was perfect and a heron was posing nicely along the shore. Of course, by the time we walked back to the car for our cameras, he was gone. The ice cream was easy, Giacopazzi’s in Kinross providing a very nice solution. Cookies and Cream for him, Peach Melba for her.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF9458_Panorama.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <strong>Loch Leven</strong> Fuji X-T2, 35mm f/2. Stitch of four images.</p>
<p>Onwards to a partly aimless drive to explore some favourite roads: through Milnathort, out by Tillyrie and Athron Hill where we had a look at a housing development seriously out of our range. Who needs a house that big anyway?</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF9479.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <strong>Stronachie Forest</strong> X-T2, Nikon 85mm f/1.4</p>
<p>On an easy walk at Stronachie, all of our senses were exercised. The air was rich in oxygen from the forest, perfumed with heather; the air crackled as the broom seed pods burst open in the warm late summer sun.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF9561.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <strong>Broom seed pods</strong></p>
<p>I changed the lens on the Fuji for the Stronachie walk, having started with the compact and versatile Fuji 35mm f/2, for my Nikon 85mm f/1.4. This is a difficult lens to focus wide open but it makes quite creamy bokeh washes from the background colours, even in low light.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF9508.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <strong>Plenty of room in the forest</strong> f/1.4 at 1600 ISO</p>
<p>The Nikon lens is well known for its flare, too. This rainbow effect from shooting into the light is caused by internal flare in the lens.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF9495.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <strong>Rainbow flare</strong></p>
<p>The Fuji X equivalent lens, the 90mm f/2, doesn’t have the same flare or bokeh as the much older Nikon. It’s not reasonable to compare them, perhaps, because of their age difference. Both are designed as portrait lenses.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF9512.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <strong>Stronachie Forest</strong> X-T2, Nikon 85mm f/1.4</p>
<p>How fortunate we are to live within reach of such wonders of nature.</p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-08-27-stronachie.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF9458_Panorama.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>East Neuk Day Trip</title>
  <link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-08-07-east-neuk.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="east-neuk-day-trip" class="level1">
<h1>East Neuk Day Trip</h1>
<p>We took a holiday hurl up the coast, just to take some air and not do the things that seem to have eaten the summer. We were lucky enough to get to the Hebrides, of course, but have managed to do other things too. Today was about switching off for a wee road trip along the fabulous Fife coast.</p>
<section id="st-monans-church" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="st-monans-church">St Monans Church</h2>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF9295Panorama.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="St Monans Church"> I am particularly pleased with this 87 megapixel image of the church that is connected so intimately with my wife’s family and her heritage. She has family in the church yard here and the iconic church deserves a decent place in our gallery. I hope to print this.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-fife-machair" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-fife-machair">The Fife Machair</h2>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF9355.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="The Fife Machair"> <strong>The Fife Machair</strong> is out in full bloom, with flowers of all colours basking in the sunshine. There seem to be fewer poppies than usual, for some reason, but we found a few near Kilconquhar.</p>
<p>All of the images in this post, except the St Monan’s beach steps below, were taken with my lightweight kit of the Fuji X-T2 and the amazing XF 35mm f2 lens. I’ve been making more large images recently, when using the digital kit, by stitching several images together, not unlike the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brenizer_Method">Brenizer method</a>.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF9337Panorama.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="St.&nbsp;Monans beach steps"> <strong>St.&nbsp;Monans beach steps</strong> For this image, taken as we returned from a walk along the path above the beach at St Monans, I used my old Nikon 85mm lens, stitching two images for a nice large square printable photo.</p>
</section>
<section id="poppies" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="poppies">Poppies</h2>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF9420.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="Poppies"> <img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF9414.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="Poppies"> <img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF9413.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="Poppies"> <strong>Poppies</strong> are the flowers of remembrance and I can’t spend time with poppies without feeling the emotions they invoke and what they signify. That culture is fading, I think, even as we are today, in time of war. People in some of my circles seem to be offended by remembrance and what used to be the importance of it. So long as I am able, I will not forget. So long as there are poppies, we will all be reminded, even if we choose to forget.</p>
</section>
<section id="ice-cream-at-pittenweem" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="ice-cream-at-pittenweem">Ice cream at Pittenweem</h2>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF9397Panorama.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="Pittenweem Harbour"> <strong>Pittenweem Harbour</strong>, X-T2, XF35mm. We stopped for an ice-cream on the way home, and enjoyed a cone in the famous fishing town of Pittenweem. This is 3 images, edited a little (as they all are) in Capture One.</p>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-08-07-east-neuk.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2022 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF9397Panorama.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>A Summer Hebridean trip</title>
  <link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-07-12-hebridean-trip.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="a-summer-hebridean-trip" class="level1">
<h1>A Summer Hebridean trip</h1>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF9085.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <strong>The Cuillins</strong>, X-T2, Nikon 85mm</p>
<p>It’s been a long time since there has been time for photography: life, COVID, and other everyday challenges have conspired to distract us from our one-time major non-work activity. A trip to the Hebrides for a short summer break demanded at least some effort, so I took my <a href="../../Cameras/fuji-x-t2.html">Fuji X-T2</a> and three lenses; the <a href="../../Cameras/ricoh-gr-iii.html">Ricoh GR-III</a>; and one concession to analogue photography, the <a href="../../Cameras/afga-isolette.html">Agfa Isolette</a>.</p>
<section id="skye" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="skye">Skye</h2>
<p>We drove cross-country from the Forth to Skye Bridges, taking our time to shop a little at the House of Bruar (one <em>has to</em>, surely) and dally at Sligachan bridge, an old favourite of ours with a newish statue to the mountaineers Prof.&nbsp;Norman Collie and John Mackenzie.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF9090.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <strong>Statue of Collie and Mackenzie</strong> at Glen Sligachan. X-T2 with a Nikon 85mm f/1.4 lens.</p>
<p>The 50-year-old Nikon lens holds up nicely on the Fuji. Wide-open at f/1.4 I find it very hard to get the focus exact – the depth of field is very narrow – but it is still a very nice lens for softening the background. It performs better on the Nikon it was designed for, being quite dark on the Fuji compared to the Fuji XF 90mm f/2.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF9086.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <strong>Glen Sligachan</strong>, X-T2, Nikon 85mm f/1.4 lens at about f/4.</p>
<p>The header image of Collie and Mackenzie’s Cuillins was also taken with the same camera and lens and shows off, in my view, the distinct colour profile of the Nikon glass. Make your own mind up whether you prefer the filmic shades of the Nikon over the technically superior and brilliant Fuji lenses.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/R0001279.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <strong>The iconic Portree harbour houses</strong>, Ricoh GR III at f/11, cropped.</p>
<p>Overnighting at a Hostel in Portree, we took the early ferry from Uig to Loch Maddy. I am always impressed with CalMac’s well-oiled operation, especially compared to the sometimes stressful experience of air travel. The 90 minute crossing was smooth and only slightly disappointing for not spotting seals at Vaternish Point. We consoled ourselves with a bacon and egg banjo in the “Mariners” café.</p>
</section>
<section id="five-islands" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="five-islands">Five Islands</h2>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF9112.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>The first couple of days in our remote “pod” were quite overcast with an ever-present wind between 20 and 40 mph, as the rest of the UK was baking in a record-breaking heat wave. It was nice, actually, and gave us a chance to explore comfortably and get a feel for the local group of islands.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF9100.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <strong>East Beach, Berneray</strong> Fuji X-T2, XF16mm f/1.4 lens at f/11, 1/250s, ISO 200.</p>
<p>The colours of the water and the machair were striking, different at every location and under the changing light. The sands are also rich with pattern and shade (below). The header image on this page was taken at Traigh Lar on North Uist which became one of our favourite places on our short trip. It was captured with the Fuji X-T2 and the XF16mm f/1.4 lens at f/16 to get the depth of field required to keep the grass in focus as well as the horizon. 1/1000s to freeze the waves, ISO 1000. There was a steep drop of about 20 m to the beach from this point.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF9095.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <strong>East Beach sands, Berneray</strong> Fuji X-T2, XF16mm f/1.4 lens at f/8, 1/1250, ISO 200.</p>
<p>Back on East Beach, the sands are also rich with pattern and texture. The countryside is rich with signs that it is expensive to dispose of old machinery and vehicles. Some effort seems to be made to at least gather the wreckage together. At Baleshare, a small collection of refrigerated trailers was forming. This one has signs of another era, like you see when shops change hands and ancient signwriting appears for a while.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/R0001290.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <strong>Dead trailer</strong> Ricoh GR III, processed in Capture One.</p>
<p>These two at least look like they’re trying to keep out of sight. The wheels stick out like shoes from under a curtain.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/R0001293.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <strong>Hidden trailers</strong> Ricoh GR III, a similar process in Capture One.</p>
</section>
<section id="to-eriskay-and-back" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="to-eriskay-and-back">To Eriskay and back</h2>
<p>We drove the length of the Outer Hebrides, at least without leaving the land. There are many causeways now connecting the various island communities and making commerce and life in general much easier for the people who live and work here. We visited five islands: North and South Uist, Berneray, Benbecula and Eriskay. We’re not counting Baleshare, although it connects to North Uist by another causeway. Most of the time one side of the causeway is all sand, and when it’s not, you could probably still wade across. We didn’t test that theory.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF9117.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <strong>Howmore Bothy</strong> (Fuji, Nikon 85mm lens)</p>
<p>Everywhere there are what seems like abandoned or derelict buildings. This example I photographed with both the Fuji (above) and the Ricoh (below) to create a different mood. I’m not sure how successful it is: the wider angle of the Ricoh allows more context to create a story with.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/R0001294.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <strong>Howmore Bothy</strong> (Ricoh, 18mm lens)</p>
<p>What really captured my heart during our leisurely and unstructured schlep around these islands was the sheer loveliness of the flowers that are just everywhere, clearly loved and protected by the local people. The wildflower meadowland that edges the beaches and reaches inland is diverse and colourful. I took far too many photographs of these flowers but will not tire of them as they adorn my desktop and walls in the coming months. Here, from the beach at Eriskay, right by the Barra Ferry terminal, is Sea Rocket:</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF9127.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <strong>Fuday Island from Prince Charles’ Beach, Eriskay</strong> Sea Rocket, Fuji X-T2, Nikon 85mm lens.</p>
<p>Back “home” to the bothy and a walk after dinner on our own beach on the doorstep, entertained on the way by rabbits and various birds playing and raising families in the meadowland.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF9140.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <strong>The beach at Baleshare</strong>, Fuji X-T2, Nikon 85mm lens.</p>
<p>Along the way, we met many of the residents.</p>
</section>
<section id="residents" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="residents">Residents</h2>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF9159.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <strong>Locals</strong> Fuji X-T2, Nikon 85mm</p>
<p>The islands have a thriving farming sector and there are sheep on every single-track road personally introducing themselves to foreign visitors. Birds are many and diverse: it is easy to see a host of sea birds in and around the machar and on the hillsides are Golden Eagles, Hen Harriers and short-eared owls hunting in the daytime.</p>
<!-- Local drivers are used to them and know how much care is required: visitors must err on the side of caution or display the appropriate yellow sticker in the back window to warn other road users. -->
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF9157.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <strong>Locals</strong> Fuji X-T2, Nikon 85mm</p>
<p>The diversity of the wildlife is noticeable for visitors like us from the central belt of Scotland. We seem to have a disproportionate seagull population and we can probably do with less of the fat pigeons and magpies, frankly.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF9149.jpg" class="img-fluid"> Where once working families lived, now stand more mechanised, efficient farming practices that make use of the land by fewer humans. A still nascent tourism industry is booked to capacity and locals still wave as visitors yield the right of way in the passing places. There is potential for development of abandoned plots and buildings across the islands. I hope that never comes to spoil the place.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/R0001301.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <strong>The roadside food wagon</strong> is no innovation nor is it a quaint enterprise: the food is home-made, delicious and locally sourced. You have to try the scallops and black pudding roll. Radio buzzers notify in your car when your lunch is ready and yes, they take contactless American Express. Check out the recycling bins. Even the coffee-cup lids are made of paper pulp. The Outer Hebrideans are right on trend when it comes to sustainable service.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF9180.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <strong>Sea birds</strong> abound along the shorelines and there are <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Sites_of_Special_Scientific_Interest_in_Western_Isles_South">sites of special scientific interest</a> intended to protect the diverse species, not least those that depend on the environment to breed and thrive. There are as many halfwits who will open gates to drive their SUVs across these spaces to access their picnics, of course but we think we saw at least one person openly challenge such behaviour.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF9166.jpg" class="img-fluid"> Most precious and beautiful of the environmental backdrop here is the machair. It is looked after and protected, as far as one can protect from human activity. Here may be common buttercups and clover but if you look, you can see many kinds of orchid.</p>
</section>
<section id="au-revoir" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="au-revoir">Au Revoir</h2>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF9206_Panorama.jpg" class="img-fluid"> This image will give you a sense of what we had hoped for when we headed North on our holiday. That image is actually a stitch of 8 images taken with the X-T2 and 35mm f/2 lens. Each image was exposed at f/8, 1/125s at ISO 200 and assembled into a panorama in Capture One. It should make a nice print about 50 inches x 20 inches if I ever get around to that.</p>
<p>Our sixth island of the trip was Skye, of course, our gateway to the Outer Hebrides. The hills and skies of Skye are something to behold: a mere photograph, least of all a digital image on a computer screen, can’t give you anything like the sense of <em>being there</em>. I tried with images like this pano, taken from the side of the road on the way from Carbost, not far from Sligachan where this series of posts began.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF9283_Panorama.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>The Broadford Co-Op was full of surprises. The cheapest diesel I’ve bought for weeks, and the right range of snacks for the rest of the journey home. Oh, and this view from the car park:</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF9289_Panorama.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>What we got from our trip was much better than we had hoped for, of course. We had the chance to explore and learn, visit and revisit under changing skies and light. We left with just the tip of a toe dipped in Hebridean life. In the end, I only took one photo with the Agfa. I forget what it was but no doubt it will pop out in a few months.</p>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2022/2022-07-12-hebridean-trip.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF9206_Panorama.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title></title>
  <link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2021/2021-10-18-ard-daraich.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="ard-daraich-anniversary-trip" class="level1">
<h1>Ard Daraich Anniversary trip</h1>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF8178.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <strong>Sanna Bay, the small isles</strong> Fuji X-T2 XF16mm ISO800 f/16 at 1/125s</p>
<p>We took a trip to the Ardnamurchan peninsula for our anniversary and enjoyed the pleasures of that with some photography. The sun shone on the first day, and took a jigsaw puzzle day on the second, giving us time for proper rest and relaxation. We stayed at Ard Daraich, home of the artist <a href="https://arddaraich.co.uk/anna-raven-artist/">Anna Raven</a> and her husband, film-maker <a href="https://ardgour-selfcatering.co.uk/norrie-maclaren/">Norrie MacLaren</a>. The house and gardens are <a href="https://www.countrylife.co.uk/gardens/country-gardens-and-gardening-tips/ard-daraich-was-the-holiday-home-of-constance-spry-155070">well known</a> as the former home of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Constance_Spry">Constance Spry</a>, famed as the creator of Coronation Chicken for the Queen. Our accommodation was the <a href="https://ardgour-selfcatering.co.uk/accommodation/the-garden-studio/">Garden Studio</a>, former garage to the larger house and nestled between the house and Anna’s studio which houses a substantial printing press which she uses to create some of her work.</p>
<p>On this trip I finished a roll of Portra 160 in a Hasselblad 503CW and Kodak 400 Tri-X in the amazing little Agfa Isolette. The exposures in those two rolls are included further below.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/R0001106.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>Bridge over the river Gour, Ricoh GRiii</em></p>
<p>The house sits on a lane that leads to <a href="https://www.ardgourholidays.co.uk/ardgour-house-">Ardgour House</a>, an altogether grander holiday destination, beyond our means and expectations. The lane passes over the river Gour by way of this bridge, which lit up in the unexpected sunshine of our first day, throwing reflections and patterns from the cool waters.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF8155.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>Reflection 1, Fuji X-T2</em></p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF8163.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>Reflection 2, Fuji X-T2</em></p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF8164.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>Reflection 3, Fuji X-T2</em></p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF8169.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>Reflection 4, Fuji X-T2</em></p>
<p>In the other direction, the lane ends at Loch Linnhe, which like all of Highland Scotland is alive with russets, rubies, rusty maroons, cardinals, carmines and ambers. The beach is striped with sea salad, echoing the leaves on the trees in heralding the fall of summer’s gaudy sparkle.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/R0001110.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>Beach salad, Ricoh GR-III</em></p>
<p>Our too-short sojourn at Ard Daraich was surely a rehearsal for a return to Ardgour and the stunning Ardnamurchan peninsula. A restful reconnaissance, well-earned and thoroughly appreciated as other duties call us back to the routine rumpus of that which pays us. We will be mellow, perhaps, as we savour the memories of the recent weekend.</p>
<!-- These are some of the digital images captured on the trip, but I also carried film cameras (Hasselblad and Agfa) with me and will be posting more from those and the trip home through Glen Coe and Glen Etive soon. -->
<section id="hasselblad-images" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="hasselblad-images">Hasselblad images</h2>
<p>I feel I have to show you some comparatives, starting with this image. Compare it with the first image in this post.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/Kodak-Portra-160-503CW-20220306_17083822.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/Kodak-Portra-160-503CW-20220306_16530161.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>Beach salad, Hasselblad 503CW</em></p>
<p>This image is quite different from the russet reds of the digital capture I made at the same time: here, no adjustments were made after scanning other than a slight crop adjustment. I think it’s just as strong in rendering the emotion of the moment. You can almost smell it. This is my favourite image from the roll and one I might print.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/Kodak-Portra-160-503CW-20220306_17400952.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>The Frandy Tree, Glendevon, Hasselblad 503CW</em></p>
<p>This is a famous tree to those who walk near Glendevon, as we did shortly after we got home. We know it as the Frandy Tree, named for the nearby fishery. It stands alone at the foot of Common Hill and strikes one of those poses that looks different at different times and seasons but also from different directions.</p>
<p>You can see some of the digital images captured on the trip are in the <a href="../../2021/10/18/ard-daraich">previous post</a>, but I also carried my Agfa and will be posting images from that when I can.</p>
<table class="table">
<thead>
<tr class="header">
<th style="text-align: left;">Brand</th>
<th style="text-align: left;">Type</th>
<th style="text-align: left;">ISO</th>
<th style="text-align: left;">Format</th>
<th style="text-align: left;">Exposures</th>
<th style="text-align: left;">Camera</th>
<th style="text-align: left;">Lens</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td style="text-align: left;">Kodak</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">T-Max BW Pan</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">400</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">120</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">12</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Agfa Isolette I</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Agfa Agnar 1:4.5/85</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td style="text-align: left;">Kodak</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Portra</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">160</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">120</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">12</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Hasselblad 503CW</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Zeiss 80mm F2.8 C</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>The Portra was sent to AG Labs 18 October 21 for C-41 processing.</p>
</section>
<section id="hasselblad-portra-160-exposures" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="hasselblad-portra-160-exposures">Hasselblad Portra 160 Exposures</h2>
<table class="table">
<thead>
<tr class="header">
<th style="text-align: right;">Frame</th>
<th style="text-align: left;">Image</th>
<th style="text-align: center;">Aperture</th>
<th style="text-align: center;">Shutter</th>
<th style="text-align: left;">Comment</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td style="text-align: right;">1</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Frandy Tree</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">f/16</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">1/60s</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">18 Sep 21</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td style="text-align: right;">2</td>
<td style="text-align: left;"></td>
<td style="text-align: center;">f/3.2</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">1/500s</td>
<td style="text-align: left;"></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td style="text-align: right;">3</td>
<td style="text-align: left;"></td>
<td style="text-align: center;">f/16</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">1/500s</td>
<td style="text-align: left;"></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td style="text-align: right;">4</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Sheep</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">f/10.6</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">1/60s</td>
<td style="text-align: left;"></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td style="text-align: right;">5</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Sanna, Ardnamurchan Lighthouse</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">f/13</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">1/15s</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">16 October</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td style="text-align: right;">6</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">The Small Isles</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">f/16</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">1/15s</td>
<td style="text-align: left;"></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td style="text-align: right;">7</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Ard Daraich loch</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">f/18</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">1/8s</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">17 Oct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td style="text-align: right;">8</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Kara’s composition of 7</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">f/22</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">1/6s</td>
<td style="text-align: left;"></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td style="text-align: right;">9 (header image)</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Beach salad</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">f/8</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">1/15s</td>
<td style="text-align: left;"></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td style="text-align: right;">10</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Jetty stakes</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">f/22</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">1/8s</td>
<td style="text-align: left;"></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td style="text-align: right;">11</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Glen Coe in mist</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">f/22</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">1/4s</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Loch Tula 18 Oct</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td style="text-align: right;">12</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">ditto</td>
<td style="text-align: center;"></td>
<td style="text-align: center;"></td>
<td style="text-align: left;"></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</section>
<section id="agfa-isolette-kodak-t-max-400-exposures" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="agfa-isolette-kodak-t-max-400-exposures">Agfa Isolette Kodak T-Max 400 Exposures</h2>
<p>This film was stand developed in Rodinal R09 in August 2022.</p>
<!-- Waiting to be scanned -->
<table class="table">
<thead>
<tr class="header">
<th style="text-align: right;">Frame</th>
<th style="text-align: left;">Image</th>
<th style="text-align: center;">Aperture</th>
<th style="text-align: center;">Shutter</th>
<th style="text-align: left;">Comment</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td style="text-align: right;">1</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Frandy Tree</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">f/11</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">1/125s</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Glendevon 25 September 21</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td style="text-align: right;">2</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Dunning Road from Common Hill climb</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">f/22</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">1/50</td>
<td style="text-align: left;"></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td style="text-align: right;">3</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Frandy Tree from CH summit</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">f/22</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">1/50</td>
<td style="text-align: left;"></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td style="text-align: right;">4</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Lower Glendevon Reservoir</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">f/16</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">1/50s</td>
<td style="text-align: left;"></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td style="text-align: right;">5</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Lochans on Common Hill</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">f/4.5</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">1/200s</td>
<td style="text-align: left;"></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td style="text-align: right;">6</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Wispy grass</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">f/4.5</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">1/200s</td>
<td style="text-align: left;"></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td style="text-align: right;">7</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Small isles</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">f/22 1/50s</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">16 Oct sanna</td>
<td style="text-align: left;"></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td style="text-align: right;">8</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">House on Sanna beach</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">f/16</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">1/50s</td>
<td style="text-align: left;"></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td style="text-align: right;">9</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Phone box and coo</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">f/8</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">1/50s</td>
<td style="text-align: left;"></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td style="text-align: right;">10</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Jetty posts</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">f/11</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">1/50s</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">17 Oct Ard Daraich</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td style="text-align: right;">11</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Twat, scrolled by</td>
<td style="text-align: center;"></td>
<td style="text-align: center;"></td>
<td style="text-align: left;"></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td style="text-align: right;">12</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Loch and jetty posts</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">f/16</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">1/50s</td>
<td style="text-align: left;"></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2021/2021-10-18-ard-daraich.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title></title>
  <link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2021/2021-09-11-polney-loch.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="polney-loch-91121" class="level1">
<h1>Polney Loch 9/11/21</h1>
<p>Remembering 9/11 20 years on</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/R0001067.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>Above Polney Loch</em>, Ricoh GRIII</p>
<p>We needed an escape from the madness and so jumped in the car and headed North to Tiso, the M&amp;S Foodstore and on to Dunkeld by way of the new road which is very nice, I have to say. The motive was almost a visceral need to be in the woods, and this time of year is when that experience is at its best as the colours are changing as fast as the air does: from the mouthfuls of balmy summer warmth to shorter bites of soupy vapour returned to the atmosphere as evanescent clouds. Mushroom time.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/Kodak-Tri-X-400-20211010_15283019.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>Fungus abounds. f/8 1/2s</em></p>
<p>I took a Hasselblad 503CW with a roll of Kodak Tri-X, and a Ricoh GRIII in my pocket for the more immediate gratification of having something to show on the day for our efforts. On this day, without explicitly talking about it, we remembered the events of 20 years ago with humility and gratitude, within one of Nature’s Cathedrals.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/Kodak-Tri-X-400-20211010_14291790.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>Bark on various trees. f/2.8 1/2s</em></p>
<p>In the peace and reflection of our walk, I noticed the bark patterns on the aged trees, like the scars of experience, each different from the others, each with their own stories to tell. These patterns became as faces of old men and women, taciturn yet expressive of triumph and loss, of lessons learned and not, of survival and the remembrance of those who did not.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/Kodak-Tri-X-400-20211010_14325659.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>Bark on various trees. f/2.8 1/4s</em></p>
<p>These were taken quite near the Cally car park where we began our stroll and I recall the steps, the birdsong and the additional aroma of the sawmill below the path, as I write this in October. A month from now is another great remembrance when I celebrate getting older, living vicariously for those who have been denied.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/Kodak-Tri-X-400-20211010_14364914.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>Bark on various trees. f/2.8 1/30s</em></p>
<p>The leaves on the birch trees on the far bank were turning a light golden yellow, which in this black and white image, is reminiscent of infra-red photographs I have taken. Not in this case; just gorgeous tones against the evergreen backdrop.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/Kodak-Tri-X-400-20211010_15193092.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>Polney Loch</em></p>
<p>At the end of the loch stands this wooden lodge – a fisherman’s howff, perhaps – that looks like it is from another age. It isn’t that old by the looks of it but we might easily be convinced that we stepped through a portal back there.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/Kodak-Tri-X-400-20211010_15072703.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>House at the end of the Loch</em></p>
<p>A detail of a hatch or door to the lodge reveals some old-time traditional craftsmanship, like you’d find on any great country estate. And ferns.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/Kodak-Tri-X-400-20211010_15024288.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>Door detail</em></p>
<p>I developed the film a couple of weeks later in Rodinal R09 using about 50:1 over 20 minutes with some agitation. I’m reasonably happy with the results but have to ask myself if the effort involved in getting these images out of an old Hasselblad is really that much superior to the almost instantaneous and high quality of the Ricoh. If it had been just the Ricoh that day, this whole story and reflection might have been consigned to history in a single, fleeting Instagram post. Perhaps it’s nothing to do with the camera.</p>
<section id="notes" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="notes">Notes</h2>
<table class="table">
<colgroup>
<col style="width: 11%">
<col style="width: 13%">
<col style="width: 8%">
<col style="width: 8%">
<col style="width: 11%">
<col style="width: 17%">
<col style="width: 13%">
<col style="width: 15%">
</colgroup>
<thead>
<tr class="header">
<th style="text-align: left;">Image</th>
<th style="text-align: left;">Camera</th>
<th style="text-align: left;">Lens</th>
<th style="text-align: left;">ISO</th>
<th style="text-align: left;">Format</th>
<th style="text-align: center;">Aperture</th>
<th style="text-align: center;">Shutter</th>
<th style="text-align: left;">Comment</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td style="text-align: left;">Header</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Ricoh GR-III</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Ricoh 18.3mm</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">ISO 6400</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Digital</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">f/11</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">1/25s</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Adjusted in Capture One.</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td style="text-align: left;">Bark</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Hasselblad 503CW</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Zeiss 80mm F2.8 C</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">400</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">120</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">f/2.8</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">1/2 sec</td>
<td style="text-align: left;"></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td style="text-align: left;">Bark 2</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Hasselblad 503CW</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Zeiss 80mm F2.8 C</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">400</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">120</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">f/2.8</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">1/4 sec</td>
<td style="text-align: left;"></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td style="text-align: left;">Bark 3</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Hasselblad 503CW</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Zeiss 80mm F2.8 C</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">400</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">120</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">f/2.8</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">1/30 sec</td>
<td style="text-align: left;"></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td style="text-align: left;">Mushroom</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Hasselblad 503CW</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Zeiss 80mm F2.8 C</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">400</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">120</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">f/2.8</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">1/2 sec</td>
<td style="text-align: left;"></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td style="text-align: left;">Polney Loch</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Hasselblad 503CW</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Zeiss 80mm F2.8 C</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">400</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">120</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">f/22</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">1/3 s</td>
<td style="text-align: left;"></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td style="text-align: left;">House</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Hasselblad 503CW</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Zeiss 80mm F2.8 C</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">400</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">120</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">f/18</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">1 sec</td>
<td style="text-align: left;"></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td style="text-align: left;">Door</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Hasselblad 503CW</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Zeiss 80mm F2.8 C</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">400</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">120</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">f/10</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">1/8 s</td>
<td style="text-align: left;"></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td style="text-align: left;">Below</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Hasselblad 503CW</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Zeiss 80mm F2.8 C</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">400</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">120</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">f/16</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">1/4s</td>
<td style="text-align: left;"></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</section>
<section id="kodak-tri-x-exposure-notes" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="kodak-tri-x-exposure-notes">Kodak Tri-X Exposure notes</h2>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/Kodak-Tri-X-400-20211010_14532281.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>Polney Loch</em></p>
<table class="table">
<thead>
<tr class="header">
<th style="text-align: left;">Brand</th>
<th style="text-align: left;">Type</th>
<th style="text-align: left;">ISO</th>
<th style="text-align: left;">Format</th>
<th style="text-align: left;">Exposures</th>
<th style="text-align: left;">Camera</th>
<th style="text-align: left;">Lens</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td style="text-align: left;">Kodak</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Tri-X</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">400</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">120</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">12</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Hasselblad 503CW</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Zeiss 80mm F2.8 C</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>Scanned 10 October 2021</p>
<table class="table">
<thead>
<tr class="header">
<th style="text-align: right;">Frame</th>
<th style="text-align: left;">Image</th>
<th style="text-align: center;">Aperture</th>
<th style="text-align: center;">Shutter</th>
<th style="text-align: left;">Comment</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td style="text-align: right;">1</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Bark</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">f/2.8</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">1/2s</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Cally car park</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td style="text-align: right;">2</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Bark 2</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">f/2.8</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">1/4s</td>
<td style="text-align: left;"></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td style="text-align: right;">3</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Bark 3</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">f/2.8</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">1/30s</td>
<td style="text-align: left;"></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td style="text-align: right;">4</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Bark 4</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">f/2.8</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">1/125s</td>
<td style="text-align: left;"></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td style="text-align: right;">5</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Polney Loch</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">f/16</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">1/4s</td>
<td style="text-align: left;"></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td style="text-align: right;">6</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">ditto</td>
<td style="text-align: center;"></td>
<td style="text-align: center;"></td>
<td style="text-align: left;"></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td style="text-align: right;">7</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">House at the end of the Loch</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">f/18</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">1 sec</td>
<td style="text-align: left;"></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td style="text-align: right;">8</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">House 2</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">f/22</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">1/2 sec</td>
<td style="text-align: left;"></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td style="text-align: right;">9</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Door</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">f/10</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">1/8s</td>
<td style="text-align: left;"></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td style="text-align: right;">10</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Loch</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">f/22</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">1/3s</td>
<td style="text-align: left;"></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td style="text-align: right;">11</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Mushrooms</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">f/2.8</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">1/2s</td>
<td style="text-align: left;"></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td style="text-align: right;">12</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Mushroom</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">f/8</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">1/2s</td>
<td style="text-align: left;"></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2021/2021-09-11-polney-loch.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title></title>
  <link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2021/2021-07-22-coigach-assynt.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="coigach-and-assynt" class="level1">
<h1>Coigach and Assynt</h1>
<p>A few days in the North West</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF8005.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>Thistles. Fuji X-T2</em></p>
<p>For our summer trip North this year, I took the Hasselblad 503CW and my Nikon FM with digital backup from a Ricoh GRIII and my Fuji X-T2. The Agfa stayed in the bag and the GW690ii stayed at home. There’s only so much gear one can carry.</p>
<p>One of the first beaches we headed for was Acheninver, a short walk from the hostel where we spent the first couple of nights. It was overcast for the first few days of our break, which was a blessing for us because the mobs were elsewhere. At the beach was a man filling builder’s bags with seaweed: curious, I asked him why. Crofter Steve Husband explained that there is a <a href="https://www.islemartin.org/isle-martin-seaweed-festival-home/">seaweed festival</a> on Isle Martin in September and that a dry run of glassmaking had used the entire stock of seaweed, so he was replenishing. The seaweed is dried and burned with sand to make artisan glass, and burning kelp is an ancient tradition in the North. Some of the seaweed Steve had gathered looked good enough to eat, and indeed, it can be used for culinary purposes.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF7975.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>Steve in his tractor with his Gaelic-speaking dog. Fuji X-T2</em></p>
<p>The next day, we tried out a new camping stove on Achmelvich beach, pushing the culinary boundaries by heating up a tin of sausages and beans. Classy. On our meander around the Coigach and Drumbeg, I tried a bit of sketching. Some way to go, I think.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/IMG_9378.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>Achnahaird beach, sketch</em></p>
<p>The last few days were spent in Drumbeg House, or at least, in a self-contained house within the grounds of said House. This was a perfectly peaceful place to escape for a few days with its own cairn at the side of its own loch and a decent deer population to get us close to that Highland feeling.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/DSF8099.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>Young stag. Fuji X-T2</em></p>
<p>We were treated to a close encounter with one of these stags, at the point we were ready to give up hope of seeing the wildlife without a telephoto lens, when one wandered through the bracken and paused on the grass between the house and the loch, to gaze at us, neither of us knowing whether to grab a camera or just experience the moment.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/Kodak-TMY-400-20210912_17513046.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>Keeper’s shed. Hasselblad 503CW, Kodak TMY 400</em></p>
<p>The old house has been renovated, we think under new ownership, perhaps to return to its former glory as an exclusive dining experience for those who do that kind of thing. Traces of a more private small estate are still seen in the grounds.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/Kodak-TMY-400-20210912_19434344.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>1907. Hasselblad 503CW, Kodak TMY 400</em></p>
<p>We went along the coast to explore the peninsula of Culkein and Stoer, where there are wild rocks and waves from the Northern Minch, and hidden caves.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/Kodak-TMY-400-20210912_20371219.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>A cave at Stoer. Hasselblad 503CW, Kodak TMY 400</em></p>
<p>Kylesku is a wonderful place and we visited, travelling home past the Sàil Gharb and Sàil Ghórm corbetts.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/Kodak-Portra-800-20211010_12151225.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>Sàil Gharb and Sàil Ghórm. Nikon FM, Kodak Portra 800</em></p>
<p>The roads were pretty much deserted around here, even in the post-COVID mad summer of 2021 when all of England discovered Scotland.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/Kodak-Portra-800-20211010_12192098.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>Passing place. Nikon FM, Kodak Portra 800, f/11 1/250s</em></p>
<section id="notes" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="notes">Notes</h2>
<p>Detailed exposure logs for this post are <a href="../../Exposures/2021/2021-07-22-coigach-assynt/">here</a>.</p>
<table class="table">
<colgroup>
<col style="width: 11%">
<col style="width: 13%">
<col style="width: 8%">
<col style="width: 8%">
<col style="width: 11%">
<col style="width: 17%">
<col style="width: 13%">
<col style="width: 15%">
</colgroup>
<thead>
<tr class="header">
<th style="text-align: left;">Image</th>
<th style="text-align: left;">Camera</th>
<th style="text-align: left;">Lens</th>
<th style="text-align: left;">ISO</th>
<th style="text-align: left;">Format</th>
<th style="text-align: center;">Aperture</th>
<th style="text-align: center;">Shutter</th>
<th style="text-align: left;">Comment</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td style="text-align: left;">Thistles</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Fuji X-T2</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">XF35mm F2 R WR</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">ISO 800</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Digital</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">f/8</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">1/250s</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Adjusted in Capture One.</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td style="text-align: left;">Tractor</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Fuji X-T2</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">XF90mm F2 R LM WR</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">ISO 800</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Digital</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">f/11</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">1/500s</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Cropped &amp; adjusted in Capture One.</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td style="text-align: left;">Young stag</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Fuji X-T2</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">XF100-400mmF4.5-5.6 R LM OIS WR</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">ISO 1600</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Digital</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">f/10</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">1/500s</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Cropped &amp; adjusted in Capture One.</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td style="text-align: left;">Shed</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Hasselblad 503CW</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Zeiss 80mm f/2.8</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">400</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">120</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">f/11</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">1/8s</td>
<td style="text-align: left;"></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td style="text-align: left;">1907</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Hasselblad 503CW</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Zeiss 80mm f/2.8</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">400</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">120</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">f/8</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">1/4s</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Cropped</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td style="text-align: left;">Caves</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Hasselblad 503CW</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Zeiss 80mm f/2.8</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">400</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">120</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">f/22</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">1/8s</td>
<td style="text-align: left;"></td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td style="text-align: left;">Sàil Gharb and Sàil Ghórm</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Nikon FM</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Nikon AI-s 28mm f/2.8</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">800</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">135</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">f/11</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">1/250s</td>
<td style="text-align: left;"></td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td style="text-align: left;">Passing place</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Nikon FM</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Nikon AI-s 28mm f/2.8</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">800</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">135</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">f/11</td>
<td style="text-align: center;">1/250s</td>
<td style="text-align: left;"></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2021/2021-07-22-coigach-assynt.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title></title>
  <link>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2021/2021-07-30-five-films.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<section id="five-films" class="level1">
<h1>Five films</h1>
<p>More random rolls from the COVID era</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/Kodak-Ektachrome-E100-20210730_20010914.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>February sunset at Patteismuir</em></p>
<p>Continuing the series of films I had lost track of this year, there were another five exposed films kicking about with only partial notes and recall to record them. Again, using my new Digitaliza film holders and a new MacBook Air, the scans were interesting. In this series:</p>
<table class="table">
<thead>
<tr class="header">
<th style="text-align: left;">Brand</th>
<th style="text-align: left;">Type</th>
<th style="text-align: left;">ISO</th>
<th style="text-align: left;">Format</th>
<th style="text-align: left;">Exposures</th>
<th style="text-align: left;">Camera</th>
<th style="text-align: left;">Lens</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr class="odd">
<td style="text-align: left;">Kodak</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Ektachrome E100</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">100</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">120</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">8</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Fuji GW690ii</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">90mm</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td style="text-align: left;">Cinestill</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">800 T</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">800</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">35mm</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">36</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Nikon FM</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Nikon AI-s 28mm f/2.8</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td style="text-align: left;">Lomography</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Metropolis</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">EI 400</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">120</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">12</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Hasselblad 503CW</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Zeiss 80mm F2.8 C</td>
</tr>
<tr class="even">
<td style="text-align: left;">Ilford</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Delta</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">3200</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">35mm</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">36</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Nikon FM</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Nikon AI-s 28mm f/2.8</td>
</tr>
<tr class="odd">
<td style="text-align: left;">Kodak</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Portra</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">160</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">35mm</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">36</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Nikon FM</td>
<td style="text-align: left;">Nikon AI-s 28mm f/2.8</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<section id="ektachrome" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="ektachrome">Ektachrome</h2>
<p>I am becoming a big fan of Kodak’s modern slide film: no big surprise, really, because years ago I favoured Kodachrome and Agfa’s transparency film in my Nikon FM. Here, a few frames in the huge Fuji GW690ii 6 x 9 camera taken around Kilconquhar and St Monans around 9th April. Scanned at 3200 dpi, the digital images are about 80 mega pixels in size, although sharpness doesn’t satisfy the pixel-neurotic: it’s colours that make these images worth making.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/Kodak-Ektachrome-E100-20210730_20292470.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>Church at Kilconquhar. Fuji GW690ii, Ektachrome E100</em></p>
<p>The composition here isn’t perfect: it was tempting to crop out the part-of-a-treee on the left of this picture but there is something in me that wants to crop and adjust as little as possible. I can see what I was thinking with the line of the path central to the composition and am pleased that I kept these parallel to the lines of the church tower. There’s always a bit of difference between what you see in the rangefinder window and the image on the film so I consider this a successful image.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/Kodak-Ektachrome-E100-20210730_20370722.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>Kilconquhar. Fuji GW690ii, Ektachrome E100</em></p>
<p>I like the colours in this image taken at the loch, facing in the other direction, a few paces from where I captured the church. The complementary sky and grass tones here work for me. What is most impressive with this film stock is that there is almost no post processing required – the header sunset image taken in February at Pattiesmuir shows this, I think, as well as these snaps from Kilconquhar and St.&nbsp;Monans. Sunlight and good skies are a real bonus too.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/Kodak-Ektachrome-E100-20210730_20451049.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>St.&nbsp;Monan’s harbour. Fuji GW690ii, Ektachrome E100</em></p>
<p>Taken from the walk down to the famous wonky sea wall at St.&nbsp;Monans, this again might have been cropped on the left if it had been a digital capture. I love the two-weather sky here.</p>
</section>
<section id="cinestill-800t" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="cinestill-800t">Cinestill 800T</h2>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/Cinestill-800T-20210731_18185960.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>Flowers at Dumbarnie Links, Nikon FM, Cinestill 800T</em></p>
<p>Cinestill 800T is a fast popular film stock, with the “T” indicating that it is designed to be used in tungsten light. It’s ideal for shooting urban scenes at night, which was my intention when I bought a few rolls of 135 and 120 at the beginning of 2021. This first roll was exposed in April in a Nikon FM in daylight at Seafield Beach, Dumbarnie Links (frames 16–25) and Elie (frames 26ff). Scanning as before, I processed them in Capture One, severely adjusting white balance and contrast to compensate for the blue shift of the abused film.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/Cinestill-800T-20210731_18112996.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>Seafield Beach. Nikon FM, Cinestill 800T</em></p>
<p>This seemed to do the trick, rendering colours realistically with only two slider adjustments off the scanner. I’m learning to not allow the scanner to do anything with the colour of the files it creates. The above image of flowers at Dumbarnie Links illustrates this.</p>
<p>I’m generally pleased with the results if not a little <em>meh</em> about my collection of dead boring images. Cinestill 800T is an exciting film to use for exciting images: punchy urban scenes evocative of some other era or dark filmic concepts. It’s not really meant for landscapes taken on walks, the purpose of which was not photography but clearing heads. I hope my next set of images with this film stock will do it better justice.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/Cinestill-800T-20210731_18550535.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>Elie Beach. Nikon FM, Cinestill 800T</em></p>
<p>I do like the rendering of contrast and tone in this film, once adjusted. Below, Lady’s Tower on a sunny day in Fife gives the film a chance to show this to create a nice image that evokes the feeling of the moment it was captured. More than that, I guess, can’t be asked for.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/Cinestill-800T-20210731_19054350.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>Lady’s Tower, Elie. Nikon FM, Cinestill 800T</em></p>
</section>
<section id="lomography-metropolis" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="lomography-metropolis">Lomography Metropolis</h2>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/Lomochrome-Metropolis-EI400-20210801_12592490.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>St.&nbsp;Monans, Fife. Hasselblad 503CW, 80mm Zeiss.</em></p>
<p>This film stock was introduced in 2019 as a new film emulsion with extended range, meaning that the sensitivity is stated on the box as ISO 100 – 400 and you take your pick. I exposed this roll at the higher speed to see how it worked there. As with all of the films in this mini-series, I got AG Photographic to develop them for me.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/Lomochrome-Metropolis-EI400-20210801_13364835.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>Bass Rock from Crail. Hasselblad 503CW, 80mm Zeiss.</em></p>
<p>I first scanned this roll using 48-bit colour and 6400 dpi settings which produced square image files post-processing of about 180 megapixels. The colours are muted and cool. It took some time to find the correct white balance adjustment in Capture One but I think the image of St Monans church in Fife is a fair rendition of the film’s character. I like that the contrast is strong. You will not see the Hasselblad notches in that image because, as with many of my hand-held photographs, the horizon was a bit squint, as they say around here, so I had to adjust it and crop.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/Lomochrome-Metropolis-EI400-20210801_13364835-1.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>Crail, Fife. Hasselblad 503CW, 80mm Zeiss.</em></p>
<p>This was the last useful frame off the roll, as some time later, during a visit to the Hermitage at Dunkeld, I reached for the Hasselblad and forgot there was film in it. Sheer stupidity caused me to open the film back to load a new film without first checking the clever mechanical indicator on the cartridge. I’m going to say that I will not do that again but then again I also say that my next car will be a Maserati.</p>
</section>
<section id="ilford-delta-3200" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="ilford-delta-3200">Ilford Delta 3200</h2>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/Ilford-Delta-3200-20210801_17251720-1.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>St.Monans Harbour. Nikon FM, 28mm f/1.4 AiS</em></p>
<p>As this is a black and white film, I might have developed this myself but as with all of the films in this mini-series, I got AG Photographic to develop it for me. It was scanned at 6400, then 3200 dpi in 24-bit colour (otherwise the scanner screws up the colour profile in the output file). In post-processing, the profile is switched to black and white. The early images were not of good enough resolution to justify 6400 dpi, hence the switch to something lower.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/Ilford-Delta-3200-20210801_16112152.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>Edinburgh, from Fife. Nikon FM, 28mm f/1.4 AiS</em></p>
<p>Most of those early frames were quite disappointing, being underexposed and losing detail in the shadows. I’m fairly sure this was a metering issue: I rely on the built-in LED through-the-lens metering when shooting with the Nikon FM and this might be the price of laziness. Some can be recovered, though, and this image shows a sort of moody shoreline to illustrate the point.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/Ilford-Delta-3200-20210801_17025154.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>Edinburgh. Nikon FM, 28mm f/1.4 AiS</em></p>
<p>This is the view from my office window on the Holyrood campus. Delta 3200 might suggest a good low-light film but I think it’s more fast than it is good in the dark. It needs light to function properly. The next image also, perhaps, is more suited to the grainy emulsion of Delta 3200.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/Ilford-Delta-3200-20210801_17174590.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>The Palace, Rosyth. Nikon FM, 28mm f/1.4 AiS</em></p>
<p>Something more urban in flavour demands not only monochrome but also the character of a grainy film stock like this. I don’t think it handles wide dynamic range the way I had hoped, however. Shooting into the light is probably not the best idea:</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/Ilford-Delta-3200-20210801_17251720.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>Harbour Bell, St.Monans. Nikon FM, 28mm f/1.4 AiS</em></p>
<p>Delta 3200 can perform well with good light, and yield decent contrasty images if you meter and expose correctly.</p>
</section>
<section id="kodak-portra-160" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="kodak-portra-160">Kodak Portra 160</h2>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/Kodak-Portra-160-20210808_18071280-2.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>Queensferry Crossing from St.&nbsp;Margaret’s Marsh</em></p>
<p>I scanned most of these at 3200 or 4800 dpi in 48-bit colour with the scanner’s colour handling switch off. The first few frames were taken at the Hermitage, near Dunkeld, during a weekend run up to one of our favourite places in May. We needed reflection time and the COVID restrictions were just so that we could do the right thing as we did The Right Thing for us.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/Kodak-Portra-160-20210808_18071280.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>Ossian’s Hall. Nikon FM, 28mm f/1.4 AiS</em></p>
<p>The Dunkeld weekend was not in the brightest of sunshine and that tends to wash out the colours in Portra, I think. This is a dark and moody kind of place when it’s overcast, so the image above does portray that. No marks for composition – there’s a better portrait version but that favours the bridge over the hall and I wanted to show that in this post.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/Kodak-Portra-160-20210808_18071280-1.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <em>Queensferry Crossing from St.&nbsp;Margaret’s Marsh</em></p>
<p>There was better light when we walked on the Forth Shore at St.&nbsp;Margaret’s Marsh, between the bridges and the dockyard. Some while later, we were at Loch Lubnaig where the colours of the greenery dominate the images taken with this film.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/Kodak-Portra-160-20210808_18365655.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>I’m not such a fan of 160 in anything other than really good daylight. Composition plays a part, too, and these images aren’t my best: the last few frames of the roll were taken at Burntisland.</p>
<p><img src="https://niximagery.com/img/Kodak-Portra-160-20210808_18565359.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<!--15 May Strathyre and Lubnaig
FM 8 ff Portra

27 June Fife beach
FM still Portra 160 ff28ff
-->


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://niximagery.com/Stories/2021/2021-07-30-five-films.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
